<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
    <title>ThreeFold - community</title>
    <subtitle>Our global digital backbone</subtitle>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://dev.threefold.io/categories/community/atom.xml"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://dev.threefold.io"/>
    <generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
    <updated>2024-06-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://dev.threefold.io/categories/community/atom.xml</id>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Creating Transformative Impact</title>
        <published>2024-06-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-06-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://dev.threefold.io/blog/transformative-impact-summit/"/>
        <id>https://dev.threefold.io/blog/transformative-impact-summit/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://dev.threefold.io/blog/transformative-impact-summit/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“By bringing together those dedicating their lives to making the world a better place, and empowering them with exposure, support, connection, and funding, we not only celebrate transformative impact, we create it.”&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Held this June 7 - 9 in Zanzibar, Tanzania, the &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.transformativeimpactsummit.com&#x2F;p&#x2F;2024&quot;&gt;Transformative Impact Summit&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; convened with this important focus, attracting an audience of people from around the world working across the entire impact ecosystem, along with students from local IT universities, and government officials from Zanzibar.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.catalist.network&#x2F;1-column-agenda&#x2F;tis-africa-24&quot;&gt;jam-packed three-day schedule of focused talks&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; gave essential background and context to the incredible group of participants and their initiatives. Different tracks for the summit included Financial Innovation, Regenerative Finance, Regenerative Agriculture and Food, along with health and social connection, and AI, Web3, and Tech for Good.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;dev.threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;transformative-impact-summit&#x2F;.&#x2F;panel.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The diverse array of speakers and topics included:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kristof, Florian, and Greg from the ThreeFold team (more on this below)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Matthew Schutte, co-founder of &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;holochain.org&quot;&gt;HoloChain&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, who talked about HoloChain and their perspective on application development&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Omrei Abumadi, founder of &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.vverse.co&#x2F;&quot;&gt;VVerse&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (a ThreeFold &amp;amp; OurWorld collaborator), who discussed the metaverse and showcased a virtual environment built just for the event&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Victor Muhagachi and David Machuche, co-founders of &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;chatafisha.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Chatafisha&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;introducing-dunia-yetu&#x2F;4147&quot;&gt;Dunia Yetu&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; collaborators, who spoke about how FinTech can empower Africa’s waste pickers&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dr. Cornelia Wallner-Frisee, co-founder of &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.africaaminilife.com&#x2F;en&quot;&gt;Africa Amini Life&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, who presented “Education is Our Strongest Medicine”&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;El Fuego Mutaz, Head of Africa at &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;refunite.org&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Refunite&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, a tech non-profit that uses technology and innovation to provide humanitarian assistance, who spoke about how technology can reconnect families, as well as reshaping the future of aid with local community leadership&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Partnerships were forged, friendships were formed, and at least one project received some funding – other outcomes remain to be seen, as it has only been a few days since the summit ended.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-zanzibar-why-now&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#why-zanzibar-why-now&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: why-zanzibar-why-now&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why Zanzibar? Why Now?&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last April, some of the ThreeFold team attended Zuzalu, a two-month “pop-up city” co-created by Vitalik Buterin, who was inspired in part by the idea of network states and wanting to simulate new ways of living together.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During those weeks, we had the opportunity to engage with a wide variety of interesting and innovative organizations and individuals. It was an amalgamation of people from around the world, some there for Web3, some for longevity, others network states, and many with a focus on impact.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One person we really connected and aligned with was Elliott Bayev of &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.globalunity.org&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Global Unity&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, who has since become a dear friend of our project. Elliott is a super-connector, weaver of people and concepts, and storyteller – on a mission to unite humanity and empower global cooperation. At the time, he was in the midst of planning for the first Transformative Impact Summit, which was held last fall in New York City during UN Climate Week.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While at Zuzalu, with Elliott and others, we often talked about the noticeably low presence of attendees from certain regions, specifically Africa. Visa restrictions and sometimes lack of resources made it difficult for this audience to attend. This seemed unfair, to say the least, and did not allow for these important voices to be heard.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What resulted was a commitment to do our part in bringing these types of conversations to the African continent. ThreeFold partnered with Niklas Anzinger to create the &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;lu.ma&#x2F;zanzibar_regen&quot;&gt;Africa Regenerative Cities Summit&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; last July and did a follow-up event last November. We’ve hosted and participated in other smaller events in Zanzibar and nearby Dar Es Salaam. Now, Elliott has brought the second Transformative Impact Summit to Zanzibar. (And we’d be remiss not to mention the team who put together and hosted &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;zanzalu.super.site&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Zanzalu&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, a direct spin-off &#x2F; extension of last year’s Zuzalu.)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;threefold-at-transformative-impact-summit&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#threefold-at-transformative-impact-summit&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: threefold-at-transformative-impact-summit&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ThreeFold at Transformative Impact Summit&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold was honored to present on a few different occasions throughout the summit and had the pleasure of hosting two evening events for speakers and attendees.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;dev.threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;transformative-impact-summit&#x2F;.&#x2F;kristoftis.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the first day of the summit, our co-founder Kristof De Spiegeleer spoke on the topic of Public Private Partnerships being a model that can change Africa, and on Saturday he spoke on a panel about uplifting Africa with technology and more specifically about ThreeFold, OurWorld, and the OurWorld Digital Free Zone project.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, ThreeFold ecosystem developer Florian Fournier spoke on the topic of crafting a conscious society for our world on the second day. And Gregory Flipo, co-founder of Sikana and ecosystem developer for ThreeFold presented on educational video content on a global scale. Crucially, all three were clear in communicating that new decentralized and sovereign infrastructure and systems are key to enabling truly transformative impact.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;dev.threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;transformative-impact-summit&#x2F;.&#x2F;flotis.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the talks throughout the summit inspired and gave context, much of the magic happened in the evening gatherings or even now after the summit has ended, where we have been able to connect more one-on-one to explore ways of collaboration with some of the attendees and speakers.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-s-next&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#what-s-next&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: what-s-next&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s Next?&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elliott and Global Unity continue their efforts to connect and empower individuals and organizations dedicating their lives to making the world a better place, with a strong commitment to Africa and its people. Their next event will be the annual Transformative Impact Summit in NYC during Climate Week, September 27-29.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We, the ThreeFold team, will continue to collaborate with Elliott and his team, finding opportunities to support each other – and as active participants in the Global Unity &#x2F; Transformative Impact network, we see many possibilities unfolding.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Primarily, impact projects need responsible digital infrastructure. ThreeFold could be a perfect choice for the impact space and we are eager to collaborate.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Project Internet Capacity: ThreeFold&#x27;s Next Chapter</title>
        <published>2024-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/introducing-project-inca/"/>
        <id>https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/introducing-project-inca/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/introducing-project-inca/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Please note the information below is subject to change as the project evolves and will be updated as is appropriate.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold’s journey over the past years has been one of deep, collaborative commitment, marked by significant technological advancements and milestones in building a new cloud infrastructure from the ground up, as well as the global expansion of the grid to its current state. Throughout this journey, we have learned, adapted, and evolved, leading us to a strong strategy for the next chapter and achieving our collective vision.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;meet-project-internet-capacity&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meet Project Internet Capacity&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are thrilled to introduce the Internet Capacity project, a promising new extension of our mission. Building on years of dedicated work by team and community, this project is the fourth generation of the ThreeFold Grid and introduces the $INCA token (more on that below). With this project, ThreeFold is ready to become a base layer for the DePIN ecosystem.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;youtu.be&#x2F;tXELhKk9RYg?si=fyz4K7gFQ1yD1PLS&quot;&gt;our most recent project update community call&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, we were grateful to hear from Michael Wellesley-Wesley, the founder of &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;green-edge.net&#x2F;en&quot;&gt;Green Edge&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and prominent farmer on the ThreeFold Grid since 2017-2018, who introduced the project to the community.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Internet Capacity project is rooted in three major objectives:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reliability:&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; Achieving service levels that allow edge and AI workloads to run efficiently.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Community:&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; Establishing scalable community and communication systems for vast communities at both the farming and user levels.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Growth:&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; Expanding the grid to a million nodes in order to see out the vision of a truly global decentralized cloud infrastructure and ecosystem.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;mission-and-vision&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mission and Vision&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an extension of ThreeFold, the Internet Capacity project promotes a decentralized, community-driven, and inclusive cloud network, providing secure, private, and autonomous access to computing resources for all. The technology ensures a resilient, censorship-resistant infrastructure that protects data integrity and privacy, fostering innovation, digital sovereignty, and a more equitable internet.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The vision is to provide a cloud engine for a decentralized internet where users control their data and digital interactions. A global network of interconnected servers and nodes known as the grid, will democratize access to computing power and storage, forming the backbone of a new digital era of sovereignty, security, privacy, and inclusivity. The token supports a robust ecosystem, enabling the free exchange of internet capacity among cloud service providers, builders, and users on the grid.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-to-look-forward-to-with-the-project&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What to Look Forward to with the Project?&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project introduces several exciting elements for farmers and users alike:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The most significant technological advancement is the Mycelium network, offering unbreakable connectivity and efficient routing, which is crucial for scalability – including for any DePIN protocol or project running on top of our grid&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hosts (farmers) will be able to earn on utilization as well as hosting rewards, and set their own competitive prices within certain limits&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A marketplace of capacity will make it easier for users to find and rent capacity&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To attract serious cloud customers at a commercial level, robust uptime and performance guarantees will be ensured through Service Level Agreements, KYC will be introduced for reliability, competitive pricing will keep customers happy, and simplified products and approach will make for a better user experience&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A quality-based reward system will motivate cloud hosts to provide reliable service, while the flexible earnings model makes hosting more appealing&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A new token will launch on a high profile blockchain&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, there are a variety of elements coming together to ensure a sustainable and healthy ecosystem to grow decentralized cloud and Internet capacity around the world.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-team&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Team&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An experienced team has been gathered around our DePIN launch, complementing the existing core team members. This combination of talent has a range of backgrounds and a collective understanding of how the $INCA token can bring a strong ecosytem for all stakeholders. This will be the natural evolution and continuation of what has been built by the ThreeFold team and community until today.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Michael Wellesley-Wesley&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Team lead, co-founder of Green Edge and a long-time member of the farming community.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;George Olver&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: An expert in the DePIN space, providing day-to-day leadership.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nick Hawkes and Max Gold&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Partners under &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;goldandhawks.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Gold Hawks&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, proficient in scaling DePIN ecosystem and historically part of the Helium and Solana communities.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quentin Issele&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Formerly of OKEx, specializing in liquidity and marketing.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rob Beland&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Founder of &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.depinconnect.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;DePIN Connect&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, with vast marketing and influencer connections.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Theo Chapman&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Managing Director of &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;zonaris.io&quot;&gt;Zonaris&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, coordinating execution within group.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mariza Wellesley-Wesley&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: A well-versed lawyer overseeing regulatory and legal aspects, co-founder of &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;green-edge.net&#x2F;en&quot;&gt;Green Edge&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sabrina Sadik and Mik Perrault&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Our vital connectors between the Internet Capacity and ThreeFold teams.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-inca-token&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The $INCA Token&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many questions have risen about the introduction of a new token to the ThreeFold ecosystem. $INCA should be seen as an extension of $TFT. It will co-exist with $TFT, both convertible and usable across TF Grid 3 and TF Grid 4. The primary differences are:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Higher Profile&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: $INCA will likely have a more prominent presence, especially on Solana.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tokenomics&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: $INCA will support app development, marketing, and community growth grants.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Max Cap&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Both tokens share a four-billion max cap, with $INCA providing an opportunity to double $TFT holdings (one $TFT converts to two $INCA).&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;benefits-for-tft-holders&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Benefits for $TFT Holders&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For $TFT holders, the benefits are clear:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Swapping&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Each $TFT converts to two $INCA (during 2024), enabling easy entry for token holders.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Market Presence&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: $INCA’s launch in the DePIN sector on Solana positions it in a visible and attractive market.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Limited Supply&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: The initial supply of $INCA will be limited, which could drive demand and price up.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;together-we-build&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Together We Build&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, while the Internet Capacity project brings a new chapter, it is really a continuation, simplification, and amplification of the ThreeFold journey. We anticipate exciting developments as we prepare for the TF Grid 4.0 launch and the introduction of the $INCA. We are happy to address any questions you may have on &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&quot;&gt;our forum&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; or &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefold&quot;&gt;our main chat&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, keeping in mind that we are still refining many aspects of this project.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Onward! Keep building, friends.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>ThreeFold Today, Tomorrow, &amp; Beyond</title>
        <published>2023-01-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2023-01-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/today-tomorrow-beyond/"/>
        <id>https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/today-tomorrow-beyond/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/today-tomorrow-beyond/">&lt;p&gt;It’s the beginning of another year, so I thought it would be a good time to put things into perspective with where we are and where we’re going.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;threefold-today&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Today&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s be honest. There is no other project or technology out there like ThreeFold, no one nearly as far along as we are. Our co-founders have decades of experience (and success) in the Internet and Cloud space. They and the team developed a new Internet infrastructure from the ground up, including a &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;threefold__zos&quot;&gt;stateless operating system&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; based on the Linux kernel, which is quite a significant accomplishment.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, we have the biggest network of decentralized storage, compute, and network on the planet. The technology is in its third generation, functional and ready for utilization, even commercially. The &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;play.grid.tf&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Playground&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; provides a sandbox of limitless opportunities for open-source builders – developers can (and are) now build(ing) and monetize(ing) projects built on the grid.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully you’ve been following along lately with community calls and all of our updates to see the &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;end-of-year-2022-community-call-recording&#x2F;3636&quot;&gt;major progress that was made in 2022&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. The technology took major strides, the grid nearly doubled, the community got way more active, and there are some partnerships in the works with huge reach where we can make big impact.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course the token price is low and this is less than ideal to say the least, especially for farmers who are running hardware and weary of costs – although a power savings feature is coming! But the token is built on strong fundamentals and our efforts are focused on creating a &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;a-new-financial-system-is-needed-for-a-better-future&#x2F;3547&quot;&gt;balanced and sustainable token economy&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for the long-term.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;threefold-tomorrow&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Tomorrow&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the coming days we’ll be announcing a super exciting project (ThreeFold Grid Services) from the ThreeFold team with the following purpose:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;To prove that the current state of the ThreeFold Grid is enough on top of which to start an end-user facing commercial business. We will release a suite of grid services with fiat gateways and we will also create content that explains in steps how to use the technical building blocks to put it all together to create your own solution &#x2F; service.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within Q1 we also aim to expose one or several partnerships with the potential to impact millions of people in emerging &#x2F; developing countries.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have ThreeFold Ventures coming as well, different businesses or arms of ThreeFold including OurPhone that create a holistic ecosystem for a more fair and equal world.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then there’s the &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;internet-of-internets&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Internet of Internets&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (Regional Internet) model which will come to life this year, and &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;digital-twin&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Digital Twin&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. And more – this is not comprehensive – but you get the picture.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;threefold-beyond&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Beyond&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold is the foundation for people around the world to live in true digital sovereignty, for people who today do not have affordable access to education, communication, and financial tools to gain access. ThreeFold can impact industries from Internet to banking to education to supply chain and more. The possibilities are really limitless, let your imagine run wild. ThreeFold can change the world.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;our-future-is-up-to-all-of-us&quot;&gt;Our Future Is up to All of Us&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve said this before, I’ll say it again (and again) … A decentralized movement is all about decentralized action and participation. And participation comes in all shapes and sizes. Together, we all need to act and push this into the world. Everyone in this community is empowered to help the project succeed though their own initiatives. The team is of course happy to offer support through technical help and even token grants. ThreeFold will be a success if people continue to choose to believe it is important and dedicate their energy towards it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold can and needs to be a complete, end-to-end decentralized ecosystem empowering all its members to build and create. We have everything we need, and if we don’t, let’s solve it. Most importantly, we have each other. Let’s do this.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to get involved, the &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&quot;&gt;forum&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefold&quot;&gt;two-way chat&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefoldfarmers&quot;&gt;farmers chat&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, and &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold&quot;&gt;library&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; &#x2F; &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;manual&#x2F;#&#x2F;&quot;&gt;manual&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; are great places to get started.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>How would Decentralisation of the Internet help India?</title>
        <published>2023-01-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2023-01-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/decentralised-internet-india/"/>
        <id>https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/decentralised-internet-india/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/decentralised-internet-india/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-would-decentralisation-of-the-internet-help-india&quot;&gt;How would Decentralisation of the Internet help India?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“This article was originally published by Ashish Bansal, a former member of ThreeFold Foundation.”&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ashish Bansal has been a member of the ThreeFold support team since October 2021. He was born in India. Ashish believes that we all deserve a better internet which is free, decentralized and equal for all.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Internet has become one of the most important aspects of human life. Our everyday lives are impacted by social media and other online platforms on a very minute level. Facebook, Instagram, WhatsApp and others have become the most convenient way to stay in touch with friends and family. WhiteHart, Udemy and others have made quality education accessible to all. Swiggy, Zomato and others have made our favourite cuisine accessible at home. Amazon, Flipkart and others have grown the shopping experience for Indians with a variety of choices. Netflix, Hotstar, Youtube and others have made entertainment on demand easy for us.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the past decade, we have all gotten addicted to the comforts that the internet has brought to us, and it wouldn’t be wrong for us to say that we cannot imagine our lives without the internet.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Indian internet usage ranks second in the world today behind China, with 43% of its total population online, this also means that there is still a lot of untapped potential in India.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;issues-with-current-internet&quot;&gt;Issues with current Internet&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although the internet has helped us in making our lives comfortable, there are several issues with the current Internet services we use. Some of them are mentioned below:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;cyber-security&quot;&gt;Cyber security&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cyber security infrastructure in India today is not well equipped to tackle increasing cyber-crimes. You may not have the resolution to your complaints filed with Cyber Cell Portals on time. Hence there is an increasing number of fraudsters and hackers in India.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;data-ownership&quot;&gt;Data ownership&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personal details shared by you on the internet are used by big companies to influence your decision-making process strategically.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;higher-cost-to-customers&quot;&gt;Higher cost to customers&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since internet infrastructure is owned and controlled by a few big companies, there is an irregular price increase which makes the internet unaffordable to many parts of rural India.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;decentralised-internet-is-the-solution&quot;&gt;Decentralised Internet is the solution&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Decentralisation of the internet refers to the arrangement of the internet or its components such that no single entity or organization has control or authority over the network. It  holds the potential to revolutionize the way every nation accesses and utilizes the world wide web. India, one of the biggest players in the digital world, can greatly benefit from Internet decentralization. It would open up many new opportunities for both the country and its citizens.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To start, decentralization of the internet would give India more control over its digital landscape. Instead of relying on a single, centralized entity to power its network, India could decentralize its internet and make the administration of the network much more efficient. With this additional control and efficiency, India could develop a more secure and reliable infrastructure, while also controlling the delivery of services. This could lead to faster, more reliable connection speeds, along with increased safety and security.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, decentralization of the internet would allow India to establish itself as a technological leader. By decentralizing the internet, India could shift its focus from the existing internet infrastructure to developing innovative technology and applications. This could include the development of decentralized artificial intelligence, blockchain technology, and much more. Potential applications of these technologies could drastically improve the education, healthcare, and transportation sectors of India.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, decentralization of the internet could help with digital media access and distribution. This could open up new opportunities for providing access to digital media in rural areas, allowing for more effective access to education and entertainment. Furthermore, it could also provide access to more reliable payment services, as well as better consumer protection policies.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, decentralization of the internet holds the potential to greatly benefit India and its citizens. It would give India control over its internet infrastructure, opening the door for development of innovative technologies and applications. Additionally, it could provide more effective access to digital media, along with more reliable payment services and consumer protection policies. In order for India to take full advantage of the potential of decentralization of the internet, it must take decisive steps towards implementing the necessary reforms and investments to ensure its success.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-threefold-can-contribute&quot;&gt;How ThreeFold can contribute&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold technology runs on the concept of a grid formed by farmers who are independent people, unlike big corporations, that connect their nodes anywhere network and electricity is present to create a global distributed internet infrastructure. This resolves the problem of monopoly and price of big internet companies.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The technology also ensures that you get data security which was how the internet was originally intended to be.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To know more of ThreeFold technology and start farming:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dive into &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&quot;&gt;the ThreeFold Library&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get a node from &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;marketplace.3node.global&#x2F;index.php&quot;&gt;the Official ThreeFold webshop&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Build your &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;farming&#x2F;threefold__diy_guide&quot;&gt;own node&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Or join us on &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefold&quot;&gt;our two-way chat&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>ThreeFold: An Organisation Building a Decentralized Internet</title>
        <published>2022-11-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2022-11-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/an-org-building-a-decentralized-internet/"/>
        <id>https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/an-org-building-a-decentralized-internet/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/an-org-building-a-decentralized-internet/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;threefold-an-organisation-building-a-decentralized-internet&quot;&gt;ThreeFold: An Organisation Building a Decentralized Internet&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Disclaimer: This blog has been written by ThreeFold community member Drew Smith, and was originally a Reddit post. The team found so much value within it that we felt it was important to give it a permanent space within the ThreeFold Blogs collection, and Drew agreed to this. Besides a few grammatical corrections and minor contextual tweaks, the content has not been edited – and you can find the original post &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.reddit.com&#x2F;user&#x2F;DrewSmith214&#x2F;comments&#x2F;yhym2f&#x2F;an_organization_building_a_decentralized_internet&#x2F;&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Greetings fellow decentralization lovers, I am in search of people looking to contribute to what is now the largest decentralized network in the world, working towards the goal of providing a decentralized internet that breaks down barriers to information and compute resource access. Our network provides digital equality to all users while placing the control of their data back into their hands.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project I’m discussing is &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Threefold.io&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, this is a project that currently has nearly 3000 Bare-Metal** **nodes in 64 countries allowing anyone in the world to deploy an industry standard VPS on the decentralized infrastructure with no involvement of the centralized cloud providers, This is a network meant to be used by everyone that can be expanded by anyone. You can check out a current map of the nodes online on the &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;dashboard.grid.tf&#x2F;explorer&#x2F;statistics&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Explorer&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ThreeFold Grid consists of three synergistic layers: The Nodes, The Network, and the BlockChain.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Nodes:&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; These are hardware that gives its grid its power, The requirements for running a 3Node are a bare metal x86_64 machine and a reliable internet connection. These nodes can be hosted in a variety of environments spanning at home deployments to rented-space DC’s. This includes DC’s themselves being able to bring capacity online so long as it’s a fully bare metal device.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;plug and play solutions&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; for bringing a 3Node online on the [3Node marketplace](https:&#x2F;&#x2F;marketplace.3node.global&#x2F;index.php?dispatch= categories.view&amp;amp;category_id=167), this marketplace includes node offerings from both the organizations itself as well as multiple independent businesses that have become certified 3Node Resellers.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re familiar with the concepts of building a server&#x2F;pc you can also bring your hardware online as &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;D.I.Y 3Node&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; this allows you to contribute any additional hardware you may have in your deployment to the support of both the grids network and compute capacity. you can find documentation on D.I.Y nodes on the &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;diy-nodes-guide&#x2F;837&quot;&gt;Forums&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; or in the &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;farming&#x2F;threefold__diy_guide&quot;&gt;Wiki&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each node is booted using a fully in house developed autonomous operating system that automates both node deployment and workloads being deployed on the node after its online, called &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;threefoldtech&#x2F;zos&quot;&gt;Zero-OS&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. This OS is a hypervisor environment that accepts commands from and is managed by the block-chain.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Network(s):&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; The grid is supported by multiple internal and external networks that allow for the nodes to function as a decentralized data center. This is made of two major components.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Z-Net&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;- is an internal private overlay network between VMs, Kubernetes Nodes, Containers and the grid. This network allows for minimal usage of Public ipv4 space while still allowing for global deployment solutions encompassing multiple 3Nodes.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Planetary Network-&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; This is a peer to peer end to encrypted network solution based on opensource technologies (yggdrasil) that allow grid users to create, develop and overlay networks designed to protect users ability to communicate and access information. You can find the github Repo &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;threefoldtech&#x2F;planetary_network&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, with 3000 endpoints all controlled by a single DAO, the potential exists to create the most reliable peer to peer mesh in existence.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Public IPv4-&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; Threefold farmers have the ability to add Public Ipv4 to the grid in addition to their compute capacity, these IPs can be deployed as gateway addresses in support of the grid, or rented by end users for their workloads, at the time of this writing the threefold grid has 1114 Public Ipv4 addresses available for use. you can find documentation on adding I.P addresses to the grid &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;diy-public-node-guide&#x2F;3340&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The BlockChain:&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; the blockchain technologies built into the Threefold Grid represent what makes the grid truly unique and allows it to be utilized to support customer facing workloads or provide a decentralized compute resource pool. grid utilization is supported and created through two avenues&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Individuals:&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; can deploy any workload they need on any node on the grid, if it can run on Linux it can run on the grid, this type of use is supported by the &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;play.grid.tf&#x2F;#&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Threefold Playground&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, a decentralized deployment solution that provides industry standard Linux vps deployments as multiple use case specific deployment solutions for &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;kubernetes.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Kubernetes&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;caprover.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Caprover&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;joinpeertube.org&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Peertube&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;funkwhale.audio&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Funkwhale&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;mattermost.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Mattermost&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.discourse.org&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Discourse&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.taiga.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Taiga&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;owncloud.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Owncloud&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;presearch.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Presearch&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;subsquid.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;SubSquid&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;casperlabs.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;CasperLabs&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, and &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;nodepilot.tech&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Node Pilot&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Custom VM images cab be uploaded to the &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;hub.grid.tf&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Threefold Hub&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; allowing full deployment customization with any Linux os image supporting cloud-init. Documentation on creating custom images can be found &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;manipulating-cloud-images-for-the-grid&#x2F;3380&quot;&gt;On the Forums&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Storage workloads can be deployed using &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;threefoldtech&#x2F;terraform-provider-grid&quot;&gt;Terraform&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; with offerings of HDD, SSD and &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;threefoldtech&#x2F;terraform-provider-grid&quot;&gt;Quantum Safe File Storage&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Solution Providers&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: these are developers of user facing services that utilize the grid as their hosting platform. These organizations&#x2F;individuals are able to develop customized solutions that provide needed services in their market and receive rewards for the utilization that their developments bring. A great example of this is &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;zonaris.con&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Zonaris&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, which is a third party organization that is quickly taking the lead in grid solution development. They have recently released an interface that allows end users to deploy &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;streamr.network&#x2F;discover&#x2F;network&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Streamr&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; nodes on the Threefold grid while paying in fiat currency. you can get started with them at &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;get.zonaris.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Get Zonaris&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This allows developers to invest in only their code while having the infrastructure of a worldwide virtual data center at their disposal to scale their solutions with their business needs.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Solution providers are able to automate their tools being deployed on the grid using &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;threefoldtech&#x2F;terraform-provider-grid&quot;&gt;Terraform&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What this has all truly come together to form is an organization where anyone can contribute to building a more private and secure internet that is designed to allow universal access to information and compute power regardless of the end user’s nationality or beliefs. Threefold truly exists to capitalize on the ideal economies from every corner of the world, in order to provide a better digital future for all.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What Can You Do?&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much of what you see today at Threefold.io is the work of 100s of decentralized contributors working together towards a common goal. The grid is designed so that anyone can contribute whether you’re a developer, a property owner, an I.S.P, or just someone with a spare computer and a network connection. As it stands the grid is strong and well supported across the world. The biggest impact that can be made today is by developing solutions that leverage the grid and use its resources to bring affordable and accessible hosting to end users.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many discussions happening on the &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&quot;&gt;Threefold Forum&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; about partnerships with other projects and how we can better support both the crypto landscape and the general internet user base. Even by just joining discussions on the Threefold Forum and providing your input and ideas you can help to make sure that the internet of tomorrow is built for and by the users of tomorrow. but there are lots of ways to contribute:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can purchase the TFT token following &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.manual.grid.tf&#x2F;documentation&#x2F;threefold_token&#x2F;buy_sell_tft&#x2F;tft_lobstr&#x2F;tft_lobstr_short_guide.html&quot;&gt;this guide&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can learn about farming &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;farming&#x2F;threefold__farming_intro&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can learn more about the Threefold Cloud and Deploying &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;cloud&#x2F;threefold__cloud_home&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Written by Drew Smith&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>An Open Invitation for Testing</title>
        <published>2022-10-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2022-10-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/open-invitation-for-testing/"/>
        <id>https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/open-invitation-for-testing/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/open-invitation-for-testing/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“This article was originally published by Hannah Cordes, a former member of ThreeFold Foundation.”&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ThreeFold technology, ecosystem and community have the potential to kickstart a new Internet era filled with abundance and opportunities for all. ThreeFold is 100% open-source, so anyone can contribute to ThreeFold on GitHub and build their own solutions and applications on ThreeFold’s infrastructure.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now’s the time to start utilizing what we’ve built together and to start deploying the solutions and experiences we want to see in this world. Now’s the time to build better alternatives for people, enterprises and governments on top of this foundational infrastructure.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We invite you all to come in, see what’s possible, and start building – today!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-is-testing-so-crucial&quot;&gt;Why is testing so crucial?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold created an open-source peer-to-peer Internet infrastructure that offers a place for developers, end-users and everyone in-between to collectively build an open digital world with full digital sovereignty. We seek to re-imagine business, governance, finance, education and more to build a better future for all.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This future can only be achieved with the collaboration of a strong, healthy and dedicated community. One of the key challenges for a project like ours is the continuous testing and improving of new features as well as building all of the applications and solutions we’d like to see to enhance and grow the ecosystem. Community contributions are the heart and a crucial driver of the growing ThreeFold movement – a global movement that is open and decentralized, meaning it is up to each and everyone of us to push things forward.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No matter your experience level, from developers to end-users and everyone in-between, there are options for you to contribute to ThreeFold. Whether you’re more tech-savvy and would like to develop solutions on top of the Grid and test tech features or rather help us improve the manuals and spread the word, there are many ways to take action and support the movement.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A reliable, open-source peer-to-peer infrastructure together with a growing community of enthusiastic, driven developers and end-users are the key to accelerating the growth and development of the Grid and to unlocking all of its potential. And the more people believe in ThreeFold and our Internet of Internets vision, the sooner we can bring digital sovereignty, empowerment and meaningful experiences to the world.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-should-you-join-threefold-s-tester-community&quot;&gt;Why should you join ThreeFold’s tester community?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So why get involved in ThreeFold? Well first of all, you can join an engaged, open movement that seeks to shape the future we want to live in and provide better solutions for our planet and people. You can meet, exchange and collaborate with people from all over the world that share similar interests and values.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You also learn new skills and get to know some innovative technology that enables you to build and test pretty cool applications and solutions – like deploying a Subsquid instance on the &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;play.grid.tf&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Playground&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; or checking out the different decentralized alternatives to solutions we use every day like WhatsApp, YouTube, Chrome or Zoom with &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;demo.freeflow.life&quot;&gt;FreeFlow Twin&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Our open, friendly and skilled community can offer you support and advice as you start testing and building. Let’s help each other and build cool stuff together!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-threefold-community-where-ideas-come-to-life&quot;&gt;The ThreeFold Community – Where ideas come to life&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Curious about what fellow community members are building on ThreeFold? Here are a few recent examples:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Teisie has been working on a few great tools to make things easier for his fellow ThreeFolders like an iOS app for node monitoring and a geo explorer. Moreover, he’s been working on an uptime tool and deployment calculator – hosted on the Grid and using Drew’s gateway node for public access. Learn more &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;teisies-uptime-tool-and-deployment-calculator&#x2F;3384?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Well done, Teisie!&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Another skilled community member building on the Grid is Drew. With his &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;cockpit-managed-ubuntu-vm&#x2F;3376?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;community project&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for a Cockpit management interface, he provides a web-based interface for managing a VM that allows users to do a lot of maintenance tasks without ssh – even including full remote desktop capabilities from the browser. Pretty cool, right?&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what are you waiting for? Start exploring and using the many solutions on the ThreeFold Grid today – whether by deploying a weblet, testing the FreeFlow Twin or simply joining our testing group!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-get-started&quot;&gt;How to get started?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many ways to get started with ThreeFold. If you’re new to ThreeFold in general, I recommend starting with “&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;how-threefold-is-building-a-new-internet-from-the-ground-up&#x2F;2057?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;Building a New Internet From the Ground Up&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;” – an approachable blog series on the inner workings of the Grid.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A great way to learn more is also by checking out the &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.docsend.com&#x2F;view&#x2F;7x2pezpn2548v8qq&#x2F;d&#x2F;an66sngk5h3yf2zk&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Litepaper&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and by exploring the &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold&#x2F;#&#x2F;&quot;&gt;knowledge base&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. The ThreeFold Grid &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;manual&#x2F;#&#x2F;&quot;&gt;manual&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; has everything you need to dive right into ThreeFold’s open-source infrastructure and technology.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Key resources to get started:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find out what you &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;manual&#x2F;#&#x2F;manual__faq?id=what-can-i-do-on-threefold-grid&quot;&gt;can do on Threefold Grid&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dive into the &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;manual&#x2F;#&#x2F;&quot;&gt;manual&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to get started&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn more about &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;manual&#x2F;#&#x2F;manual__grid3_testing?id=testing-the-threefold_grid3&quot;&gt;testing&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; the Grid&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Join our &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefoldtesting&quot;&gt;testing community&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Watch helpful tutorials from the community in the &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;threefold-video-gallery&#x2F;3091?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Video Gallery&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn how to &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;how-to-contribute-to-threefold-wikis-and-websites&#x2F;1154&quot;&gt;contribute to ThreeFold wikis and websites&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Build on ThreeFold’s Open Infrastructure – Part Three: Weblets &amp; End-Users</title>
        <published>2022-09-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2022-09-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/build-on-threefolds-open-infrastructure-part-three/"/>
        <id>https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/build-on-threefolds-open-infrastructure-part-three/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/build-on-threefolds-open-infrastructure-part-three/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“This article was originally published by Hannah Cordes, a former member of ThreeFold Foundation.”&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post is the third one in a series about building on ThreeFold’s open infrastructure. While &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;build-on-threefolds-open-infrastructure&#x2F;&quot;&gt;part one&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, gives you a comprehensive overview of the Grid, its evolution and capabilities, the &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;build-on-threefolds-open-infrastructure-part-two&#x2F;&quot;&gt;second part&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is focused on the low-level building blocks and particularly interesting for the more tech-savvy crowd.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the third and final part of our series on ThreeFold’s game-changing Internet infrastructure and the solutions available today. This time, we’ll show you what’s possible on the ThreeFold Playground today and how you can become one of the first testers of digitally sovereign end-user experiences.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an incredible opportunity to become early adopters of our unique solutions, to get a taste of what it means to become digitally sovereign, and to help shape the future of the Internet. Together we build a decentralized digital world!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;explore-a-playground-full-of-simple-yet-powerful-deployment-experiences&quot;&gt;Explore a playground full of simple yet powerful deployment experiences&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;play.grid.tf&#x2F;&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Playground&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; makes it quite easy to build on top of the ThreeFold Grid by deploying weblets. A &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;manual&#x2F;#&#x2F;manual__weblets_home?id=weblets&quot;&gt;weblet&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is a compiled JavaScript component which can be embedded in any site. With ThreeFold, it basically establishes a private environment running inside your browser, and allows you to share it – while you maintain full control of all activities happening there by using your private key, and with full decentralization.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the TF Playground, a variety of applications are made available and deployable within just a few clicks, all on top of a fully decentralized peer-to-peer Internet infrastructure. From Virtual Machines to Kubernetes to Presearch Nodes, CapRover, ownCloud, and more – the playground allows you to build in a truly decentralized environment. Essentially, the Playground is an ever-expanding ecosystem of easily-deployable weblets that are built for a decentralized future. It’s the fastest way to build, test, and deploy and enables pretty much anyone to build and experiment with deployment on the Grid. So, this is huge!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;play.grid.tf&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Visit&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; the TF Playground to explore the possibilities and read this &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;threefold-product-focus-series-tf-playground-v3-7-0&#x2F;3315?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;post&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to find out what the new version 3.7.0 of the Playground – now live on testnet – has to offer. Dive right in and &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;manual&#x2F;#&#x2F;getstarted&#x2F;manual__tfgrid3_getstarted&quot;&gt;get started&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on the TF Grid today!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are a few examples of the weblets available on the Playground:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;presearch&quot;&gt;Presearch&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presearch is a longstanding partner of ThreeFold and one of the most popular solutions offered on the Grid. As of the Grid v3.6 release, any 3Node can now host a Presearch node – so if you’re a ThreeFold farmer, it’s now become quite easy for you to host Presearch on your own node. Simply follow &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;presearch-nodes&#x2F;3250?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;this deployment guide&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to get decentralized search on top of a truly decentralized infrastructure!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;caprover&quot;&gt;CapRover&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leverage the entire &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;caprover-your-app-environment&#x2F;2133&#x2F;3&quot;&gt;CapRover app catalogue&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; even faster and easier and deploy CapRover apps on the ThreeFold Grid. You’ll benefit from full decentralization, energy efficiency and affordability. &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;create-your-own-app-environment-fast-and-easy-with-caprover-on-the-people-s-internet&#x2F;2644?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;CapRover&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is a powerful platform for app deployment and thanks to our &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;manual&#x2F;#&#x2F;manual__weblets_caprover?id=caprover&quot;&gt;CapRover weblet&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, you’re able to deploy anything you want on top of the ThreeFold Grid!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;new-subsquid-testnet&quot;&gt;NEW: Subsquid (testnet)&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;tfgrid-v3-7-0-is-now-live&#x2F;3375?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;latest addition&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to the ThreeFold Playground is &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;manual&#x2F;#&#x2F;manual__weblets_subsquid&quot;&gt;Subsquid&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, Web3’s premier API framework which is supercharging decentralized apps across more than 30 chains. Basically, you can think of Subsquid as an ETL (extract, transform, load) tool, with a GraphQL server included. With Grid v3.7.0 live on testnet, you can now pre-process and decode raw chain data and store it for easier access by the query nodes by deploying your own Subsquid instance on the Grid’s testnet within just a few clicks &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;play.test.grid.tf&#x2F;#&#x2F;subsquid&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So with the ThreeFold Playground, ThreeFold is building a vast ecosystem of advanced deployment experiences and opening up a world of possibilities – allowing anyone to build, test and deploy easily and within a few clicks.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the best thing about the &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;manual&#x2F;#&#x2F;getstarted&#x2F;manual__tfgrid3_getstarted&quot;&gt;playground&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;? It’s already been available for a while and continuously being improved and extended!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-achieve-digital-sovereignty-with-a-set-of-end-user-experiences&quot;&gt;How to achieve digital sovereignty with a set of end-user experiences&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Through simple, secure, and scalable technology, ThreeFold empowers millions to invent and explore new experiences.“ – &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.threefold.io&#x2F;newsroom&#x2F;paradise-hills&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Kristof de Spiegeleer&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve entered the &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;four-phases-of-threefold&#x2F;&quot;&gt;third phase of our journey&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; towards our ultimate vision of a better future – the phase of Web 4. In addition to fully comprehensive decentralized edge cloud solutions, the ThreeFold ecosystem is also developing a range of applications and experiences across IoT, metaverse, blockchain, DeFi, banking, education and beyond.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout this phase – which has only just begun – a multitude of valuable and meaningful experiences are being built by the ThreeFold ecosystem and partners to empower people with equal chances to learn, create, and thrive in a decentralized digital economy – what we like to call an abundance-based future for humanity.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first roll-out of the third phase will empower people to become fully self-sovereign thanks to ThreeFold’s Digital Twin technology and a variety of decentralized alternatives to popular applications and tools. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;freeflow-twin&quot;&gt;FreeFlow Twin&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Digital Twin technology provides each user with a unique digital identity that can serve as the key to an open, self-sovereign and complete digital future. This solution was designed with a very simple objective in mind: everyone should be the center of their entire digital life. It represents your digital self and hosts your entire digital life in a secure and private way – empowering you to own your data and offering you decentralized applications that enable you to maintain your sovereignty. For end users, owning their own deployments opens the possibility for a full range of experiences that have the same quality as crypto – self custody.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Grid V3.7.0, ThreeFold’s all-in-one decentralized productivity tool that includes instant messaging, video call, social, and data storage features – formerly known as Uhuru – is being rebranded to &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;lets-test-out-freeflow-twin-beta-formerly-uhuru&#x2F;3299?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;FreeFlow Twin&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. It brings sovereign and secure alternatives to many of the centralized solutions we use every day like Facebook, WhatsApp, YouTube, Chrome, Zoom and many more.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;threefold-product-updates-august-2022&#x2F;3272?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;FreeFlow Twin&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; will be part of an ecosystem of decentralized alternatives called FreeFlow Life. Find more information on the experiences, how to start testing now and where to share your feedback &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;lets-test-out-freeflow-twin-beta-formerly-uhuru&#x2F;3299?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This paradigm shift is a pretty big deal, isn’t it?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;defi-solutions&quot;&gt;DeFi Solutions&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve also decided to develop our &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;future-tft-ecosystem&#x2F;&quot;&gt;own DeFi solutions&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to support the growth and expansion of the Internet of Internets and an abundance-based future where we are truly sovereign: community-based liquidity pools and the P2P DeFi Wallet – both expected early next year. Learn more about the upcoming solutions &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;future-tft-ecosystem&#x2F;&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-grid-is-open-an-invitation-to-build-deploy-and-test&quot;&gt;The Grid is open – an invitation to build, deploy and test&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold’s open Internet infrastructure is fully peer-to-peer, decentralized and super reliable. It already offers a multitude of solutions for developers, end-users and everyone in-between. And the Grid and the solutions offered are ready for the community to build, deploy and test, as we continue to collectively build, advance and expand.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And while we’ve collectively already built a lot and achieved crucial milestones towards realizing our ultimate goals, we’re also just the beginning of the third phase of our exciting journey with many ambitions and goals still ahead.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While we’re still in a spot where we can be considered a hidden gem and being way undervalued, remember this: ThreeFold is inevitable. We are visionaries, building the plane in the air. We are confident in growing the project in a real and authentic way. We have a strong plan and vision. Our technology is needed. The underlying foundation is functional and ready. Now, it’s up to the believers to build, test and deploy the solutions we need for a better world. And together, we build. Together, we can achieve the extraordinary and provide better alternatives for people, enterprises and governments.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We not only invite you to come see what’s possible. We invite you to get involved. What are you waiting for?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Start exploring and using the many solutions on the ThreeFold Grid today – whether by deploying a weblet, testing the FreeFlow Twin or simply joining our &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefoldtesting&quot;&gt;testing group&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;build-on-threefolds-open-infrastructure&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Build on ThreeFold’s Open Infrastructure – Part One: Intro&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;build-on-threefolds-open-infrastructure-part-two&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Build on ThreeFold’s Open Infrastructure – Part Two: For Experts&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Not sure where to start? Dive into the &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;manual&#x2F;#&#x2F;&quot;&gt;manual&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and learn more about &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;manual&#x2F;#&#x2F;manual__grid3_testing?id=testing-the-threefold_grid3&quot;&gt;testing the ThreeFold Grid&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Build on ThreeFold’s Open Infrastructure – Part Two: For Experts</title>
        <published>2022-09-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2022-09-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/build-on-threefolds-open-infrastructure-part-two/"/>
        <id>https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/build-on-threefolds-open-infrastructure-part-two/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/build-on-threefolds-open-infrastructure-part-two/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“This article was originally published by Hannah Cordes, a former member of ThreeFold Foundation.”&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold’s reliable, open-source, peer-to-peer Internet infrastructure together with a growing community of enthusiastic, driven early-adopter developers and end-users are the key to accelerating the growth and development of the Grid and to unlocking all of its potential. While the foundation has been laid, it will be up to all of us as a movement to improve and build upon it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After looking back at the ThreeFold Grid’s evolution and what makes it a game-changing Internet infrastructure in &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;build-on-threefolds-open-infrastructure&#x2F;&quot;&gt;part one&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, it’s time to explore our cloud solution and the technology available today in part two! You can think of these as some of the essential low-level building blocks that when combined created a limitless sandbox for developers.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re wondering what virtual machines are, haven’t heard about Kubernetes before and don’t know your way around coding languages, this part might be less interesting for you. Feel free to skip and jump right into &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;build-on-threefolds-open-infrastructure-part-three&#x2F;&quot;&gt;part three&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on weblets and end-user experiences.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;elements-of-our-comprehensive-decentralized-cloud-solution&quot;&gt;Elements of our comprehensive &amp;amp; decentralized cloud solution&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ThreeFold Grid provides &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;technology&#x2F;threefold__tfgrid_primitives&quot;&gt;various primitives&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for compute, storage, and network – fulfilling all the needs centralized cloud providers cater to as well, while offering advantages in terms of decentralization, energy efficiency, security and more. &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;all-you-need-to-know-about-zero-os&#x2F;1734&quot;&gt;Zero-OS&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; includes a collection of components, called primitives. These primitives are the low-level constructs which can be deployed on the ThreeFold Grid. As mentioned above, they act as building blocks for skilled developers that enable them to build and create in complete digital freedom.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, the high compatibility of ThreeFold’s primitives with industry-standard tools and protocols makes it easy and seamless for developers to migrate workloads to the Grid. All of the primitives not only benefit from the unique efficiency and security features of &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;technology&#x2F;threefold__zos&quot;&gt;Zero-OS&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, but also come with unique features and capabilities themselves. Here are some of the primitives to give you an idea of what you’ll get:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;zmachine&quot;&gt;ZMachine&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold’s &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;technology&#x2F;zmachine?id=zmachine&quot;&gt;ZMachine&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is a lightweight virtual machine (VM) solution that’s unique to the ThreeFold Grid. ZMachine enables both traditional VM deployments and also introduces a next generation container specification built on our &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;technology&#x2F;threefold__zos_fs?id=why-this-zflist-concept&quot;&gt;ZFlist&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; technology. ZFlist containers enabled by ZMachines are more secure and more flexible than the current industry standard Docker-based containers. With Kubernetes running on top of ThreeFold’s ZMachine &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;threefold__grid_use?id=tfgrid-kubernetes-cloud&quot;&gt;technology&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, we have a highly compatible and unique solution.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;zflist&quot;&gt;ZFlist&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;technology&#x2F;threefold__zos_fs?id=why-this-zflist-concept&quot;&gt;ZFlist&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is a next generation container format – supported directly at the operating system level on Zero-OS – which extends the industry-standard Docker container concept in an efficient and secure way. It provides a unique advantage over traditional containers via the use of mini VMs. By employing mini VMs, the FList concept provides better isolation than traditional container systems while retaining the advantages that containers offer over full VMs.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;kubernetes&quot;&gt;Kubernetes&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold has long supported the most used open-source container orchestration tool in the world, &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;kubernetes.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Kubernetes&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, which integrates the industry standard &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.docker.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Docker&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; format, a container creation and management tool. It’s used to manage many of the largest and most complex cloud deployments. Kubernetes can be used to create a production-ready environment. The ThreeFold Grid provides a lightweight Kubernetes VM that can be used to create clusters according to specific needs. By providing both VMs and Kubernetes, we’re able to offer the most comprehensive solution in the decentralized&#x2F;blockchain space to deploy, scale, and manage cloud compute workloads. Kubernetes users can, for the most part, simply bring their existing configuration files and recreate their deployments on a Grid based cluster seamlessly. With the third generation of the Grid, we provided a very simple way to provision &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;manual&#x2F;#&#x2F;manual3_iac&#x2F;grid3_terraform&#x2F;manual__terraform_k8s?id=more-info&quot;&gt;Kubernetes clusters with Terraform&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;terraform&quot;&gt;Terraform&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;threefold-grid-3-0-supports-terraform&#x2F;1184?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;Terraform&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is a widely-used open-source Infrastructure as Code (IaC) software tool enabling a consistent workflow in order to manage complex deployments across different cloud providers. It also integrates directly with our Grid’s &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;cloud&#x2F;threefold__usp_compatible?id=kubernetes&quot;&gt;existing Kubernetes functionality&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to offer a complete solution for reserving hardware and deploying software.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a nutshell, Terraform offers a complete solution for reserving hardware and deploying software. It allows for specifying deployments on the &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;threefold__tfgrid_home&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Grid&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; in a simple, declarative, and human-readable language describing the desired end state. Terraform can be used to deploy the full set of &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;all-you-need-to-know-about-zero-os&#x2F;1734&quot;&gt;Zero-OS&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; primitives, supporting any existing or future Linux workload, with endless possibilities. It is like a lower-level Kubernetes for the hardware part of cloud deployments.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;dedicated-nodes&quot;&gt;Dedicated Nodes&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re also supporting &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;exciting-news-dedicated-nodes-on-the-people-s-internet&#x2F;2645?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;dedicated nodes&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. By utilizing dedicated nodes on the ThreeFold Grid, you’ll benefit from a truly decentralized and highly reliable Internet infrastructure that uses less energy and comes at a much more affordable price than any comparable alternative. With dedicated nodes, users are able to exclusively reserve the entire capacity of a 3Node to deploy solutions for themselves or for other customers, while also paying for all capacity of the respective 3Node. Dedicated nodes on our Grid will be highly cost effective, as they’ll be available with a 70% discount on &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;pricing-for-tfgrid&#x2F;2518&#x2F;7&quot;&gt;pricing&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. All the ThreeFold Grid features will be available on &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;exciting-news-dedicated-nodes-on-the-people-s-internet&#x2F;2645?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;dedicated nodes&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; as well – from deploying VMs and containers to CapRover and more. Dedicated and non-dedicated 3Nodes can be combined.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;v-language&quot;&gt;V Language&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold is built with simplicity in mind which is why we’re using &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.threefold.io&#x2F;partners&#x2F;vlang&#x2F;&quot;&gt;V&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; – a statically typed programming language similar to Go, and inspired by Rust, Swift, and Oberon. It’s the official &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;technology&#x2F;threefold__smartcontract_it&quot;&gt;smart contract&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; language on the Grid, as its simplicity and readability allows anyone to go through and understand any code base, even non-developers.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite being simple, V gives a lot of power to the developer and can be used in pretty much every field, including systems programming, webdev, gamedev, GUI, mobile, science, embedded, tooling, etc. It aims to become an alternative to JavaScript as the de facto coding language on the market in the upcoming years. With V, the developer doesn’t need to change anything in their code. “It just works”, like in Python, Go, or Java, except there’s no heavy GC tracing everything or expensive RC for each object. V can translate your entire C project and offer you the safety, simplicity, and 10-25x faster compilation speeds.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With +30,5K Stars on &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;vlang&#x2F;v&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, V brings a strong open-source developer community to the ThreeFold ecosystem to develop the infrastructures and applications of tomorrow – making it the ideal smart contract language for the ThreeFold ecosystem.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;an-open-invitation&quot;&gt;An open invitation&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, now that you’ve learned more about the building blocks of the ThreeFold Grid and how you can build with them, we’d like to invite you to try and test them yourselves!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While we’re very proud of our progress and the strong ecosystem around us, now’s the time to build upon the foundation. The team continues to do incredible work to further develop and advance the Grid with each and every release. They continue to improve the components, develop new features and build new solutions.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With your support, the team can work even faster. If you share our belief in open source and decentralization, we invite you to help us test and improve not only the Grid and its primitives but also the solutions built on top. Together, we keep building and advancing to realize our Internet of Internets vision and to empower people with true digital sovereignty. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dive into the &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;manual&#x2F;#&#x2F;&quot;&gt;manual&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to get started&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn more about &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;manual&#x2F;#&#x2F;manual__grid3_testing?id=testing-the-threefold_grid3&quot;&gt;testing the ThreeFold Grid&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Join this growing &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefold&quot;&gt;movement&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; &amp;amp; our &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefoldtesting&quot;&gt;testing community&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;join-us-for-part-three&quot;&gt;Join us for &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;build-on-threefolds-open-infrastructure-part-three&#x2F;&quot;&gt;part three&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;!&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get ready for &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;build-on-threefolds-open-infrastructure-part-three&#x2F;&quot;&gt;part three&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; of our series where we’re diving into a world of possibilities for developers, end-users and everyone in-between. The final part will not only show you what’s possible on the ThreeFold Playground today but also introduce you to our end-user experiences that empower you with digital sovereignty which are available for beta testing now!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Build on ThreeFold’s Open Infrastructure – Part One: Intro</title>
        <published>2022-09-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2022-09-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/build-on-threefolds-open-infrastructure/"/>
        <id>https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/build-on-threefolds-open-infrastructure/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/build-on-threefolds-open-infrastructure/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“This article was originally published by Hannah Cordes, a former member of ThreeFold Foundation.”&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What started out as an idea for a better Internet about a decade ago amongst a few early Internet and Cloud pioneers has now become a reality. Today, ThreeFold is a global movement building a reliable, open and inclusive Internet.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve reached a pivotal moment in the evolution of the Internet. And ThreeFold is ready to unlock a new Internet era – one filled with &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;planet-first-people-first&#x2F;&quot;&gt;abundance and opportunity&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for all, one which is better for &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;planting-the-seeds&#x2F;&quot;&gt;our planet&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Our open-source technology, future-facing ecosystem and collaborative community have the potential to drive this new era forward.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For us, the Internet was always meant to be &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;p2p-web3&#x2F;&quot;&gt;peer-to-peer&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, where anyone could own hardware, and connect and exchange directly with full security and in full privacy – without any entity in the middle. This is how the Internet began. But as demand grew, big tech began to monopolize its infrastructure and all the major platforms.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since its inception, ThreeFold has been committed not only to delivering on the original promise of the Internet, but also to realizing our ultimate vision of a better future for all. For the past six years, we’ve been building up an incredible full-stack, open-source, decentralized Internet, all &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;how-threefold-is-building-a-new-internet-from-the-ground-up&#x2F;2057?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;from the ground-up&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. We’ve come a long way and the result is, well, exceptional. There is &lt;em&gt;nothing&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; else out there like ThreeFold.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From creating our own blockchain-driven and highly secure &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;all-you-need-to-know-about-zero-os&#x2F;1734?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;operating system&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (which allows computers to become decentralized servers), to building an ultra-scalable &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;technology&#x2F;qsss&#x2F;threefold__qsss_home?id=quantum-safe-storage-system&quot;&gt;Quantum Safe Storage System&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, a complete far &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;internet-at-the-edge&#x2F;&quot;&gt;edge cloud&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; computing platform and a &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;how-our-planetary-network-works&#x2F;1210?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;planetary peer-to-peer network&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; all accessible via a unique Smart Contract for IT on the &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;tf-chain&#x2F;&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Blockchain&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, we’re proud to have the most &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;internet-at-the-edge&#x2F;&quot;&gt;complete edge infrastructure&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to power the next-generation Internet era.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And we’re taking concrete steps to further expand this infrastructure that offers a truly decentralized layer 0 for any blockchain or Internet application. Moreover, with the help of our &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefoldtesting&quot;&gt;community of Grid testers&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, we’re continuously advancing the underlying technology and working towards making it usable for as many people and use cases as possible.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our vision and technology have matured into the &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;internet-of-internets&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Internet of Internets&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; – a network of thousands of community-built and -owned Internets through which we strive to interconnect all of humanity. A new world is coming, and &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;technology&#x2F;threefold__technology&quot;&gt;our technology&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; has the potential to revolutionize digitization on a global scale, across sectors. And yet we remain a hidden gem.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, what solutions does the ThreeFold Grid offer today already? And why exactly should you start to build on top of ThreeFold? Let’s explore some of the many possibilities available today.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-threefold-grid-a-cutting-edge-highly-scalable-peer-to-peer-infrastructure&quot;&gt;The ThreeFold Grid – A cutting-edge, highly scalable peer-to-peer infrastructure&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“ThreeFold is growing the ThreeFold Grid by enabling a community of thousands of farmers from around the world to participate and own a piece of the Internet.” – &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;news&#x2F;post&#x2F;threefold_cybernews&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Adnan Fatayerji&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Grid is a peer-to-peer cloud computing network that’s highly compatible with current industry standards. In late December 2021, ThreeFold launched the third generation of the ThreeFold Grid on mainnet with a fully functional tech stack – a huge and crucial step towards a fully production-ready and decentralized infrastructure. The third generation not only brought a massive leap forward in the decentralization of the Grid but also made for a much simpler user experience for farmers and Grid users. People from all over the world are connecting thousands of 3Nodes to create the world’s largest decentralized Internet infrastructure, and new capacity is being connected every day. Find the latest Grid stats and utilization numbers in &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;grid-stats-new-nodes-overview&#x2F;3291?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;this regularly updated thread&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;threefold-2022-reflect-h1-outlook-h2&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Over the past months&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, the team evolved the Grid through version 3.6.1 and upgraded it to mainnet in July after receiving 100% community approval. This &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;tfgrid-product-updates-july-2022-tfgrid-v3-6-1-highlights-and-more&#x2F;3206&#x2F;2?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;release&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; introduces more stability to the TF Grid and includes various upgrades and new features like the ThreeFold Connect App, the new unified dashboard for a simpler user experience, and more. Big progress was also made in terms of the DAO functionality that went live on TF Chain, with the first TF Chain (L1) DAO proposal was voted on and approved in August.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And with each new Grid release, we’re getting one step closer to solidifying the foundation of the Internet of Internets. Currently, the team is working towards completing &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;threefold-product-updates-august-2022&#x2F;3272?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;Grid version 3.7.0&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; which includes some significant updates, improvements and new features like FreeFlow Twin, a new Node Pilot, new deployment features and &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;threefold-product-updates-august-2022&#x2F;3272?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;a lot more&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. The team continues to do incredible work to further develop and advance the Grid as well as to support utilization and adoption by offering tools and applications that are user-friendly, secure, efficient and scalable. A massive thank you to our incredible tech team and the community of Grid testers!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;next-up-our-cloud-solution&quot;&gt;Next up: our cloud solution&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, the ThreeFold Grid has been evolved, advanced and expanded quite a bit, hasn’t it? About time to take a closer look at our cloud solution and everything enabled by the technology and tooling built on top. As a heads up, part two of our series on ThreeFold’s game-changing Internet infrastructure is for the more tech-savvy crowd. If you don’t consider yourself “a tech person” you might prefer to jump to part three on weblets and end-user experiences right away.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Helpful Resources:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dive into the &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;manual&#x2F;#&#x2F;&quot;&gt;manual&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to get started&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find out more about our &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;technology&#x2F;technology&quot;&gt;technology&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn more about &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;manual&#x2F;#&#x2F;manual__grid3_testing?id=testing-the-threefold_grid3&quot;&gt;testing the ThreeFold Grid&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Join this growing &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefold&quot;&gt;movement&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; &amp;amp; our &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefoldtesting&quot;&gt;testing community&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Planet first. People first.</title>
        <published>2022-07-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2022-07-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/planet-first-people-first/"/>
        <id>https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/planet-first-people-first/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/planet-first-people-first/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“This article was originally published by Hannah Cordes, a former member of ThreeFold Foundation.”&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, the world is facing an unprecedented number of crises and disruptions stemming from the COVID-19 pandemic to climate change to Russia’s invasion of Ukraine. From supply chain disruptions and rising inflation to shortages in food and energy supply, serious challenges lie ahead.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have always believed that technology can help some of humanity’s greatest challenges – for example by providing the foundation for an interconnected world that can enable abundance to spread. ThreeFold has focused on developing a more reliable Internet that can meet the demands and challenges of the future. A &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;planting_the_seeds&#x2F;&quot;&gt;more sustainable&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; Internet that uses &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;for_our_planet&#x2F;&quot;&gt;less energy&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and is offsetting its carbon emissions by supporting tree planting and other impact initiatives. And an Internet that empowers us with digital &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;threefold_data_sovereignty&#x2F;&quot;&gt;sovereignty&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; while providing high levels of &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;critical-security-updates-for-apple-and-google-underline-need-for-secure-it-ecosystem&#x2F;1271?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;privacy and security&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. One that is &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;more_inclusive_internet&#x2F;&quot;&gt;inclusive&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; by being more affordable and accessible.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;mission.threefold.me&#x2F;&quot;&gt;mission&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is planet first and people first. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-planet-and-people-are-at-the-heart-of-our-movement&quot;&gt;The planet and people are at the heart of our movement&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without our planet, humanity has no home. Without our planet, we can’t survive. The fate of humanity depends on the planet’s health. We need a healthy planet for humanity to thrive. And our planet needs regenerative solutions at a large scale that combat climate change and the collapse of biodiversity. That includes the Internet and everything that lives on top.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold aims to deliver on our promise of providing better solutions for our planet and people through our technology. With this approach, we’re taking action and making productive choices for our planet and humanity. Our &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;four_phases_of_threefold&#x2F;&quot;&gt;journey&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is shaped by the determination to drive the regeneration of our planet and to enable a better life for people.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Today billions of people don’t have access to the internet because of their station of birth. On one hand, it is unfair to them, and on the other, the world is losing billions of inventors and talents. Our internet can scale to anywhere electricity and network exist to provide access to the internet, education, and financial inclusion to everyone.” – &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;medium.com&#x2F;authority-magazine&#x2F;the-future-is-now-kristoff-de-spiegeleer-of-threefold-on-how-their-technological-innovation-will-7acc0e51c365&quot;&gt;Kristof de Spiegeleer&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our approach is also based on community and connection. We’re determined to build better, sustainable, and inclusive systems for the planet and people – from realizing the Internet of Internets on a global scale to reimagining business, governance, finance, education, and more in order to provide better alternatives for people, enterprises, and governments. And we are in dialogue and partnership with global leaders who share a similar vision.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are three examples of the impact we’re creating together:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Together with &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;planting_the_seeds&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Take Action Global&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, we’re offsetting the ThreeFold Grid’s emissions three times by planting and protecting trees&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Together with &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.threefold.io&#x2F;newsroom&#x2F;threefold-ietsa&#x2F;&quot;&gt;IETSA&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, we’re making the decentralized Internet more accessible in underserved South African communities while also providing education in blockchain and Web 3.0 technologies&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Together with &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;solidaridad-revival&#x2F;2158?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;Solidaridad&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, we’re working on the Fair Data initiative to enable a fair data economy&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;driving-change-towards-the-future-we-want-to-live-in&quot;&gt;Driving change towards the future we want to live in&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We strongly believe in the ThreeFold Law which states that any good you do will return to you threefold in this lifetime. By making our technology actionable, we energize a collective approach towards a single mission – empowering humanity while regenerating our planet.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re aware that this mission is a big one. We’re aware of how aspirational it is. We’re aware that we are not perfect. And we realize that changing the world for the better requires patience and community. We’re in it for the &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;four_phases_of_threefold&#x2F;&quot;&gt;long run&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and we’re in it together.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“It’s an honor every day to wake up and be a part of a global movement of people who are trying to build a better Internet for humanity that can uplift and empower.” – &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.threefold.io&#x2F;newsroom&#x2F;threefold-cybernews&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Adnan Fatayerji&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold is more than a company or a project. ThreeFold is a global movement consisting of like-minded individuals and partners who share these values and vision. A movement united in our shared beliefs in open source, peer-to-peer, equality, and inclusion. By coming together to build a better Internet, we can create the foundation for a better world. We’re incredibly proud of the ThreeFold community and ecosystem. This beautiful community consists of open-minded, passionate, and determined people from all around the world, just like you. We’re dreamers, creators, builders, and change-makers.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;embed&#x2F;vK78zZT85_4&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;&#x2F;iframe&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-are-part-of-the-solution&quot;&gt;We are part of the solution&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many great projects and organizations out there that also follow the planet-first people-first philosophy. Like &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.ecosia.org&#x2F;?c=en&quot;&gt;Ecosia&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; – the search engine that plants trees and thereby positively impacts ecosystems, communities, and our planet. Like &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;sharethemeal.org&#x2F;en&#x2F;index.html&quot;&gt;ShareTheMeal&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; – the world’s first app against global hunger that enables you to ‘share the meal’ with a child in need with one simple tap on your phone. Like &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.patagonia.com&#x2F;home&#x2F;?utm_source=actionworks&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_campaign=global_nav&amp;amp;utm_content=link&quot;&gt;Patagonia&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; – a designer of outdoor clothing and sports gear that turned into an environmental activist. And like so many others.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Together, we can achieve the extraordinary. The ThreeFold movement is building our own future through the &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;internet_of_internets&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Internet of Internets&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; – an Internet that will be made up of hundreds, thousands, and ultimately millions, of interconnected local Internets that enables us all to directly connect and exchange without limitations or intermediaries. No matter what you do to support planet-first people-first movements, thank you. In doing so, you’re making a difference. You’re contributing to making the world a better place.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With ThreeFold, anyone anywhere can make a difference. For a better life, for a better future.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If not us, who? If not now, when?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you’re new to ThreeFold and don’t know you to contribute best, here are a few ways to take action:&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefold&quot;&gt;Join&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; this growing movement&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;marketplace.3node.global&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Buy&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; or &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;farming&#x2F;threefold__diy_guide&quot;&gt;build&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; a 3Node and be the Internet&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.manual.grid.tf&#x2F;documentation&#x2F;threefold_token&#x2F;buy_sell_tft&#x2F;buy_sell_tft.html&quot;&gt;Buy&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; TFT&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>ThreeFold Weekly! July 5th, 2022 (Vol 23)</title>
        <published>2022-07-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2022-07-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/weekly-vol-23/"/>
        <id>https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/weekly-vol-23/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/weekly-vol-23/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“This article was originally published by Hannah Cordes, a former member of ThreeFold Foundation.”&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As of edition 24, we’ll only share the Weekly via email and &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefoldnews&quot;&gt;TF News&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, so make sure to subscribe via the respective buttons on the top-right corner of &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&quot;&gt;our website&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;community-updates&quot;&gt;Community Updates:&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;YouTube influencer &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;channel&#x2F;UCPRC2wIfZtAlzCa_6iKE46w&quot;&gt;Tactical Investing&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; featured ThreeFold in a &lt;strong&gt;new video&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; and shared the &lt;strong&gt;potential of ThreeFold farming&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; with his community of 82.3K subscribers. Watch it &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;youtu.be&#x2F;maISozq2p1o&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;!&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You’re going on vacation but don’t know how to check on your 3Nodes? Read the community-sourced &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;tf-farm-tips-when-youre-away-for-some-days&#x2F;3088?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;tips and tricks&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on how to &lt;strong&gt;secure and maintain your TF farm&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; while you’re away.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Did you already check out the new &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;threefold-video-gallery&#x2F;3091?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Video Gallery&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;? It’s a collection of all video material available on ThreeFold – from deep dive sessions to DIY tutorials and more!&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;technology-developments&quot;&gt;Technology Developments:&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TF Chain&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; was updated to the latest version of Substrate on devnet. This will facilitate further development and allows us to get code reviews from the Parity team.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We now have a new &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;manual&#x2F;#&#x2F;manual__manual3_tfservices?id=supported-planetary-network-nodes&quot;&gt;peer list&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; available for the &lt;strong&gt;Planetary Network&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; which you can use to access the end-to-end encrypted peer-to-peer global overlay network.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start testing &lt;strong&gt;ThreeFold Grid V3.6.0 live&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; on testnet. Check out the full release with actionable tips for testing &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;tfgrid-v3-6-0-is-now-live&#x2F;3084?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;!&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;threefold-grid&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Grid:&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take a look at this &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;tf-grid-deploying-workloads&#x2F;3094?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;actionable guide&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for &lt;strong&gt;deploying workloads on the ThreeFold Grid&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, shared by all-star farmer Mik, and get started today!&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Migrate your 3Nodes to V3&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; asap by following the simple steps of the &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;farming-migration-grid-v2-v3&#x2F;2143?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;migration process&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Global Titan shipping continues, so don’t forget to provide all &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;creating-your-v3-farm-required-for-open-unshipped-orders&#x2F;2144&quot;&gt;information&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for your Titan order to ensure quick delivery.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See you next week, ThreeFolders! 🙌&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you’re a community member interested in &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;looking-for-farmer-stories-to-share-with-the-world&#x2F;2398?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;sharing your story&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; or &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;looking-for-people-to-feature-in-threefold-content-its-super-simple&#x2F;2636&#x2F;3&quot;&gt;being featured&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; in ThreeFold content, please reach out!&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can find the previous editions on &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&quot;&gt;our blog&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. For older editions of ThreeFold Weekly (Vol 1-11), go to &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;c&#x2F;ecosystem-developments&#x2F;41&quot;&gt;our forum&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Consensus 2022 Recap – ThreeFold Community Celebrates the  Internet of Internets</title>
        <published>2022-06-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2022-06-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/consensus-2022-recap/"/>
        <id>https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/consensus-2022-recap/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/consensus-2022-recap/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“This article was originally published by Hannah Cordes, a former member of ThreeFold Foundation.”&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ThreeFold Team was in Austin, Texas, in June to share our vision for a decentralized Internet as an exhibitor and sponsor of &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;threefold_at_consensus_2022&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Consensus&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; by Coindesk. The four-day conference attracted over &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;cointelegraph.com&#x2F;news&#x2F;consensus-2022-web3-unpacking-regulations-and-optimism-for-crypto-s-future&quot;&gt;20,000 people&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; who explored conversations on topics like decentralization, blockchain, crypto, Web 3 and more. The ThreeFold team shared our “planet first, people first” vision and story with hundreds of attendees who visited our conference booth to learn about ThreeFold – leading to new community members, farmers, token holders, and partners. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Co-founder &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;people&#x2F;adnan_fatayerji&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Adnan Fatayerji&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; conducted several media interviews and found that our story resonated well – after all, &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;threefold_at_consensus_2022&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Consensus&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is the Festival for the Decentralized World. Nevertheless, many of the other projects at Consensus are still using centralized infrastructure for hosting. We shared the potential for ThreeFold as the foundation to make a truly decentralized world a reality. Already, independent people and organizations from 80 countries and counting are connecting decentralized Internet capacity, bringing to life this new infrastructure.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;dev.threefold.io&#x2F;blogarchive&#x2F;consensus-2022-recap&#x2F;.&#x2F;threefold_booth_consensus.png&quot; alt=&quot;ThreeFold Booth Consensus&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;dev.threefold.io&#x2F;blogarchive&#x2F;consensus-2022-recap&#x2F;.&#x2F;threefold_booth_people.png&quot; alt=&quot;ThreeFold Booth People&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“As the Layer 0 for Web2&#x2F;3&#x2F;4 or 5, we came to Consensus with open arms and in the spirit of collaboration and that’s exactly what happened. We made friends and connected with the projects out there that are truly moving the needle of ‘Trust’&#x2F;Web3 forward. We look forward to nurturing these incredible partnerships on ThreeFold’s foundational layer and to scale ‘Digital Trust’ in all its forms towards mainstream adoption.” – Adnan Fatayerji&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;bringing-the-sovereign-internet-to-austin&quot;&gt;Bringing the Sovereign Internet to Austin&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Together with some of &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.yourhomecommunity.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;our Austin friends&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, we gathered with 45 like-minded people at Casa de Luz, a spiritual and wellness retreat, to launch the first sovereign Regional Internet in Austin, Texas. All of us shared our own stories and reasons for attending. Then we explored the opportunities, benefits and next steps for Austin to establish its own truly self-sovereign regional Internet.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We found shared values among a group of open, inspiring, passionate and like-minded individuals who formed this founding group. Austin has long been a hub for innovative thinkers and high-tech companies. Austin has a strong connection to and respect for nature. Austin is aligned well with our planet-first, people-first philosophy.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe that, together, we’re strong enough to build new regenerative systems powerful enough to enable anyone to have a sovereign, safer and more fulfilling life. And we’re honoured to be working with the people of Austin in the global rollout of the Internet of Internets. We’re now looking to launch the first 3Nodes there to lay the foundation of Austin’s sovereign Regional Internet.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;dev.threefold.io&#x2F;blogarchive&#x2F;consensus-2022-recap&#x2F;.&#x2F;threefold_austin_community.png&quot; alt=&quot;ThreeFold and Austin Community&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve spent a truly incredible week in Austin, spreading the word about ThreeFold, forming meaningful connections and finding a new home. Thank you, Austin!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“It’s been inspiring to meet everyone at Casa de Luz! Feeling so grateful for the opportunity to build Austin’s sovereign Internet together!” – Sacha Obeegadoo&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“It was such an honor. I’ll never forget that day. We’re going to do something really beautiful!” – Sam Taggart&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Connecting with the beautiful community of the good people of Austin was absolutely amazing. We really felt at home and Austin is a true freedom vortex in the US where people truly value their free spirits and the importance of staying resilient and independant. We could not have dreamt of a better place to start the Internet of Internets in the US and create the first local internet. Keep it weird Austin!” – Florian Fournier&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;next-steps&quot;&gt;Next steps&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The founding gathering in Austin was just the beginning. Building meaningful relationships with local communities to start the next few Regional Internets will be a big focus for the ThreeFold ecosystem in 2022. Therefore, we’ll be travelling to various places across the globe to &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;connecting_the_dots&#x2F;&quot;&gt;connect the dots&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; in the upcoming months.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After entering a partnership with &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;paradise_hills&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Paradise Hills&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to build the first Community Cloud, planting the seeds for the first Regional Internet in Austin represents another crucial step in our journey to create the &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;internet_of_internets&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Internet of Internets&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; – a glocal model that is infinitely scalable. So, the next few months will be vital for our &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;four_phases_of_threefold&#x2F;&quot;&gt;expansion phase&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and for building a better future for all of us.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Together, we’re building a better Internet by and for the people, the foundation for a better world. An Internet to regenerate our planet and to empower the collective – the many and not the few.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, we’re proud to join together to build the future we want to live in – whether by &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;farming&#x2F;threefold__diy_guide&quot;&gt;building&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; or &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;marketplace.3node.global&#x2F;&quot;&gt;buying&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; a 3Node, by buying the ThreeFold Token (&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;tft&quot;&gt;TFT&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;), or by helping us bring the sovereign Internet to your community or region.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;New to ThreeFold? &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefold&quot;&gt;Join&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; the movement now and learn how to &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;what_is_farming&#x2F;&quot;&gt;be&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; the Internet.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>ThreeFold at Consensus: A Decentralized World is in Our Hands</title>
        <published>2022-05-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2022-05-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/threefold-at-consensus-2022/"/>
        <id>https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/threefold-at-consensus-2022/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/threefold-at-consensus-2022/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“This article was originally published by Hannah Cordes, a former member of ThreeFold Foundation.”&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s that time of the year when believers and builders of a decentralized tomorrow  gather to celebrate the festival for the decentralized world. About 15,000 people will attend Consensus 2022 by CoinDesk from June 9 through June 12. Throughout the festival, key topics around decentralization, blockchain, crypto, Web 3 and the metaverse will be explored and discussed.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is ThreeFold attending Consensus? Excellent question. The ThreeFold community truly believes that collaboration, decentralization and peer-to-peer systems are the foundation for a better Internet, and subsequently, a better world. And together we are making that world a reality. But we need to grow and extend the community on the ground with the right people, dreamers who choose to act now.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As many consider Consensus the festival for the decentralized world, some questions linger:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;How committed are the projects and participants to decentralization, and for what reasons? How far are they willing to go to bring that world to life?&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s no secret that many projects in the space still rely on centralized infrastructure – at least to some degree. So, are they really delivering on their promise of decentralization?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-decentralized-world-needs-a-decentralized-foundation&quot;&gt;A decentralized world needs a decentralized foundation&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think we’ve already come to Consensus that decentralization has to start at the foundational level. See what I did there? The ThreeFold co-founders have more than 20 years of experience in setting world records in Internet storage and cloud automation technologies. With ThreeFold, they started from scratch to build a fully decentralized Internet infrastructure that’s peer-to-peer and open source. We’re realizing the promise of an Internet built and owned by the people, back to the vision of Web 1 through the implementation of Web 4 technology. For us, it’s obvious that we simply cannot build a fair and equal digital world on top of today’s old-world infrastructure which is owned by the few.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With our fair, inclusive and decentralized Internet infrastructure, we’re laying the foundation for a better world. Following our ethos of &lt;em&gt;planet first – people second – profit (value) only as a result&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, we’re striving to regenerate our planet and to empower the collective – the many and not the few. By putting our planet and people first, we create real sustainable value. We believe that, together, we’re strong enough to build new regenerative systems powerful enough to enable anyone to have a sovereign, safer and more fulfilling life.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of today, people from 77 countries are connecting thousands of computers (3Nodes) to the ThreeFold Grid – all contributing to ThreeFold’s open-source peer-to-peer Internet infrastructure. And any node or dApp, actually anything that can run on Linux, can run on top of the ThreeFold Grid in a truly decentralized way. With ThreeFold’s infrastructure and thriving ecosystem, there’s an abundance of potential and opportunities – really anything is possible.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;threefold-consensus&quot;&gt;ThreeFold @Consensus&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ThreeFold team and community will soon gather at the Austin Convention Center, 500 E. Cesar Chavez Street, Austin. Meet the ThreeFold team at &lt;strong&gt;Exhibit Booth 310&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; not far from the Networking Lounge. We’ll be there throughout the entire exhibit to connect with participants, share the ThreeFold story and extend the community – Friday, June 10 through Saturday, June 11 from 9am until 6pm.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At our booth, you’ll be able to meet the team, see and hold a Titan 3Node, have the chance to win a free 3Node of your own, find resources that will empower you to get involved, and more.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold will also host a gathering outside of the Convention Center. We will share more via &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefoldnews&quot;&gt;our Telegram News Channel&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; when the details are finalized, so stay tuned.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold is more than an Internet. It is the foundation for a truly decentralized world. Are you ready to &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefold&quot;&gt;join&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; the global ThreeFold movement?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Check out the full &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;events.coindesk.com&#x2F;consensus2022&#x2F;agenda&quot;&gt;Consensus agenda&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and take advantage of &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;events.coindesk.com&#x2F;consensus2022?promo=a7MsHxui&quot;&gt;our 25% discount code&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to buy tickets.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And don’t forget to let us know if you’ll be joining ThreeFold at Consensus – we’d love to connect with you!&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Co-Realizing the Promise</title>
        <published>2022-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2022-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/realizing-the-promise/"/>
        <id>https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/realizing-the-promise/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/realizing-the-promise/">&lt;p&gt;What was once a massive global movement sparked by the idealism of free culture and the net, is now hosting a wave of unintended consequences that may destroy sovereignty and freedom as we know it. The digital revolution and the “democratization” of the Internet promised to lead us to a prosperous and equitable world, one that brought us closer together, eliminating both physical and virtual boundaries.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“We are creating a world that all may enter without privilege or prejudice accorded by race, economic power, military force, or station of birth… a world where anyone, anywhere may express his or her beliefs, no matter how singular, without fear of being coerced into silence or conformity… Your legal concepts of property, expression, identity, movement, and context do not apply to us. They are all based on matter, and there is no matter here.” –  Declaration of independence of Cyberspace – John Perry Barlow – Davos, 1996.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, this is not the world we live in today. Borders are hardening in our virtual world with the Great Firewall of China and the widespread emergence of Internet “clusters”. Many countries have attempted to turn off Internet services or to prevent free speech. Networks and algorithms turn us into data generators, influencing our daily habits and interests. It’s turning into a big AI-driven machine that commoditizes our lives, leaves the underserved behind and fails to provide sovereignty where we gather.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A centralized Internet which is controlled by a handful of companies is a serious existential threat. The technology that connects us is now used to distract, manipulate, polarize, divide and control the way we think, act and live our lives. If emerging technologies such as IoT, Blockchain and the Metaverse are not hosted on a self-sovereign, peer-to-peer infrastructure owned by all of us, we may be running head down into the matrix.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With billions of people and IoT devices expected to join this broken digital world this decade, we have no choice but to heal our broken information ecosystem if we want to address the challenges we face collectively. So as we move towards a world where tech and science are merging together, how do we ensure a neutral, inclusive and regenerative digital future – one that truly serves humanity and eliminates the barriers that divide us?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The peer-to-peer Internet incentivizes all citizens of our world to connect computers from their homes or offices to participate in a distributed data economy owned by the people. By allowing humans and machines to interweave without intermediaries, a decentralized and self-sovereign Internet can emerge.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quite simply – there is no good reason that our data is being stored and controlled by others in the information age. Why are we paying centralized companies to handle our information on our  behalf, when it makes us vulnerable to be turned into products, and would take us the same time to do it ourselves?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peer-to-peer isn’t an alternative to the Internet, it’s an alternative to centralized cloud giants. The Internet doesn’t need replacing; it is one of the most beautiful inventions of our civilization, if not the greatest. Which is not to say that cloud providers are completely obsolete. They serve functions that decentralized systems cannot (e.g. big data); but peer-to-peer systems are just infinitely more resilient, secure, private and scalable.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In times of exponential evolution and innovation, we have our fears around the Internet.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We don’t need to disconnect ourselves even further from our reality and it is our responsibility to ensure a safe and fair future for the generations to come. A centralized Internet which is controlled by a handful of companies is a serious existential threat. If emerging technologies such as IoT, Blockchain and the Metaverse are not hosted on a self-sovereign, peer-to-peer infrastructure owned by all of us, we may be running head down into the matrix.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The potential of technology to change the world remains endless and limited to our own imagination. We decide to switch from fear to love, and to move forward as one humanity. It is our responsibility as global citizens to pursue greater collective consciousness.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Join the &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefold&quot;&gt;ThreeFold&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; movement, a community of like-minded people that build the world of tomorrow!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn how to &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;farm&quot;&gt;host the Internet&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; at your home or office.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;gettft.com&#x2F;gettft&#x2F;&quot;&gt;TFT&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, the currency of the peer-to-peer Internet.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Bridges Connecting the ThreeFold Ecosystem to External Networks</title>
        <published>2022-01-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2022-01-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/bridges-connecting-threefold-ecosystem/"/>
        <id>https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/bridges-connecting-threefold-ecosystem/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/bridges-connecting-threefold-ecosystem/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“This article was originally published by Hannah Cordes, a former member of ThreeFold Foundation.”&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wondering how to switch between blockchains? Cross-chain bridges allow you to easily transfer TFT from one blockchain to another. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the launch of &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;technology&#x2F;threefold__threefold_grid&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Grid&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; 3.0, &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;tft&quot;&gt;TFT&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; has been available on three blockchains – Stellar, Binance Smart Chain and the Substrate-based ThreeFold Blockchain (aka TF Chain).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are already active bridges that connect Stellar to Binance Smart Chain and &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;tf_chain&#x2F;&quot;&gt;TF Chain&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, improving the accessibility and availability of TFT, while also connecting the ThreeFold ecosystem to external blockchain networks.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn more about TF Chain in our blog post &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;tf_chain&#x2F;&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-are-bridges-and-why-are-they-important&quot;&gt;What are bridges and why are they important?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The concept of bridges in crypto is similar to a bridge in the physical world. Bridges in the real world simply connect two different locations and communities so that the people can travel back and forth and resources can be exchanged freely.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, using bridges in blockchain allows users to easily transfer tokens and other crypto assets between two or more networks – regardless of the different protocols, tooling, and governance models these networks have. Simply put, a bridge ensures a secure interoperability between different blockchains.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold uses blockchain bridges to connect external blockchain networks to the ThreeFold ecosystem. The bridging mechanisms we’ve implemented allow TFT to be transferred securely between &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;technology&#x2F;threefold__money_blockchain_partity_link&quot;&gt;different blockchains&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Currently, we’ve established &lt;strong&gt;two 2-way bridges&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stellar &amp;lt;&amp;gt; Binance Smart Chain&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stellar &amp;lt;&amp;gt; TF Chain&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what is the difference between the 3 chains?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.stellar.org&#x2F;?locale=en&quot;&gt;Stellar&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; is an open-source network for storing and moving digital assets, and still remains the main blockchain for the minting of TFT and distribution of farming rewards. Until the launch of TF Chain with Grid 3.0, only TFT living on Stellar were accepted for the reservation of Internet capacity on the ThreeFold Grid. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.binance.org&#x2F;en&#x2F;smartChain&quot;&gt;Binance Smart Chain&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; (BSC) is a standalone, parallel Binance chain that is a leading DeFi ecosystem next to Ethereum. On BSC, TFT is implemented as a cross-chain asset, allowing anyone to &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;bridge.bsc.threefold.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;connect&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to the bridge using &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;tokens&#x2F;threefold__tft_bsc_metamask&quot;&gt;Metamask&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; or &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold&#x2F;#&#x2F;tokens&#x2F;threefold__threefold_wallets?id=the-threefold-connect-app&quot;&gt;Trust Wallet&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; – the most popular Web 3 wallets in the world.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;tech&#x2F;tf-chain&quot;&gt;TF Chain&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; was built on the &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;substrate.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Substrate framework&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; with the purpose of decentralizing user-farmer relationships on the ThreeFold Grid. It has its own native form of &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;tft&quot;&gt;TFT&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, which can be bridged back and forth from Stellar-based TFT. This model will be implemented for other chains in the future, for interoperability and cross-chain features between blockchain and DeFi ecosystems and the ThreeFold Grid.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-s-new-with-tf-chain&quot;&gt;What’s new with TF Chain?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TF Chain represents a leap forward for simplicity in payments for capacity reservations and a move towards greater decentralization of the systems that support the ThreeFold Grid. With the launch of &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;what-is-new-in-tfgrid-3-0&#x2F;1133&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Grid 3.0&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, TF Chain became the official record of ThreeFold farms and nodes, and brought peer-to-peer &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;introducing-tf-chain-an-updated-billing-model&#x2F;1277&quot;&gt;billing&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; based on smart contracts for workload deployments on the ThreeFold Grid. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For now, minting will remain on Stellar but reservations of nodes and capacity on ThreeFold Grid 3.0 are already executed via &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;technology&#x2F;threefold__tfchain&quot;&gt;TF Chain&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Bridges were established between Stellar and TF Chain to facilitate payments, e.g. if you pay for a workload deployment in Stellar TFT, this payment needs to be bridged to TF  Chain’s native TFT to fund the &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;technology&#x2F;threefold__smartcontract_it&quot;&gt;smart contract&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-two-way-bridge-between-stellar-bsc&quot;&gt;The two-way &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;bridge.bsc.threefold.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;bridge&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; between Stellar &amp;amp; BSC &lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until recently, the bridge between Stellar and Binance Smart Chain (BSC) was one-way only: from BSC to Stellar. Even though it was possible to transfer TFT from Stellar to BSC via  &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;threefoldfoundation&#x2F;tft&#x2F;blob&#x2F;main&#x2F;bsc&#x2F;bridges&#x2F;stellar&#x2F;transfers.md&quot;&gt;command line&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, this was only an option for tech-savvy people. Now, you can also deposit TFT from Stellar to BSC using the bridge with a proper UI, as you can see in the image below.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;dev.threefold.io&#x2F;blogarchive&#x2F;bridges-connecting-threefold-ecosystem&#x2F;.&#x2F;tft_bsc_bridge.png&quot; alt=&quot;tft_bsc_bridge&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When depositing from TFT Stellar, &lt;strong&gt;please be sure that both addresses and memo are as indicated&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; in the instructions or the TFT you transfer will be lost forever. To facilitate the process, a &lt;strong&gt;QR code&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; is generated and can be scanned using the &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold&#x2F;#&#x2F;tokens&#x2F;threefold__threefold_connect&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Connect app&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, automatically filling in the right address and memo on your behalf.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;dev.threefold.io&#x2F;blogarchive&#x2F;bridges-connecting-threefold-ecosystem&#x2F;.&#x2F;tft_bsc_transfer.png&quot; alt=&quot;tft_bsc_transfer&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Binance Smart Chain is a more expensive chain, &lt;strong&gt;a fee of 50 TFT&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; will be automatically charged for the bridge from Stellar to BSC. Find the full &lt;strong&gt;step-by-step guide&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; for the Stellar-BSC bridge &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;tokens&#x2F;threefold__tft_bsc_bridge&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-s-next&quot;&gt;What’s next? &lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the ThreeFold ecosystem continues to grow, we’re looking into building more bridges (e.g. Cosmos, Ethereum) to improve the accessibility of TFT and simplify the onboarding of blockchain and DeFi projects on the ThreeFold Grid. TF Chain will play an important role in the further development of the People’s Internet, so give our blog post on TF Chain a read &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;tf_chain&#x2F;&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Try out the Stellar-BSC bridge &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;bridge.bsc.threefold.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and visit &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;our forum&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to share your experiences.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>A Journey Into ThreeFold</title>
        <published>2021-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2021-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/journey-into-threefold/"/>
        <id>https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/journey-into-threefold/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/journey-into-threefold/">&lt;p&gt;If you’re part of the ThreeFold Movement, we’re sure you’ve seen Scott in a demo, or in the chats or forums. Scott is new-ish to the team but he’s been active in the community for quite a while.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
In this video, Sam, based in Turkey, and Scott, based in the Pacific Northwest (USA), have a conversation about Scott’s journey into ThreeFold. They speak about how he found out about the project and started contributing (and how you can do the same), the technology, the mission, vision, and values, the people, and what Scott is most looking forward to in the short, medium, and long-term.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;embed&#x2F;eXpXtHRSji0&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;&#x2F;iframe&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Eager to contribute? Find us on our forums, chats, or on GitHub!
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Forum&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefold&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Main Chat&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefoldfarmers&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Farmers Chat&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefoldtesting&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Testing Chat&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;threefoldfoundation&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Foundation GitHub&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;threefoldtech&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Tech GitHub&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>This ThreeFold Farm Keeps Veggies Warm</title>
        <published>2021-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2021-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/blockheating-intro/"/>
        <id>https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/blockheating-intro/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/blockheating-intro/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“This article was originally published by Roel Van Sabben, a former member of ThreeFold Foundation.”&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somewhere in the Netherlands, a ThreeFold Farm is supporting the growth of vegetable crops such as tomatoes, peppers and cucumbers. By directing the excess heat generated from the hardware operations to the greenhouse next door, they are able to achieve an incredible model that benefits both hardware and vegetables.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Jeroen Burks, CEO of Blockheating, tells us everything we need to know about their sustainable farming operations. As far as he can remember, Jeroen has always been a protagonist of the “no waste” approach. He started by recycling material previously used by the tech industry, mainly in the cloud market.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
“By default, most data center operations replace their power supplies every 3 years, no matter the state they are in. They are being replaced to counter any possible downtime.”
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
By refurbishing and repurposing “old” power units from data centers, he gives them a second life as electric tractor chargers, lithium ION pack chargers, and more.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
“You just need to trick the unit into thinking it is still powering servers, add some cables here and there, and it is ready for duty.”
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
His quest towards sustainability started when he was challenged on a pilot project. His friend had bought a new building and was looking for the most sustainable approach to heating it. Jeroen came up with the idea of putting two server racks in the basement and using the heat from that operation, to heat the offices and spaces above. While this project was a success, Jeroen realised that it could be way more efficient, if done with other structures.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
He quickly engaged with a second pilot project where he used two server racks to heat a small greenhouse. This model turned out to be a great combination, which benefited both hardware, as well as farming operations. And so sprouted ‘Blockheating’ – a data center that provides heat for tomatoes, peppers and cucumbers. Why specifically these vegetables? Well, the Netherlands has a fair amount of greenhouses cultivating them, and these ‘veggies’ need that heat during summer nights.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Right now Blockheating has around 400 compute nodes with direct cooling that stores all the heat in a buffer throughout the day, which is then released into the greenhouses during the night hours.
“By doing it the way we do, we grow the internet grid, help grow vegetables and curb fossil fuel usage – in carbon negative compute power!”
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Right now, Blockheating has a portion of their data center dedicated to ThreeFold Farming for a few reasons:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The alignment of values is huge&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ThreeFold Farming is easy to manage&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ThreeFold Farming counters wasteful behavior of internet resources, so it’s a triple win&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Blockheating envisions to scale up-to three data centers of this kind, in an interconnected way, with a fiber ring between them. By doing so, they will be able to increase their offering and have a larger impact on countering the wasteful patterns of the cloud industry. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
ThreeFold is proud to have Blockheating as a ‘State-of-the-Art’ Farmer and Partner, and hopes to see many more people and companies inspired by Blockheating around the world, to expand the ‘People’s Internet’ in a regenerative way. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find out more about Blockheating here: &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;blockheating.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;blockheating.com&#x2F;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find out more about our partners here: &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;partners&quot;&gt;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;partners&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Into the Fold – The ThreeFold Movement</title>
        <published>2021-07-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2021-07-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/the-threefold-movement/"/>
        <id>https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/the-threefold-movement/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/the-threefold-movement/">&lt;p&gt;It’s not by mistake that you’re here, reading this post. You, like I, understand that today’s systems need to change. You know that decentralization is needed for better wealth distribution and equal opportunities. And that we need better solutions for our planet. You can feel that a global shift is happening. And you want to do something about it. You want to be a part of it.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
You’ve dreamt of a different world. A world where people trust and treat each other with respect – and where everyone has equal chances to learn and to thrive. A world where we’re not just cogs in a machine that serves only the few, rather we work and co-create as part of systems that benefit all. A world where solutions are sustainable for our planet, or even better, regenerative. This world is not just a dream, though – and you’re not alone. Each day, more and more like-minded people are coming together. Welcome into the fold.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;meet-the-movement&quot;&gt;Meet the Movement&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To understand ThreeFold, you should first understand where we came from. Since the late 90’s, some of the ThreeFold co-founders have worked on Internet storage and cloud technology. And after years of building, and many successful launches, they came to understand that they were part of a broken system that was productizing people and damaging the planet. Despite this, they knew that the Internet held and holds the key to a better world, and that the only way to have a truly sovereign, secure, and energy-efficient Internet was to start from scratch. So we did.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
This is how our story began – and over the past four years we have grown and expanded a team of like-minded and passionate people from around the world to bring ThreeFold to life. But for us, we are still in the beginning of something much bigger to come.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
We don’t consider ourselves a company, rather a group of humans helping other humans – and our planet. We believe the world needs to change, and we choose to not just talk, but act, to make that change happen. We cannot and would not want to do this alone. There is a strong, passionate, and growing community around us – partners, farmers, ambassadors, technology testers, other contributors, and supporters just like you.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;our-mission-vision-and-values-drive-us-forward&quot;&gt;Our Mission, Vision, and Values Drive us Forward&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our mission is to build and expand a data-sovereign and planet-positive Internet owned by the people, for the people. This will enable equal chances for people around the world to learn, partake and succeed, and will help to heal our planet.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Engrained into the work that we do are three key values or principles:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
We believe in &lt;strong&gt;sovereignty&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, and in protecting people. Everyone should own their data, and no one else, not even ThreeFold. Our peer-to-peer technology allows every user to be data sovereign – giving them 100% control over their data.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
We believe that everyone should be given &lt;strong&gt;equal chances&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; to learn, partake and succeed. Internet access is a human right, and at ThreeFold we commit to scale our technology to new regions to empower the unconnected.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
And we unify our practices, partnerships, and products around a single mission – to &lt;strong&gt;heal our planet&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;. By making our technology actionable, we enable a collective approach to have an impact together.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;together-we-invite-the-world-into-the-fold&quot;&gt;Together, We Invite the World Into the Fold&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s important for others to understand who we are. Thus, we identify with and embody three key attributes as a collective, to show the world what the movement is all about:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;ThreeFold is purposeful.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; We exist to help humanity thrive. Our mission is bold and motivates every step we take. We adapt to our evolving environment and passionately strive for excellence.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;ThreeFold is empowering.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; We help people find themselves and do what they love. We provide support to people and projects that help build a better world, whether they have moonshot visions or down-to-earth ambitions. We aren’t the hero of our story – they are.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;ThreeFold is approachable.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; ThreeFold keeps it real. We’re open and honest, avoiding upstage corporate language and phony marketing spins. We don’t see ourselves as a company, but more like humans helping other humans. So being genuine, friendly, and loving comes naturally.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
In its essence, the movement is open and inviting. We’ve created &lt;strong&gt;a participatory Internet economy&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, where anybody around the world can plug in a 3Node and add capacity to the ThreeFold Grid. Together, we’re expanding a data sovereign and planet positive Internet infrastructure, owned by the people, across geographical and cultural borders.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
We believe in &lt;strong&gt;collaboration, not competition&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;. Our technology serves as a responsible underlying layer on top of which anybody can build and create. We have &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;partners&quot;&gt;beautiful partners&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; already on board – and &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;aci&quot;&gt;an alliance&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; of conscious people and organizations who share our vision – and we are constantly expanding our ecosystem across industries.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
And while the ThreeFold Foundation is currently the driving force behind the ThreeFold Movement, we believe in &lt;strong&gt;decentralization&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;. We have open channels like &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&quot;&gt;a forum&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefold&quot;&gt;a two-way Telegram chat&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, Github (&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;threefoldfoundation&quot;&gt;Foundation&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;threefoldtech&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Tech&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;), and &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;twitter.com&#x2F;threefold_io&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, where people can and do contribute, ask questions and provide feedback that goes into our everyday decision-making and actions.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
As I said at the start, you’ve dreamt of a different world. And so have I. John Lennon once said, “A dream you dream alone is only a dream. A dream you dream together is reality.” Thank you for dreaming with us. Together, this will happen!
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Photo by Ahmad Odeh on Unsplash.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>ThreeFold&#x27;s Long Story Short</title>
        <published>2020-05-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2020-05-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/how-it-works/"/>
        <id>https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/how-it-works/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/how-it-works/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;so-threefold-is-building-a-new-internet-why&quot;&gt;So, ThreeFold is building a new internet. Why?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We strongly believe that a new internet is needed for our planet and for humanity. “If not now, when? If not us, who?”
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
What it boils down to is that currently the internet is only available to about 1&#x2F;2 of the world (meaning billions are being left behind), it is centralized (a handful of large corporations own and profit off of our data), and it uses up to 10% of the world’s energy consumption. So, we’re building a new (peer-to-peer) internet that empowers equality (access), autonomy (data ownership, for example), and sustainability (reduces energy consumption). These values drive us forward.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-does-it-work&quot;&gt;How does it work?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything on the internet – websites, apps, photos, videos, etc – uses up capacity and is stored in huge data centers owned by big companies, mainly in North America, Europe, and some in Asia. In our solution, centralized data centers are replaced with a grid of “nodes” distributed around the world.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
These nodes are owned by &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold&#x2F;#&#x2F;what_is_farming&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Farmers&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; – but only the physical hardware – the data inside of the nodes belongs to the people or organizations who put it there. So, “farmers” plug in hardware and start to create capacity that can be used by people.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Farmers come in all shapes and sizes. Some farmers run small data centers while others simply run a node out of their living room.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
When Farmers connect active hardware (add capacity) to the ThreeFold Grid, ThreeFold Tokens are created. Farmers can then sell those tokens to people who want to use capacity (e.g. a developer that wants to build or host a website, or a person who wants to store some photos). More on tokens down below.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;seems-quite-lofty-how-will-you-build-it&quot;&gt;Seems quite lofty. How will you build it?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s true that rebuilding the internet is not so simple. But a lot of infrastructure has already been built and the technology is quite advanced. Over the past 2+ years (as of May 2020), independent ThreeFold Farmers have already plugged in more than 40,000,000 GigaBytes worth of storage and 15,000 CPU Cores across 21+ countries. That might not mean a lot to non-technical folks but it is quite a significant amount.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;21-countries-what-happened-to-equality&quot;&gt;21+ countries? What happened to equality?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As far along as we are, we still have work to do. One of our biggest goals in the near future is to expand the grid to Africa, South America, and parts of Asia where currently the Internet is too expensive or not available. Currently, we farming is incentivized around these key geographies.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;and-what-do-you-mean-by-peer-to-peer&quot;&gt;And what do you mean by peer-to-peer?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peer-to-peer means no middlemen – direct exchange of information and&#x2F;or value between equal participants. Peer-to-peer means decentralization – breaking away from pyramid-based systems, greed-based systems – and putting &lt;strong&gt;people&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; back in the center of their own (digital) lives.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;so-how-can-i-access-use-your-internet-today-what-can-i-do-on-it&quot;&gt;So how can I access &#x2F; use your internet today? What can I do on it?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By June, some of the first experiences will be live. This includes file storage and communication tools and a virtual browser, all with the advantages of being more sustainable for our planet and with full control of your own data. And over time, more and more experiences will come to this internet. We’ll be updating here and on our communication platforms as they come. But don’t worry, as a user it doesn’t change much – no coding required. :)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;will-enter-website-or-app-here-be-available-on-your-internet&quot;&gt;Will [enter website or app here] be available on your internet?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are some tremendous reasons for a website or app to use our internet, but that will really be up to the website or the app. In the end, we are providing a responsible solution for responsible people and organizations. We would love to host anybody who believes in what we are doing!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-are-you-making-sure-it-s-safe&quot;&gt;How are you making sure it’s safe?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hacking has become a part of life and is almost impossible to avoid in the current systems – they are too complex and require too many people to operate. This results in less security which results in lots of security breaches. We took a look at the existing Internet (seven layers) and simplified it down to three layers. By simplifying the architecture and instead creating technology that is self-driving &amp;amp; self-healing, we removed the human requirement and therefore vastly minimized the possibility for hacking or human error. Then we also developed a storage algorithm which makes it such that if some of the information gets lost or stolen (somehow) or if some hardware goes down, it is all retrievable. Long story short, we flipped the existing system on its head.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-about-the-data-ownership-part&quot;&gt;What about the data ownership part?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That has a bit to do with the security as well. Since you own your data, you decide who gets access. Which means your data isn’t just out “there” for the taking. Basically, we put you at the center of your digital life, where the applications and experiences you use serve you, not the other way around.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;and-how-is-it-better-for-the-planet&quot;&gt;And how is it better for the planet?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a few reasons for us being more sustainable. Data centers are super unsustainable, so the simple (but incomplete) answer is “no more huge data centers.” But if you want more detail:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We use up to 3x less hardware for the same output, and using hardware at least 2x longer while maintaining good performance&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Having capacity everywhere, local to where users are – this reduces network requirements (and can even improve security)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using new algorithms (e.g. the one mentioned above for storage) which have dramatic efficiency improvement&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Re-using hardware where possible – let’s not throw away&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-much-will-it-cost&quot;&gt;How much will it cost?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end we want to provide sustainable access to the internet and all of its solutions for less than a dollar per month per person but for now the cost will depend on what you choose to do. Certain experiences will cost money. Storing photos or videos, for example. But all at a fair price.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;speaking-of-money-so-what-s-up-with-the-threefold-token&quot;&gt;Speaking of money – so what’s up with the ThreeFold Token?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we mentioned above, tokens are generated when ThreeFold Farmers adds capacity to the ThreeFold Grid.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Essentially, the ThreeFold Token is the medium of exchange on the new internet. So, if a developer wants to build something (e.g. a website or an app) or a user wants to store something (e.g. photos), he&#x2F;she&#x2F;they use(s) ThreeFold Tokens.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;need-more-answers&quot;&gt;Need more answers?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We hope that helps explains things. Obviously there is &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold&#x2F;#&#x2F;&quot;&gt;a whole wiki&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to dive in to. If you don’t find what you’re looking for, please ask us on our &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&quot;&gt;forum&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;!
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Photo by Nong Vang on &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;unsplash.com&#x2F;photos&#x2F;9pw4TKvT3po&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
</feed>
