<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
    <title>ThreeFold - cloud</title>
    <subtitle>Our global digital backbone</subtitle>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://dev.threefold.io/categories/cloud/atom.xml"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://dev.threefold.io"/>
    <generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
    <updated>2024-02-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://dev.threefold.io/categories/cloud/atom.xml</id>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Rethinking Data Center Design with Tier S</title>
        <published>2024-02-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-02-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://dev.threefold.io/blog/tier-s-data-center/"/>
        <id>https://dev.threefold.io/blog/tier-s-data-center/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://dev.threefold.io/blog/tier-s-data-center/">&lt;p&gt;In an era where artificial intelligence is reshaping our technological landscape, it is imperative to reconsider how we design and operate data centers. With decades of experience in the Internet and Cloud space and in response to technological evolutions, ThreeFold is proposing a new approach.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the last 30 years, data center construction has largely remained static. Contemporary data centers risk becoming obsolete if they continue to neglect evolving needs. As we stand at this technological crossroads, the urgency to adapt is clear: unless we pay close attention, new data centers risk repeating the inefficiencies of their predecessors, leading to a poor utilization of investments and a significant mismatch with current and future requirements.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-two-main-flaws-of-existing-data-centers&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#the-two-main-flaws-of-existing-data-centers&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: the-two-main-flaws-of-existing-data-centers&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;The Two Main Flaws of Existing Data Centers&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;inadequate-power-provision&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#inadequate-power-provision&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: inadequate-power-provision&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;Inadequate Power Provision&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The advent of AI has dramatically escalated power needs. An AI-centric rack can consume up to 200 kW – a staggering 15 times more than the capacity of data centers built in the conventional model. This exponential increase poses significant challenges, particularly when dissipation exceeds 50 kW per rack. Traditional designs fall short in crucial aspects like cooling and power distribution, with conventional air cooling methods becoming increasingly unviable.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-shift-in-market-needs-beyond-co-location&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#the-shift-in-market-needs-beyond-co-location&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: the-shift-in-market-needs-beyond-co-location&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;The Shift in Market Needs: Beyond Co-location&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The market dynamics have evolved; selling space in a data center, akin to ‘advanced real estate’, is a model that is rapidly losing relevance. The traditional co-location framework, which expects customers to manage their hardware and infrastructure within leased rack space, is becoming antiquated.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the modern landscape, the role of a data center should transcend mere space rental. The emphasis should be on providing integrated solutions – selling compute, storage, and network capacity, not just rackspace and power. It’s about delivering a comprehensive service that aligns with the complex, ever-evolving needs of businesses immersed in the digital and AI revolution.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-data-center-landscape-today&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#the-data-center-landscape-today&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: the-data-center-landscape-today&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;The Data Center Landscape Today&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tier 3 and Tier 4 Data Centers are classifications outlined by the Uptime Institute, which provide standards for the design, construction, and operation of data centers. The Institute defines four tiers (1, 2, 3, &amp;amp; 4) to categorize data centers according to their design and infrastructure capabilities. For the purposes of this article, we will focus on the top two tiers.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;tier-3&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#tier-3&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: tier-3&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;Tier 3&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Tier 3 Data Center is a type of data center facility that is designed to provide a high level of availability and redundancy for IT infrastructure and data storage.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;key-characteristics&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#key-characteristics&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: key-characteristics&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;Key Characteristics&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Availability: Tier 3 Data Centers typically offer 99.982% availability, translating to around 1.6 hours of downtime per year.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Redundancy: They feature N+1 redundancy for power and cooling systems, providing backup components to ensure continuous operation in case of failure.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Concurrent Maintenance: Tier 3 Data Centers allow for maintenance and repairs to be performed on systems without disrupting operations.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cost: Tier 3 Data Centers are less expensive to build and operate compared to Tier 4 due to lower redundancy requirements.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s important to note that while Tier 3 Data Centers provide a high level of availability and redundancy, they are not as robust as Tier 4 Data Centers, which are designed to provide even higher levels of fault tolerance and uptime. The choice of data center tier depends on the specific needs and risk tolerance of the organization using the facility.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;key-challenges&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#key-challenges&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: key-challenges&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;Key Challenges&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Limited Uptime: Despite high reliability, Tier 3 Data Centers may still experience noticeable downtime, which could impact critical operations.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Single Points of Failure: While designed for redundancy, Tier 3 Data Centers may still have single points of failure, potentially leading to downtime during component failures.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scalability: They may have limitations in scalability compared to higher tier data centers, potentially requiring more significant upgrades for expansion.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a business is considering colocation or hosting in a Tier 3 Data Center, it’s important to assess its power requirements carefully. For operations with high power demands, it might be necessary to discuss with the data center provider the possibilities of allocating additional power resources or choosing a high-density zone within the data center. Data center providers typically measure power in kilowatts (kW) per rack and will have different pricing models based on the power and cooling requirements of the equipment hosted.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;tier-4&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#tier-4&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: tier-4&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;Tier 4&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Tier 4 Data Center is the most advanced type of data center tier, as classified by the Uptime Institute. The Tier 4 Data Center is the most robust and less prone to failures. Its design ensures redundancy and reliability.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;key-characteristics-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#key-characteristics-1&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: key-characteristics-1&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;Key Characteristics&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Availability: Tier 4 Data Centers offer the highest level of availability, typically guaranteeing 99.995% uptime or just around 26.3 minutes of downtime per year.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fault Tolerance: They feature a fault-tolerant design with 2N+1 redundancy for critical systems, ensuring uninterrupted operation even during component failures.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Redundancy: Tier 4 Data Centers have redundant power and cooling distribution paths, eliminating single points of failure.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Security: They often have advanced security measures in place, including biometric access controls and surveillance systems.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;key-challenges-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#key-challenges-1&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: key-challenges-1&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;Key Challenges&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Complexity: Tier 4 Data Centers are more complex and expensive to design, build, and maintain due to their fault-tolerant architecture.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;High Cost: The increased redundancy and fault tolerance come with higher costs, making Tier 4 Data Centers more expensive to operate compared to lower tiers.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overkill for Some Applications: For organizations with less critical operations or smaller budgets, Tier 4 Data Centers may be overkill and not cost-effective.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;choosing-between-tier-3-and-tier-4&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#choosing-between-tier-3-and-tier-4&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: choosing-between-tier-3-and-tier-4&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;Choosing Between Tier 3 and Tier 4&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cost vs. Need: Tier 4 Data Centers are significantly more expensive to build and operate. Organizations should assess whether they need the highest level of uptime and fault tolerance that Tier 4 provides.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Business Requirements: Businesses that can afford occasional downtimes for maintenance or those that don’t have extremely critical data operations may find Tier 3 facilities adequately sufficient.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Industry Compliance: Certain industries may require or favor Tier 4 facilities due to regulatory requirements.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In summary, while both Tier 3 and Tier 4 Data Centers are designed to ensure high levels of uptime and reliability, Tier 4 takes this a step further with increased redundancy, fault tolerance, and a correspondingly higher price point.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;introducing-the-tier-s-data-center&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#introducing-the-tier-s-data-center&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: introducing-the-tier-s-data-center&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;Introducing the Tier S Data Center&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Tier S model is designed to exceed the capabilities of traditional Tier 3 and 4 Data Centers, addressing the increasing demand for infrastructure that can support emerging IT workloads with greater efficiency and resilience. Where “S” stands for “Self-Healing,” Tier S Data Centers present a new way forward, while remaining backwards compatible.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Tier S “circular approach” allows us to build the most reliable and redundant data centers in the world. A larger data center (typically 2-10 mW capacity) is extended with at least nine edge data centers. Key features include advanced liquid cooling technology and cybersecurity mechanisms, enhancing the center’s ability to handle complex IT workloads like AI and ML.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flexibility is central to the design, with each edge data center capable of housing 3-30 pods (subsections), and a versatile main data center. The innovative self-healing technology ensures continuous, secure operations, reducing downtime and maintenance needs. The infrastructure, integrating state-of-the-art hydro coolant distribution units, is designed for high-performance computing, meeting emerging technological demands.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;key-benefits&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#key-benefits&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: key-benefits&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;Key Benefits&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Superior Reliability: Data storage is highly secure and can’t be lost, would even be safe if quantum computing would be used for hacking.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;100% Redundancy: Fully redundant power and network paths. All hardware is equipped with liquid cooling for enhanced reliability and energy-efficiency..&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Capacity and Expansion: A main data center with a 2-10 MW capacity, supplemented by at least 9 edge data centers.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flexible Configuration: Each edge data center can include 3 to 30 pods (more information below), with the main data centers configurable as pod, rack, or container-based.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Disaster Resilience: The circular design, with a main data center and edge data centers, offers robust protection against natural disasters, war, or unrest.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Self-Healing: Equipped with self-healing properties, Tier S Data Centers ensure that workloads can operate safely with minimal need for human intervention.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;in-conclusion&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#in-conclusion&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: in-conclusion&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;In Conclusion&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The existing data center model is simply insufficient for emerging demands of the IT world. Billions of dollars will be mis-spent if we continue down the existing path. This is why ThreeFold is presenting a new approach. While the Tier S Data Center is still in its conceptual phase, we are actively working with partners on implementing the first of its kind in the near future.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>An Open Invitation for Testing</title>
        <published>2022-10-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2022-10-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/open-invitation-for-testing/"/>
        <id>https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/open-invitation-for-testing/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/open-invitation-for-testing/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“This article was originally published by Hannah Cordes, a former member of ThreeFold Foundation.”&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ThreeFold technology, ecosystem and community have the potential to kickstart a new Internet era filled with abundance and opportunities for all. ThreeFold is 100% open-source, so anyone can contribute to ThreeFold on GitHub and build their own solutions and applications on ThreeFold’s infrastructure.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now’s the time to start utilizing what we’ve built together and to start deploying the solutions and experiences we want to see in this world. Now’s the time to build better alternatives for people, enterprises and governments on top of this foundational infrastructure.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We invite you all to come in, see what’s possible, and start building – today!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-is-testing-so-crucial&quot;&gt;Why is testing so crucial?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold created an open-source peer-to-peer Internet infrastructure that offers a place for developers, end-users and everyone in-between to collectively build an open digital world with full digital sovereignty. We seek to re-imagine business, governance, finance, education and more to build a better future for all.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This future can only be achieved with the collaboration of a strong, healthy and dedicated community. One of the key challenges for a project like ours is the continuous testing and improving of new features as well as building all of the applications and solutions we’d like to see to enhance and grow the ecosystem. Community contributions are the heart and a crucial driver of the growing ThreeFold movement – a global movement that is open and decentralized, meaning it is up to each and everyone of us to push things forward.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No matter your experience level, from developers to end-users and everyone in-between, there are options for you to contribute to ThreeFold. Whether you’re more tech-savvy and would like to develop solutions on top of the Grid and test tech features or rather help us improve the manuals and spread the word, there are many ways to take action and support the movement.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A reliable, open-source peer-to-peer infrastructure together with a growing community of enthusiastic, driven developers and end-users are the key to accelerating the growth and development of the Grid and to unlocking all of its potential. And the more people believe in ThreeFold and our Internet of Internets vision, the sooner we can bring digital sovereignty, empowerment and meaningful experiences to the world.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-should-you-join-threefold-s-tester-community&quot;&gt;Why should you join ThreeFold’s tester community?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So why get involved in ThreeFold? Well first of all, you can join an engaged, open movement that seeks to shape the future we want to live in and provide better solutions for our planet and people. You can meet, exchange and collaborate with people from all over the world that share similar interests and values.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You also learn new skills and get to know some innovative technology that enables you to build and test pretty cool applications and solutions – like deploying a Subsquid instance on the &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;play.grid.tf&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Playground&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; or checking out the different decentralized alternatives to solutions we use every day like WhatsApp, YouTube, Chrome or Zoom with &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;demo.freeflow.life&quot;&gt;FreeFlow Twin&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Our open, friendly and skilled community can offer you support and advice as you start testing and building. Let’s help each other and build cool stuff together!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-threefold-community-where-ideas-come-to-life&quot;&gt;The ThreeFold Community – Where ideas come to life&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Curious about what fellow community members are building on ThreeFold? Here are a few recent examples:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Teisie has been working on a few great tools to make things easier for his fellow ThreeFolders like an iOS app for node monitoring and a geo explorer. Moreover, he’s been working on an uptime tool and deployment calculator – hosted on the Grid and using Drew’s gateway node for public access. Learn more &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;teisies-uptime-tool-and-deployment-calculator&#x2F;3384?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Well done, Teisie!&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Another skilled community member building on the Grid is Drew. With his &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;cockpit-managed-ubuntu-vm&#x2F;3376?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;community project&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for a Cockpit management interface, he provides a web-based interface for managing a VM that allows users to do a lot of maintenance tasks without ssh – even including full remote desktop capabilities from the browser. Pretty cool, right?&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what are you waiting for? Start exploring and using the many solutions on the ThreeFold Grid today – whether by deploying a weblet, testing the FreeFlow Twin or simply joining our testing group!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-get-started&quot;&gt;How to get started?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many ways to get started with ThreeFold. If you’re new to ThreeFold in general, I recommend starting with “&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;how-threefold-is-building-a-new-internet-from-the-ground-up&#x2F;2057?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;Building a New Internet From the Ground Up&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;” – an approachable blog series on the inner workings of the Grid.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A great way to learn more is also by checking out the &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.docsend.com&#x2F;view&#x2F;7x2pezpn2548v8qq&#x2F;d&#x2F;an66sngk5h3yf2zk&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Litepaper&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and by exploring the &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold&#x2F;#&#x2F;&quot;&gt;knowledge base&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. The ThreeFold Grid &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;manual&#x2F;#&#x2F;&quot;&gt;manual&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; has everything you need to dive right into ThreeFold’s open-source infrastructure and technology.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Key resources to get started:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find out what you &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;manual&#x2F;#&#x2F;manual__faq?id=what-can-i-do-on-threefold-grid&quot;&gt;can do on Threefold Grid&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dive into the &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;manual&#x2F;#&#x2F;&quot;&gt;manual&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to get started&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn more about &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;manual&#x2F;#&#x2F;manual__grid3_testing?id=testing-the-threefold_grid3&quot;&gt;testing&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; the Grid&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Join our &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefoldtesting&quot;&gt;testing community&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Watch helpful tutorials from the community in the &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;threefold-video-gallery&#x2F;3091?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Video Gallery&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn how to &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;how-to-contribute-to-threefold-wikis-and-websites&#x2F;1154&quot;&gt;contribute to ThreeFold wikis and websites&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Build on ThreeFold’s Open Infrastructure – Part Three: Weblets &amp; End-Users</title>
        <published>2022-09-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2022-09-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/build-on-threefolds-open-infrastructure-part-three/"/>
        <id>https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/build-on-threefolds-open-infrastructure-part-three/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/build-on-threefolds-open-infrastructure-part-three/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“This article was originally published by Hannah Cordes, a former member of ThreeFold Foundation.”&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post is the third one in a series about building on ThreeFold’s open infrastructure. While &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;build-on-threefolds-open-infrastructure&#x2F;&quot;&gt;part one&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, gives you a comprehensive overview of the Grid, its evolution and capabilities, the &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;build-on-threefolds-open-infrastructure-part-two&#x2F;&quot;&gt;second part&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is focused on the low-level building blocks and particularly interesting for the more tech-savvy crowd.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the third and final part of our series on ThreeFold’s game-changing Internet infrastructure and the solutions available today. This time, we’ll show you what’s possible on the ThreeFold Playground today and how you can become one of the first testers of digitally sovereign end-user experiences.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an incredible opportunity to become early adopters of our unique solutions, to get a taste of what it means to become digitally sovereign, and to help shape the future of the Internet. Together we build a decentralized digital world!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;explore-a-playground-full-of-simple-yet-powerful-deployment-experiences&quot;&gt;Explore a playground full of simple yet powerful deployment experiences&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;play.grid.tf&#x2F;&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Playground&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; makes it quite easy to build on top of the ThreeFold Grid by deploying weblets. A &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;manual&#x2F;#&#x2F;manual__weblets_home?id=weblets&quot;&gt;weblet&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is a compiled JavaScript component which can be embedded in any site. With ThreeFold, it basically establishes a private environment running inside your browser, and allows you to share it – while you maintain full control of all activities happening there by using your private key, and with full decentralization.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the TF Playground, a variety of applications are made available and deployable within just a few clicks, all on top of a fully decentralized peer-to-peer Internet infrastructure. From Virtual Machines to Kubernetes to Presearch Nodes, CapRover, ownCloud, and more – the playground allows you to build in a truly decentralized environment. Essentially, the Playground is an ever-expanding ecosystem of easily-deployable weblets that are built for a decentralized future. It’s the fastest way to build, test, and deploy and enables pretty much anyone to build and experiment with deployment on the Grid. So, this is huge!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;play.grid.tf&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Visit&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; the TF Playground to explore the possibilities and read this &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;threefold-product-focus-series-tf-playground-v3-7-0&#x2F;3315?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;post&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to find out what the new version 3.7.0 of the Playground – now live on testnet – has to offer. Dive right in and &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;manual&#x2F;#&#x2F;getstarted&#x2F;manual__tfgrid3_getstarted&quot;&gt;get started&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on the TF Grid today!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are a few examples of the weblets available on the Playground:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;presearch&quot;&gt;Presearch&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presearch is a longstanding partner of ThreeFold and one of the most popular solutions offered on the Grid. As of the Grid v3.6 release, any 3Node can now host a Presearch node – so if you’re a ThreeFold farmer, it’s now become quite easy for you to host Presearch on your own node. Simply follow &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;presearch-nodes&#x2F;3250?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;this deployment guide&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to get decentralized search on top of a truly decentralized infrastructure!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;caprover&quot;&gt;CapRover&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leverage the entire &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;caprover-your-app-environment&#x2F;2133&#x2F;3&quot;&gt;CapRover app catalogue&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; even faster and easier and deploy CapRover apps on the ThreeFold Grid. You’ll benefit from full decentralization, energy efficiency and affordability. &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;create-your-own-app-environment-fast-and-easy-with-caprover-on-the-people-s-internet&#x2F;2644?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;CapRover&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is a powerful platform for app deployment and thanks to our &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;manual&#x2F;#&#x2F;manual__weblets_caprover?id=caprover&quot;&gt;CapRover weblet&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, you’re able to deploy anything you want on top of the ThreeFold Grid!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;new-subsquid-testnet&quot;&gt;NEW: Subsquid (testnet)&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;tfgrid-v3-7-0-is-now-live&#x2F;3375?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;latest addition&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to the ThreeFold Playground is &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;manual&#x2F;#&#x2F;manual__weblets_subsquid&quot;&gt;Subsquid&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, Web3’s premier API framework which is supercharging decentralized apps across more than 30 chains. Basically, you can think of Subsquid as an ETL (extract, transform, load) tool, with a GraphQL server included. With Grid v3.7.0 live on testnet, you can now pre-process and decode raw chain data and store it for easier access by the query nodes by deploying your own Subsquid instance on the Grid’s testnet within just a few clicks &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;play.test.grid.tf&#x2F;#&#x2F;subsquid&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So with the ThreeFold Playground, ThreeFold is building a vast ecosystem of advanced deployment experiences and opening up a world of possibilities – allowing anyone to build, test and deploy easily and within a few clicks.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the best thing about the &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;manual&#x2F;#&#x2F;getstarted&#x2F;manual__tfgrid3_getstarted&quot;&gt;playground&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;? It’s already been available for a while and continuously being improved and extended!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-achieve-digital-sovereignty-with-a-set-of-end-user-experiences&quot;&gt;How to achieve digital sovereignty with a set of end-user experiences&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Through simple, secure, and scalable technology, ThreeFold empowers millions to invent and explore new experiences.“ – &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.threefold.io&#x2F;newsroom&#x2F;paradise-hills&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Kristof de Spiegeleer&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve entered the &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;four-phases-of-threefold&#x2F;&quot;&gt;third phase of our journey&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; towards our ultimate vision of a better future – the phase of Web 4. In addition to fully comprehensive decentralized edge cloud solutions, the ThreeFold ecosystem is also developing a range of applications and experiences across IoT, metaverse, blockchain, DeFi, banking, education and beyond.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout this phase – which has only just begun – a multitude of valuable and meaningful experiences are being built by the ThreeFold ecosystem and partners to empower people with equal chances to learn, create, and thrive in a decentralized digital economy – what we like to call an abundance-based future for humanity.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first roll-out of the third phase will empower people to become fully self-sovereign thanks to ThreeFold’s Digital Twin technology and a variety of decentralized alternatives to popular applications and tools. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;freeflow-twin&quot;&gt;FreeFlow Twin&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Digital Twin technology provides each user with a unique digital identity that can serve as the key to an open, self-sovereign and complete digital future. This solution was designed with a very simple objective in mind: everyone should be the center of their entire digital life. It represents your digital self and hosts your entire digital life in a secure and private way – empowering you to own your data and offering you decentralized applications that enable you to maintain your sovereignty. For end users, owning their own deployments opens the possibility for a full range of experiences that have the same quality as crypto – self custody.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Grid V3.7.0, ThreeFold’s all-in-one decentralized productivity tool that includes instant messaging, video call, social, and data storage features – formerly known as Uhuru – is being rebranded to &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;lets-test-out-freeflow-twin-beta-formerly-uhuru&#x2F;3299?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;FreeFlow Twin&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. It brings sovereign and secure alternatives to many of the centralized solutions we use every day like Facebook, WhatsApp, YouTube, Chrome, Zoom and many more.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;threefold-product-updates-august-2022&#x2F;3272?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;FreeFlow Twin&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; will be part of an ecosystem of decentralized alternatives called FreeFlow Life. Find more information on the experiences, how to start testing now and where to share your feedback &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;lets-test-out-freeflow-twin-beta-formerly-uhuru&#x2F;3299?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This paradigm shift is a pretty big deal, isn’t it?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;defi-solutions&quot;&gt;DeFi Solutions&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve also decided to develop our &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;future-tft-ecosystem&#x2F;&quot;&gt;own DeFi solutions&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to support the growth and expansion of the Internet of Internets and an abundance-based future where we are truly sovereign: community-based liquidity pools and the P2P DeFi Wallet – both expected early next year. Learn more about the upcoming solutions &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;future-tft-ecosystem&#x2F;&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-grid-is-open-an-invitation-to-build-deploy-and-test&quot;&gt;The Grid is open – an invitation to build, deploy and test&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold’s open Internet infrastructure is fully peer-to-peer, decentralized and super reliable. It already offers a multitude of solutions for developers, end-users and everyone in-between. And the Grid and the solutions offered are ready for the community to build, deploy and test, as we continue to collectively build, advance and expand.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And while we’ve collectively already built a lot and achieved crucial milestones towards realizing our ultimate goals, we’re also just the beginning of the third phase of our exciting journey with many ambitions and goals still ahead.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While we’re still in a spot where we can be considered a hidden gem and being way undervalued, remember this: ThreeFold is inevitable. We are visionaries, building the plane in the air. We are confident in growing the project in a real and authentic way. We have a strong plan and vision. Our technology is needed. The underlying foundation is functional and ready. Now, it’s up to the believers to build, test and deploy the solutions we need for a better world. And together, we build. Together, we can achieve the extraordinary and provide better alternatives for people, enterprises and governments.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We not only invite you to come see what’s possible. We invite you to get involved. What are you waiting for?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Start exploring and using the many solutions on the ThreeFold Grid today – whether by deploying a weblet, testing the FreeFlow Twin or simply joining our &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefoldtesting&quot;&gt;testing group&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;build-on-threefolds-open-infrastructure&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Build on ThreeFold’s Open Infrastructure – Part One: Intro&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;build-on-threefolds-open-infrastructure-part-two&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Build on ThreeFold’s Open Infrastructure – Part Two: For Experts&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Not sure where to start? Dive into the &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;manual&#x2F;#&#x2F;&quot;&gt;manual&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and learn more about &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;manual&#x2F;#&#x2F;manual__grid3_testing?id=testing-the-threefold_grid3&quot;&gt;testing the ThreeFold Grid&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Build on ThreeFold’s Open Infrastructure – Part Two: For Experts</title>
        <published>2022-09-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2022-09-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/build-on-threefolds-open-infrastructure-part-two/"/>
        <id>https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/build-on-threefolds-open-infrastructure-part-two/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/build-on-threefolds-open-infrastructure-part-two/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“This article was originally published by Hannah Cordes, a former member of ThreeFold Foundation.”&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold’s reliable, open-source, peer-to-peer Internet infrastructure together with a growing community of enthusiastic, driven early-adopter developers and end-users are the key to accelerating the growth and development of the Grid and to unlocking all of its potential. While the foundation has been laid, it will be up to all of us as a movement to improve and build upon it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After looking back at the ThreeFold Grid’s evolution and what makes it a game-changing Internet infrastructure in &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;build-on-threefolds-open-infrastructure&#x2F;&quot;&gt;part one&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, it’s time to explore our cloud solution and the technology available today in part two! You can think of these as some of the essential low-level building blocks that when combined created a limitless sandbox for developers.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re wondering what virtual machines are, haven’t heard about Kubernetes before and don’t know your way around coding languages, this part might be less interesting for you. Feel free to skip and jump right into &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;build-on-threefolds-open-infrastructure-part-three&#x2F;&quot;&gt;part three&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on weblets and end-user experiences.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;elements-of-our-comprehensive-decentralized-cloud-solution&quot;&gt;Elements of our comprehensive &amp;amp; decentralized cloud solution&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ThreeFold Grid provides &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;technology&#x2F;threefold__tfgrid_primitives&quot;&gt;various primitives&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for compute, storage, and network – fulfilling all the needs centralized cloud providers cater to as well, while offering advantages in terms of decentralization, energy efficiency, security and more. &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;all-you-need-to-know-about-zero-os&#x2F;1734&quot;&gt;Zero-OS&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; includes a collection of components, called primitives. These primitives are the low-level constructs which can be deployed on the ThreeFold Grid. As mentioned above, they act as building blocks for skilled developers that enable them to build and create in complete digital freedom.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, the high compatibility of ThreeFold’s primitives with industry-standard tools and protocols makes it easy and seamless for developers to migrate workloads to the Grid. All of the primitives not only benefit from the unique efficiency and security features of &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;technology&#x2F;threefold__zos&quot;&gt;Zero-OS&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, but also come with unique features and capabilities themselves. Here are some of the primitives to give you an idea of what you’ll get:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;zmachine&quot;&gt;ZMachine&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold’s &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;technology&#x2F;zmachine?id=zmachine&quot;&gt;ZMachine&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is a lightweight virtual machine (VM) solution that’s unique to the ThreeFold Grid. ZMachine enables both traditional VM deployments and also introduces a next generation container specification built on our &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;technology&#x2F;threefold__zos_fs?id=why-this-zflist-concept&quot;&gt;ZFlist&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; technology. ZFlist containers enabled by ZMachines are more secure and more flexible than the current industry standard Docker-based containers. With Kubernetes running on top of ThreeFold’s ZMachine &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;threefold__grid_use?id=tfgrid-kubernetes-cloud&quot;&gt;technology&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, we have a highly compatible and unique solution.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;zflist&quot;&gt;ZFlist&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;technology&#x2F;threefold__zos_fs?id=why-this-zflist-concept&quot;&gt;ZFlist&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is a next generation container format – supported directly at the operating system level on Zero-OS – which extends the industry-standard Docker container concept in an efficient and secure way. It provides a unique advantage over traditional containers via the use of mini VMs. By employing mini VMs, the FList concept provides better isolation than traditional container systems while retaining the advantages that containers offer over full VMs.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;kubernetes&quot;&gt;Kubernetes&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold has long supported the most used open-source container orchestration tool in the world, &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;kubernetes.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Kubernetes&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, which integrates the industry standard &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.docker.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Docker&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; format, a container creation and management tool. It’s used to manage many of the largest and most complex cloud deployments. Kubernetes can be used to create a production-ready environment. The ThreeFold Grid provides a lightweight Kubernetes VM that can be used to create clusters according to specific needs. By providing both VMs and Kubernetes, we’re able to offer the most comprehensive solution in the decentralized&#x2F;blockchain space to deploy, scale, and manage cloud compute workloads. Kubernetes users can, for the most part, simply bring their existing configuration files and recreate their deployments on a Grid based cluster seamlessly. With the third generation of the Grid, we provided a very simple way to provision &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;manual&#x2F;#&#x2F;manual3_iac&#x2F;grid3_terraform&#x2F;manual__terraform_k8s?id=more-info&quot;&gt;Kubernetes clusters with Terraform&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;terraform&quot;&gt;Terraform&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;threefold-grid-3-0-supports-terraform&#x2F;1184?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;Terraform&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is a widely-used open-source Infrastructure as Code (IaC) software tool enabling a consistent workflow in order to manage complex deployments across different cloud providers. It also integrates directly with our Grid’s &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;cloud&#x2F;threefold__usp_compatible?id=kubernetes&quot;&gt;existing Kubernetes functionality&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to offer a complete solution for reserving hardware and deploying software.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a nutshell, Terraform offers a complete solution for reserving hardware and deploying software. It allows for specifying deployments on the &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;threefold__tfgrid_home&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Grid&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; in a simple, declarative, and human-readable language describing the desired end state. Terraform can be used to deploy the full set of &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;all-you-need-to-know-about-zero-os&#x2F;1734&quot;&gt;Zero-OS&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; primitives, supporting any existing or future Linux workload, with endless possibilities. It is like a lower-level Kubernetes for the hardware part of cloud deployments.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;dedicated-nodes&quot;&gt;Dedicated Nodes&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re also supporting &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;exciting-news-dedicated-nodes-on-the-people-s-internet&#x2F;2645?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;dedicated nodes&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. By utilizing dedicated nodes on the ThreeFold Grid, you’ll benefit from a truly decentralized and highly reliable Internet infrastructure that uses less energy and comes at a much more affordable price than any comparable alternative. With dedicated nodes, users are able to exclusively reserve the entire capacity of a 3Node to deploy solutions for themselves or for other customers, while also paying for all capacity of the respective 3Node. Dedicated nodes on our Grid will be highly cost effective, as they’ll be available with a 70% discount on &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;pricing-for-tfgrid&#x2F;2518&#x2F;7&quot;&gt;pricing&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. All the ThreeFold Grid features will be available on &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;exciting-news-dedicated-nodes-on-the-people-s-internet&#x2F;2645?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;dedicated nodes&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; as well – from deploying VMs and containers to CapRover and more. Dedicated and non-dedicated 3Nodes can be combined.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;v-language&quot;&gt;V Language&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold is built with simplicity in mind which is why we’re using &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.threefold.io&#x2F;partners&#x2F;vlang&#x2F;&quot;&gt;V&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; – a statically typed programming language similar to Go, and inspired by Rust, Swift, and Oberon. It’s the official &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;technology&#x2F;threefold__smartcontract_it&quot;&gt;smart contract&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; language on the Grid, as its simplicity and readability allows anyone to go through and understand any code base, even non-developers.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite being simple, V gives a lot of power to the developer and can be used in pretty much every field, including systems programming, webdev, gamedev, GUI, mobile, science, embedded, tooling, etc. It aims to become an alternative to JavaScript as the de facto coding language on the market in the upcoming years. With V, the developer doesn’t need to change anything in their code. “It just works”, like in Python, Go, or Java, except there’s no heavy GC tracing everything or expensive RC for each object. V can translate your entire C project and offer you the safety, simplicity, and 10-25x faster compilation speeds.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With +30,5K Stars on &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;vlang&#x2F;v&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, V brings a strong open-source developer community to the ThreeFold ecosystem to develop the infrastructures and applications of tomorrow – making it the ideal smart contract language for the ThreeFold ecosystem.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;an-open-invitation&quot;&gt;An open invitation&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, now that you’ve learned more about the building blocks of the ThreeFold Grid and how you can build with them, we’d like to invite you to try and test them yourselves!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While we’re very proud of our progress and the strong ecosystem around us, now’s the time to build upon the foundation. The team continues to do incredible work to further develop and advance the Grid with each and every release. They continue to improve the components, develop new features and build new solutions.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With your support, the team can work even faster. If you share our belief in open source and decentralization, we invite you to help us test and improve not only the Grid and its primitives but also the solutions built on top. Together, we keep building and advancing to realize our Internet of Internets vision and to empower people with true digital sovereignty. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dive into the &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;manual&#x2F;#&#x2F;&quot;&gt;manual&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to get started&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn more about &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;manual&#x2F;#&#x2F;manual__grid3_testing?id=testing-the-threefold_grid3&quot;&gt;testing the ThreeFold Grid&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Join this growing &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefold&quot;&gt;movement&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; &amp;amp; our &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefoldtesting&quot;&gt;testing community&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;join-us-for-part-three&quot;&gt;Join us for &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;build-on-threefolds-open-infrastructure-part-three&#x2F;&quot;&gt;part three&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;!&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get ready for &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;build-on-threefolds-open-infrastructure-part-three&#x2F;&quot;&gt;part three&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; of our series where we’re diving into a world of possibilities for developers, end-users and everyone in-between. The final part will not only show you what’s possible on the ThreeFold Playground today but also introduce you to our end-user experiences that empower you with digital sovereignty which are available for beta testing now!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Build on ThreeFold’s Open Infrastructure – Part One: Intro</title>
        <published>2022-09-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2022-09-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/build-on-threefolds-open-infrastructure/"/>
        <id>https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/build-on-threefolds-open-infrastructure/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/build-on-threefolds-open-infrastructure/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“This article was originally published by Hannah Cordes, a former member of ThreeFold Foundation.”&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What started out as an idea for a better Internet about a decade ago amongst a few early Internet and Cloud pioneers has now become a reality. Today, ThreeFold is a global movement building a reliable, open and inclusive Internet.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve reached a pivotal moment in the evolution of the Internet. And ThreeFold is ready to unlock a new Internet era – one filled with &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;planet-first-people-first&#x2F;&quot;&gt;abundance and opportunity&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for all, one which is better for &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;planting-the-seeds&#x2F;&quot;&gt;our planet&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Our open-source technology, future-facing ecosystem and collaborative community have the potential to drive this new era forward.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For us, the Internet was always meant to be &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;p2p-web3&#x2F;&quot;&gt;peer-to-peer&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, where anyone could own hardware, and connect and exchange directly with full security and in full privacy – without any entity in the middle. This is how the Internet began. But as demand grew, big tech began to monopolize its infrastructure and all the major platforms.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since its inception, ThreeFold has been committed not only to delivering on the original promise of the Internet, but also to realizing our ultimate vision of a better future for all. For the past six years, we’ve been building up an incredible full-stack, open-source, decentralized Internet, all &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;how-threefold-is-building-a-new-internet-from-the-ground-up&#x2F;2057?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;from the ground-up&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. We’ve come a long way and the result is, well, exceptional. There is &lt;em&gt;nothing&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; else out there like ThreeFold.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From creating our own blockchain-driven and highly secure &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;all-you-need-to-know-about-zero-os&#x2F;1734?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;operating system&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (which allows computers to become decentralized servers), to building an ultra-scalable &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;technology&#x2F;qsss&#x2F;threefold__qsss_home?id=quantum-safe-storage-system&quot;&gt;Quantum Safe Storage System&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, a complete far &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;internet-at-the-edge&#x2F;&quot;&gt;edge cloud&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; computing platform and a &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;how-our-planetary-network-works&#x2F;1210?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;planetary peer-to-peer network&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; all accessible via a unique Smart Contract for IT on the &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;tf-chain&#x2F;&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Blockchain&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, we’re proud to have the most &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;internet-at-the-edge&#x2F;&quot;&gt;complete edge infrastructure&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to power the next-generation Internet era.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And we’re taking concrete steps to further expand this infrastructure that offers a truly decentralized layer 0 for any blockchain or Internet application. Moreover, with the help of our &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefoldtesting&quot;&gt;community of Grid testers&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, we’re continuously advancing the underlying technology and working towards making it usable for as many people and use cases as possible.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our vision and technology have matured into the &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;internet-of-internets&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Internet of Internets&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; – a network of thousands of community-built and -owned Internets through which we strive to interconnect all of humanity. A new world is coming, and &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;technology&#x2F;threefold__technology&quot;&gt;our technology&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; has the potential to revolutionize digitization on a global scale, across sectors. And yet we remain a hidden gem.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, what solutions does the ThreeFold Grid offer today already? And why exactly should you start to build on top of ThreeFold? Let’s explore some of the many possibilities available today.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-threefold-grid-a-cutting-edge-highly-scalable-peer-to-peer-infrastructure&quot;&gt;The ThreeFold Grid – A cutting-edge, highly scalable peer-to-peer infrastructure&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“ThreeFold is growing the ThreeFold Grid by enabling a community of thousands of farmers from around the world to participate and own a piece of the Internet.” – &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;news&#x2F;post&#x2F;threefold_cybernews&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Adnan Fatayerji&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Grid is a peer-to-peer cloud computing network that’s highly compatible with current industry standards. In late December 2021, ThreeFold launched the third generation of the ThreeFold Grid on mainnet with a fully functional tech stack – a huge and crucial step towards a fully production-ready and decentralized infrastructure. The third generation not only brought a massive leap forward in the decentralization of the Grid but also made for a much simpler user experience for farmers and Grid users. People from all over the world are connecting thousands of 3Nodes to create the world’s largest decentralized Internet infrastructure, and new capacity is being connected every day. Find the latest Grid stats and utilization numbers in &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;grid-stats-new-nodes-overview&#x2F;3291?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;this regularly updated thread&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;threefold-2022-reflect-h1-outlook-h2&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Over the past months&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, the team evolved the Grid through version 3.6.1 and upgraded it to mainnet in July after receiving 100% community approval. This &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;tfgrid-product-updates-july-2022-tfgrid-v3-6-1-highlights-and-more&#x2F;3206&#x2F;2?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;release&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; introduces more stability to the TF Grid and includes various upgrades and new features like the ThreeFold Connect App, the new unified dashboard for a simpler user experience, and more. Big progress was also made in terms of the DAO functionality that went live on TF Chain, with the first TF Chain (L1) DAO proposal was voted on and approved in August.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And with each new Grid release, we’re getting one step closer to solidifying the foundation of the Internet of Internets. Currently, the team is working towards completing &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;threefold-product-updates-august-2022&#x2F;3272?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;Grid version 3.7.0&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; which includes some significant updates, improvements and new features like FreeFlow Twin, a new Node Pilot, new deployment features and &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;threefold-product-updates-august-2022&#x2F;3272?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;a lot more&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. The team continues to do incredible work to further develop and advance the Grid as well as to support utilization and adoption by offering tools and applications that are user-friendly, secure, efficient and scalable. A massive thank you to our incredible tech team and the community of Grid testers!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;next-up-our-cloud-solution&quot;&gt;Next up: our cloud solution&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, the ThreeFold Grid has been evolved, advanced and expanded quite a bit, hasn’t it? About time to take a closer look at our cloud solution and everything enabled by the technology and tooling built on top. As a heads up, part two of our series on ThreeFold’s game-changing Internet infrastructure is for the more tech-savvy crowd. If you don’t consider yourself “a tech person” you might prefer to jump to part three on weblets and end-user experiences right away.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Helpful Resources:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dive into the &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;manual&#x2F;#&#x2F;&quot;&gt;manual&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to get started&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find out more about our &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;technology&#x2F;technology&quot;&gt;technology&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn more about &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;manual&#x2F;#&#x2F;manual__grid3_testing?id=testing-the-threefold_grid3&quot;&gt;testing the ThreeFold Grid&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Join this growing &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefold&quot;&gt;movement&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; &amp;amp; our &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefoldtesting&quot;&gt;testing community&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>ThreeFold Weekly! July 5th, 2022 (Vol 23)</title>
        <published>2022-07-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2022-07-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/weekly-vol-23/"/>
        <id>https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/weekly-vol-23/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/weekly-vol-23/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“This article was originally published by Hannah Cordes, a former member of ThreeFold Foundation.”&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As of edition 24, we’ll only share the Weekly via email and &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefoldnews&quot;&gt;TF News&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, so make sure to subscribe via the respective buttons on the top-right corner of &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&quot;&gt;our website&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;community-updates&quot;&gt;Community Updates:&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;YouTube influencer &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;channel&#x2F;UCPRC2wIfZtAlzCa_6iKE46w&quot;&gt;Tactical Investing&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; featured ThreeFold in a &lt;strong&gt;new video&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; and shared the &lt;strong&gt;potential of ThreeFold farming&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; with his community of 82.3K subscribers. Watch it &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;youtu.be&#x2F;maISozq2p1o&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;!&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You’re going on vacation but don’t know how to check on your 3Nodes? Read the community-sourced &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;tf-farm-tips-when-youre-away-for-some-days&#x2F;3088?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;tips and tricks&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on how to &lt;strong&gt;secure and maintain your TF farm&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; while you’re away.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Did you already check out the new &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;threefold-video-gallery&#x2F;3091?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Video Gallery&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;? It’s a collection of all video material available on ThreeFold – from deep dive sessions to DIY tutorials and more!&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;technology-developments&quot;&gt;Technology Developments:&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TF Chain&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; was updated to the latest version of Substrate on devnet. This will facilitate further development and allows us to get code reviews from the Parity team.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We now have a new &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;manual&#x2F;#&#x2F;manual__manual3_tfservices?id=supported-planetary-network-nodes&quot;&gt;peer list&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; available for the &lt;strong&gt;Planetary Network&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; which you can use to access the end-to-end encrypted peer-to-peer global overlay network.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start testing &lt;strong&gt;ThreeFold Grid V3.6.0 live&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; on testnet. Check out the full release with actionable tips for testing &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;tfgrid-v3-6-0-is-now-live&#x2F;3084?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;!&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;threefold-grid&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Grid:&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take a look at this &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;tf-grid-deploying-workloads&#x2F;3094?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;actionable guide&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for &lt;strong&gt;deploying workloads on the ThreeFold Grid&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, shared by all-star farmer Mik, and get started today!&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Migrate your 3Nodes to V3&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; asap by following the simple steps of the &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;farming-migration-grid-v2-v3&#x2F;2143?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;migration process&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Global Titan shipping continues, so don’t forget to provide all &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;creating-your-v3-farm-required-for-open-unshipped-orders&#x2F;2144&quot;&gt;information&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for your Titan order to ensure quick delivery.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See you next week, ThreeFolders! 🙌&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you’re a community member interested in &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;looking-for-farmer-stories-to-share-with-the-world&#x2F;2398?u=hannahcordes&quot;&gt;sharing your story&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; or &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;looking-for-people-to-feature-in-threefold-content-its-super-simple&#x2F;2636&#x2F;3&quot;&gt;being featured&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; in ThreeFold content, please reach out!&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can find the previous editions on &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&quot;&gt;our blog&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. For older editions of ThreeFold Weekly (Vol 1-11), go to &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;c&#x2F;ecosystem-developments&#x2F;41&quot;&gt;our forum&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>The Internet is Moving to the Edge</title>
        <published>2022-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2022-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/internet-at-the-edge/"/>
        <id>https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/internet-at-the-edge/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/internet-at-the-edge/">&lt;p&gt;With new devices being connected every day and emerging technologies like the Internet of Things (IoT), the metaverse and Web 3 gaining popularity, the &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.cbre.com&#x2F;en&#x2F;insights&#x2F;reports&#x2F;north-america-data-center-trends-h2-2021&quot;&gt;demand&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for Internet capacity is booming. Already, these developments are shifting the &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.securityinfowatch.com&#x2F;perimeter-security&#x2F;physical-hardening&#x2F;article&#x2F;21263002&#x2F;real-words-or-buzzwords-edge-cloud-and-the-evolving-internet&quot;&gt;Internet’s “center of gravity”&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; from its core to the edges in order to keep up with the growing demand. In an increasingly interconnected world, centralized cloud architectures are proving to be &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.forbes.com&#x2F;sites&#x2F;forbestechcouncil&#x2F;2022&#x2F;03&#x2F;25&#x2F;demystifying-edge-technology&#x2F;&quot;&gt;bottlenecks&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; hindering future growth.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some interesting numbers to emphasize the explosive growth of connected devices and the impending data explosion:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Back in 2018, &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.securityinfowatch.com&#x2F;perimeter-security&#x2F;physical-hardening&#x2F;article&#x2F;21263002&#x2F;real-words-or-buzzwords-edge-cloud-and-the-evolving-internet&quot;&gt;90% of global data creation&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; took place within the two previous years.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In 2022, &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.securityinfowatch.com&#x2F;perimeter-security&#x2F;physical-hardening&#x2F;article&#x2F;21263002&#x2F;real-words-or-buzzwords-edge-cloud-and-the-evolving-internet&quot;&gt;4.95 billion people&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; are using the Internet and about &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.securityinfowatch.com&#x2F;perimeter-security&#x2F;physical-hardening&#x2F;article&#x2F;21263002&#x2F;real-words-or-buzzwords-edge-cloud-and-the-evolving-internet&quot;&gt;2.5 quintillion bytes&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; of data are created on a daily basis.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;About 2 billion computers, 15 billion mobile devices and more than 22 billion IoT devices are &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.securityinfowatch.com&#x2F;perimeter-security&#x2F;physical-hardening&#x2F;article&#x2F;21263002&#x2F;real-words-or-buzzwords-edge-cloud-and-the-evolving-internet&quot;&gt;active worldwide&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on a daily basis.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;By 2025, more than &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.cisco.com&#x2F;c&#x2F;en&#x2F;us&#x2F;solutions&#x2F;executive-perspectives&#x2F;annual-internet-report&#x2F;index.html&quot;&gt;1 billion people&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.statista.com&#x2F;statistics&#x2F;471264&#x2F;iot-number-of-connected-devices-worldwide&#x2F;#:~:text=Internet%20of%20Things%20%2D%20number%20of%20connected%20devices%20worldwide%202015%2D2025&amp;amp;text=By%202025%2C%20forecasts%20suggest%20that,IoT%20installed%20base%20in%202019.&quot;&gt;75 billion IoT devices&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; are expected to join the Internet.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And yet, the expansion of Internet capacity still largely occurs in the same centralized and inefficient way. The client-server model of hyperscale data centers is unable to meet this rapidly growing demand due to high building and operational costs to fulfill bandwidth, performance and cybersecurity requirements. As data centers are primarily built in the US, China and Europe, emerging countries have to be connected via sea cables which makes the model’s limitations particularly severe for these countries. And even in countries where many data centers are located, they are built in regions where land and electricity are as cheap as possible. Consequently, the bulk of data centers is still &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.securityinfowatch.com&#x2F;perimeter-security&#x2F;physical-hardening&#x2F;article&#x2F;21263002&#x2F;real-words-or-buzzwords-edge-cloud-and-the-evolving-internet&quot;&gt;far away&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; from where the majority of users and connected devices reside, and where huge amounts of data are generated that require processing – resulting in a &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;threefold__grid_valuation?id=what39s-the-potential-of-the-threefold-grid&quot;&gt;weak distribution&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; of Internet capacity.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.seagate.com&#x2F;files&#x2F;www-content&#x2F;our-story&#x2F;rethink-data&#x2F;files&#x2F;Rethink_Data_Report_2020.pdf&quot;&gt;175 Zettabytes&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; of data will be created by 2025, as our economy becomes increasingly digital and data driven. And this amount of data needs to be captured, stored and activated in a secure, efficient and high-performing way. So, the aforementioned technological use cases will not only &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.cbre.com&#x2F;en&#x2F;insights&#x2F;reports&#x2F;north-america-data-center-trends-h2-2021&quot;&gt;accelerate the demand&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for Internet capacity but also require edge capabilities, such as low latencies, in order to run and scale successfully. In fact, the centralized data center model poses one of the biggest obstacles to the success and spread of the Internet of Things and related applications. This will have to change. Actually, industry experts &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.i-scoop.eu&#x2F;edge-computing-explained&#x2F;&quot;&gt;expect 75%&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; of data to be processed outside of the traditional data center or cloud model by 2025.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-rise-of-edge-computing&quot;&gt;The rise of edge computing&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Computing needs to be pushed from centralized data centers to the edge to support the massive data consumption coupled to the rise of connected devices and emerging technologies. For instance, as more and more home appliances and devices are getting interconnected through the IoT economy, the amount of real-time data generated within our homes on a daily basis is rapidly expanding. Edge computing &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.i-scoop.eu&#x2F;edge-computing-explained&#x2F;&quot;&gt;tackles the shortcomings&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; of the centralized model in terms of bandwidth, latency and autonomy. It enables applications and solutions to be hosted closer to where their data is being produced and consumed, thereby allowing for low latencies, rapid data processing and real-time decisions. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The industry analyst company &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.idc.com&#x2F;getdoc.jsp?containerId=prUS48772522&quot;&gt;IDC estimates&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; the global spending on edge computing to increase by 14.8% compared to 2021 – amounting to roughly $176 billion in 2022. By 2025, this number is predicted to reach about $274 billion.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea of edge computing’s ability to process data on-site is simple enough. Nevertheless, edge computing fails to deliver on its promise as it still remains somewhat centralized today. Granted, so-called edge data centers are &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;stlpartners.com&#x2F;articles&#x2F;edge-computing&#x2F;edge-data-centres&#x2F;&quot;&gt;closer&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to where the data is being consumed than hyperscale data centers. But while they do provide an improvement from traditional data centers, they are not able to provide &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.thefastmode.com&#x2F;expert-opinion&#x2F;23002-what-are-various-types-of-edge-computing-that-exist-today&quot;&gt;far-edge&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; capabilities, i.e. moving as close to the user and point of data creation as possible. They are simply smaller types of data centers that are still operated in a centralized manner, require the &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;connectorsupplier.com&#x2F;how-the-rise-of-edge-computing-will-reshape-the-data-center-landscape&#x2F;&quot;&gt;same infrastructure elements&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; as centralized data centers, and usually &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.techtarget.com&#x2F;searchdatacenter&#x2F;definition&#x2F;edge-data-center&quot;&gt;rely&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on bigger, central data centers. Quite edgy isn’t it?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the need for Internet capacity – specifically at the edge – is rapidly intensifying, a new approach to Internet infrastructure is clearly needed. The Web 3 movement created a spur of interest across industries due to its promise to decentralize the Internet and cloud as we know it. Future data will be generated at the edge of the network and Internet which certainly requires an &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.forbes.com&#x2F;sites&#x2F;forbestechcouncil&#x2F;2022&#x2F;03&#x2F;25&#x2F;demystifying-edge-technology&#x2F;&quot;&gt;architectural shift&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; away from the current model.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;realizing-an-interconnected-future&quot;&gt;Realizing an interconnected future&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ironically, decades after the spark of the open-source peer-to-peer Internet movement was steamrolled by large tech companies and governments eager to centralize the global Internet, we seem to enter an era of decentralization again. There’s no doubt that large tech companies did bring a lot of innovation to our global Internet and cloud stack. Technically though, &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;p2p_web3&#x2F;&quot;&gt;peer-to-peer&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; systems have always been the most scalable option. Moreover, open-source architectures have built a strong reputation for providing high levels of security and flexibility. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a peer-to-peer model, people and devices are able to exchange directly, without intermediaries or servers in the middle – leading to a more energy-efficient, scalable and flexible paradigm that can expand on-demand. And undoubtedly, open-source will play a &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;news.crunchbase.com&#x2F;news&#x2F;edge-computing-said-quissal-zededa&#x2F;&quot;&gt;key role&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; in edge computing by simplifying and enhancing the building and deployment of software at the edge.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By leveraging open-source and peer-to-peer technologies, ThreeFold has come up with an Internet infrastructure that is capable of far-edge computing. ThreeFold offers a powerful set of &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;building_a_new_internet_from_the_ground_up_3&#x2F;&quot;&gt;compute primitives&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; that provide the agility to create and deploy containers, Virtual Machines (VMs) and &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;technology&#x2F;threefold__zkube?id=zkube&quot;&gt;Kubernetes&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; environments at the edge. Having integrated all leading industry-standard tools, ThreeFold’s solution allows for a seamless migration of any digital workload, making ThreeFold the ideal infrastructure for edge workloads. And all data produced by these workloads can be stored in a way that is ultra safe, highly reliable and &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;technology&#x2F;qsss&#x2F;threefold__qsss_home?id=quantum-safe-storage-system&quot;&gt;unbreakable&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Combined with end-to-end encrypted peer-to-peer &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;technology&#x2F;threefold__planetary_network?id=planetary-network&quot;&gt;networking&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, applications can be hosted closer to where the data is being consumed – representing the ideal underlying layer for IoT networks, blockchain-based workloads and more to run and scale at the edge seamlessly, efficiently and privately.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The shift towards the edge is inevitable. ThreeFold is the first full-stack, &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;coincheckup.com&#x2F;blog&#x2F;threefold-is-the-decentralized-web-the-future-of-the-internet&#x2F;&quot;&gt;decentralized&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, peer-to-peer Internet infrastructure in the world that combines compute in the form of highly-optimized containers, storage and network capacity in an all-in-one solution. With  more than &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;81 Petabytes&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; of capacity distributed across thousands of 3Nodes and 76 countries as well as &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;connecting_the_dots&#x2F;&quot;&gt;plans&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to sponsor the expansion of the Internet to developing regions, ThreeFold is the foundation for a thriving interconnected future that is secure, borderless and at the edge.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;what_is_farming&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Expand the new Internet&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; by setting up a 3Node at your home or office.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Help us &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;connecting_the_dots&#x2F;&quot;&gt;connect the dots&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and accelerate our far-edge capabilities.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Join our global &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefold&quot;&gt;movement&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; today.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>How ThreeFold Can Truly Decentralize Blockchain</title>
        <published>2021-10-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2021-10-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/decentralize-blockchain/"/>
        <id>https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/decentralize-blockchain/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/decentralize-blockchain/">&lt;p&gt;The topic of decentralization is commonly tied to blockchain and cryptocurrencies. Blockchain doesn’t store any of its information in a central location, rather it is copied and spread across a network of computers. And the most popular name in the blockchain space, Bitcoin, was intended as an alternative payment system free of central control.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But many blockchains are facing the same challenge: How can they escape the monopolies of centralized cloud providers for their own workloads, as well as for the dApps built on top of them? The key question is, is a blockchain truly decentralized if it is being hosted on a centralized solution? We say: no.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An example to illustrate this challenge is the fact that up to 60% of Ethereum (the world’s second most-popular blockchain) nodes run on centralized cloud providers and &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;aws.amazon.com&#x2F;blockchain&#x2F;&quot;&gt;25% of them run on Amazon Web Services (AWS)&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the topic is being addressed, it isn’t being solved at scale. The good news is that ThreeFold can play a large part in solving it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-should-blockchains-make-this-move&quot;&gt;Why should blockchains make this move?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The blockchain movement, as mentioned, is very heavily tied to the movement around decentralization. Cryptocurrencies represent the move away from centralized banks as the authorities and gatekeepers around money – just as ThreeFold and similar projects represent the move away from centralized clouds as the authorities and gatekeepers around data. The thing is, if blockchains are to rely on centralized cloud for hosting, they aren’t truly embodying decentralization.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understandably, many blockchains have chosen centralized cloud providers in the past because there wasn’t much of an alternative. But now, the Decentralized Cloud (DeCloud) movement has changed all of that.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is how some specific audiences can benefit:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;for-node-operators&quot;&gt;For Node Operators&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any full node or validator node can run on ThreeFold’s &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;cloud.threefold.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Peer-to-Peer (P2P) Cloud&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, making that particular Blockchain even more community-owned, and more decentralized from an IT&#x2F;cloud level. Any node operator can choose to run their nodes from any farmer location on the ThreeFold Grid, totally &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;what_is_peer_to_peer&#x2F;&quot;&gt;peer-to-peer&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; between the chosen farmer and the node operator. The deployed workloads are computed in a P2P manner, no middle party involved.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;for-dapp-developers&quot;&gt;For dApp Developers&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Web3&#x2F;Blockchain developers can use ThreeFold’s P2P Cloud - offering both compute and storage - to build and power their applications in a truly decentralized cloud infrastructure, both blockchain-native and cloud-native. A strong advantage here is that developers have the ability to leverage Kubernetes, Docker, S3, and other cloud-native tools (all compatible &#x2F; integrated with the ThreeFold) to power and optimize their data processing capabilities, as well as the overall functionality of their dApps. But the sweet spot is that it is deployed on a decentralized IT infrastructure, close to where users would be located.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;but-why-choose-threefold-over-other-decloud-projects&quot;&gt;But why choose ThreeFold over other DeCloud projects?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There may be bigger names in the space, but ThreeFold’s technology and offerings are much more comprehensive than the rest. ThreeFold provides decentralized storage, compute, and network all under one roof (whereas most other projects offer only one of the three) and as mentioned, we have created an environment for developers which is highly-compatible to the developer tools and solutions they use today. Further, ThreeFold is building new infrastructure &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;an_intro_to_the_threefold_grid&#x2F;&quot;&gt;from the ground up&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (rather than relying on extra space in data centers) and the technology is truly peer-to-peer.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We already have &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;partners&#x2F;blockchain&quot;&gt;a number of partners in the space&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; who recognize these advantages.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any blockchain protocol or dApp, whether operating DeFi, NFTs, DEXs, etc, will at some point need to leverage the power of the decentralized cloud and escape from centralized cloud providers. We’re seeing some of that adoption from a decentralized storage side with IPFS, which has been adopted by many dApps, and others – but as a developer, you will have to think twice, not just about where your&#x2F;your users’ data is being stored, but also about how (and where) your app is computed and powered.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Participate now in our quest to fully decentralize the Internet by &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;farm&quot;&gt;becoming a node&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on our grid or &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;tft&quot;&gt;buying TFT&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>A Smart Contract for all IT workloads</title>
        <published>2021-05-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2021-05-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/smart-contract-blog/"/>
        <id>https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/smart-contract-blog/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/smart-contract-blog/">&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold was inspired by the blockchain burst when it was created in 2016. After doing a comprehensive scan of the technological space we realized that Blockchain holds the best technology to store (1) Smart Contracts and (2) Transactions in an immutable way. We created our own blockchain database: Rivine to host the Smart Contract layer before switching to the Parity Substrate of Polkadot and our Transactional blockchain to the Stellar Network.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
While we use blockchain technology, ThreeFold is much more than just “a blockchain project” as we apply many more revolutionary technologies. We decided to use Parity Substrate as we don’t see the need to create something if there’s already great technologies out there that we can already use. Today we’re proud of our Smart Contract for IT layer and approach the ThreeFold Grid v3.0 release this year which will expose its full potential to interact with the primitives of the grid.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;so-what-is-this-smart-contract-for-it-about&quot;&gt;So what is this Smart Contract for IT about?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Smart Contract for IT allows you, your company or your community to execute the storage and running of your files and applications securely with consensus and automatic billing. You could compare it as a fingerprint check and your data would be accessible only if presenting your private key (fingerprint). Let’s maybe go through the process for a better idea of how this works.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The smart contracts are like recipes for chefs to cook exactly what you want. In that sense they need to be very accurate and as descriptive as possible to deliver what you need. In the case of ThreeFold, the smart contracts would define different sets of Internet resources you would need to store files, run applications, or communicate across the network.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Whenever you want to reserve more resources to store your latest album or run your applications, you will define the resources you need to your 3Bot or Digital Twin (your personal virtual system administrators) which will then look at different smart contracts that are available and choose the most appropriate package. For e.g. Reserve 3 PB of Storage in Switzerland across 7 nodes.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Following that, your 3Bot or Digital Twin will create and register the smart contract in the blockchain database in a few seconds, providing you with all your specific needs. It will also store and secure some instructions to the BCDB for the nodes to meet smart contract completion.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
ThreeFold had to make sure that user data would remain ultra-secure. Inspired by storage and communication algorithms used in space, we integrated it between the Smart Contract layer and Zero OS. The algorithm splits data into unrecognizable ‘slices’ that are distributed via network connections to different nodes locally or across the world, and that can be reconstructed only with your fingerprint.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;more-than-the-average-smart-contract&quot;&gt;More than the average Smart Contract&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Via your Smart Contract for IT, you can also define a consensus mechanism and create multi-signatures for smart contract execution or completion to deliver appropriate digital services in for example work related activities.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The beauty of the Smart Contract for IT is that it can work with thousands of connected nodes for the proper execution of any digital requirements on the infrastructure, verify if consensus was reached or not, download the right files to execute the smart contract and verify them, make sure that no hacker or outsider can ever gain access or influence its execution and more.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
If you want to learn more about ThreeFold’s Smart Contract for IT, read more &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold&#x2F;#&#x2F;internet4__smartcontract_it&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>A Scalable and Secure Operating System</title>
        <published>2021-05-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2021-05-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://dev.threefold.io/blog/zero-os-blog/"/>
        <id>https://dev.threefold.io/blog/zero-os-blog/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://dev.threefold.io/blog/zero-os-blog/">&lt;p&gt;Just like a brain is an interconnected network of neurons, the Internet (or internet) is a global interconnected network of computers and devices that communicate with each other via the &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Internet_protocol_suite&quot;&gt;Internet protocol suite&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (TCP&#x2F;IP). The communications infrastructure of the Internet consists of hardware components and a system of software layers that control various aspects of the architecture.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
To create a new Internet from scratch, ThreeFold had to start at the operating system (OS) level. An operating system is a software that manages computer hardware, software resources, and provides common services for computer programs. And this is how Zero OS was born&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-makes-zero-os-special&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#what-makes-zero-os-special&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: what-makes-zero-os-special&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;What makes Zero OS special?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zero OS is a stateless and lightweight operating system. Given it has no shell, remote or server interface, it is much safer than the big majority of the OSs on the market. When storing your data on Zero OS, it is fingerprinted and made available only when requested by you or those you provide access to.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The state of an application represents its state of being in a given moment in time. Think of a stateless transaction as vending machines, a single request and a response. In ThreeFold’s Internet infrastructure, this can be represented as data being accessible only when requested.
The only way to access data on Zero OS is via the private key (or fingerprint) of a user. In that sense, the data is not accessible unless the data owner requests access to it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-does-zero-os-apply-to-developers&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#how-does-zero-os-apply-to-developers&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: how-does-zero-os-apply-to-developers&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;How does Zero OS apply to developers?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to its lightweight architecture, Zero OS is a perfect fit to run microservice architectures and emerging IT workloads such as IoT, Blockchains, Big Data, and more. A key benefit of microservice architecture is the freedom it offers you to choose the best runtime for the task at hand.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Let’s take the example of decentralizing service-oriented developing teams. A common challenge there is that most of the time they don’t really understand the applications they are exposing. But no one knows the data infrastructure of the applications better than those who craft them.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
ThreeFold permits decentralized developer teams with the ability to share keys (access) to the developing environment on Zero OS and the gateways to the world wide web within the secure peer-to-peer overlay network. This is game changing. Also with all the automation frameworks provided, it creates the perfect environment to develop current and emerging technologies.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Put shortly, decentralized development and integration is now officially an organizational or cultural change, not a technical one anymore.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;zero-os-allows-anyone-to-provide-sovereign-capacity&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#zero-os-allows-anyone-to-provide-sovereign-capacity&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: zero-os-allows-anyone-to-provide-sovereign-capacity&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;Zero OS allows anyone to provide sovereign capacity&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given stateless systems separate the OS configuration and user data, Zero OS simplifies the  maintenance and the deployment of digital workloads, while making it impossible to hack into user data on a hardware level.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
3Nodes provide all the storage, compute and network primitives for a new internet infrastructure. Given they are booted with Zero OS, anyone can now participate in the Internet economy without jeopardizing user data sovereignty and security.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Conclusively, Zero OS is ultra secure, perfect to develop current and future technologies, and enables anyone to take part in the planet positive and data sovereign Internet brought by ThreeFold.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Learn more about Zero OS and the grid primitives &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;manual.grid.tf&#x2F;knowledge_base&#x2F;technology&#x2F;concepts&#x2F;zos.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Zero People IT is the Future</title>
        <published>2020-08-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2020-08-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/zero-people-it-is-the-future/"/>
        <id>https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/zero-people-it-is-the-future/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/zero-people-it-is-the-future/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;Introduction&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-cost-of-complexity-in-traditional-it&quot;&gt;The “cost” of complexity in traditional IT&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Classic IT infrastructure setup is complex and is not cost-effective. Applications need a specific environment to operate in, built by integrating different technology components from different vendors. Elements of such a setup are operating systems, storage systems, networks, security systems, authentication systems, and more.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Putting components together is called (system) integration, and integration requires agreement on how these components will fit together and the knowledge to do it.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
This complexity and need for integration originate from the way the IT industry historically developed. With time more and more layers appeared to bring new possibilities. Additional layers masked existing problems. Instead of fixing the underlying issues, several third parties needed to be involved, adding complexity and increased costs (such as license costs, upgrades, updates, etc.). Complexity has become a business model.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;where-can-we-get-inspiration-to-do-it-a-different-way&quot;&gt;Where can we get inspiration to do it a different way?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What if we could build IT architectures in a different way.  What if we would not accept component solution approaches anymore and start over with a completely blank sheet of paper?  Would we then come up with a different way of actually building automation, architectures, and business models?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;looking-at-nature-for-inspiration&quot;&gt;Looking at nature for inspiration&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s start by looking for inspiration in nature. Suppose we consider IT systems to be a complex system. Are there parallels that we can draw between systems that exist in nature (and have evolved and improved over thousands of years) and those within the IT industry?
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
In nature, we see two kinds of systems (societies): centralized and decentralized systems.  Examples of centralized systems are herds, groups, or schools of animals living together where there is a hierarchy in the way they organize themselves. For decentralized systems, we can look at beehives and anthills.  Organizing efforts and benefits are distinct and come at a different cost.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;centralized-systems-in-nature&quot;&gt;Centralized systems in nature&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In centralized systems, there is governance of activities, wealth positions, and so forth.  Think of a group of lions or chimpanzees.  There is always an alpha male who is dominant in the whole group.  He is the only that enjoys all of the benefits because the entire group&#x2F;structure works towards his wishes.  He gets to mate with most female group members because the system believes that he has the strongest genes to help the group to survive in the future. The dominant male also gets most of the food gathered by the group, and if he doesn’t get it, he will claim it by showing his dominance and fight for it.  All the others are working towards this alpha male, and all the other males in the group will occasionally challenge the alpha male for dominance.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
This is very similar to how the IT industry has been operating to date:  there are a few alpha males in the industry - one for each sector that can be recognized (for example, in the Cloud Industry, you have Amazon, Google, Microsoft, and on the system integration front you have Dell, Siemens, CA Technologies).  They end up with the majority of businesses available in their specific markets. When challenged by new companies, they fight them (in every way possible, including killing them or acquiring them). And in analogy to the animal group, these alpha male companies have a lot of organizations that work with them, usually called “partners” or “channels.”&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;decentralized-systems-in-nature&quot;&gt;Decentralized systems in nature&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For decentralized systems on &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Decentralised_system&quot;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, we learn; “One of the most well-known examples of a “natural” decentralized system is one used by insect colonies such as Ants. In these insect colonies, control is distributed among the biological agents who act upon local information and local interactions to create complex and universal behavior collectively. While individually exhibiting simple behaviors, these agents achieve universal goals such as feeding the colony or raising the brood using dynamical mechanisms like non-explicit communication and exploiting their closely coupled action and perception systems. Without any form of central authority, these insect colonies achieve their universal goals by performing required tasks and by responding to changing conditions in their external environment. They also adjust the number of workers performing each task to ensure the completion of all tasks. For example, ant colonies guide their global behavior (in terms of foraging, patrolling, brood care, and nest maintenance) using a pulsing, shifting web of Spatio-temporal patterned interactions that rely on antennal contact rate and olfactory sensing. While these interactions consist of both interactions with the environment and each other, ants do not direct the behavior of other ants. They thus never have a “central controller” dictating what is to be done to achieve global goals.“
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
So nature has provided us with solid examples of centralized and decentralized systems.  For much of what works in the modern world, we have ended up using the centralized model governing enterprises and countries.  Various industries have also adopted the centralized model where there is a pyramid structure, and everything works towards the alpha males.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-different-approach-to-creating-and-operating-it-workloads&quot;&gt;A different approach to creating and operating IT workloads&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What if we can develop a new concept for creating, deploying, and operating IT workloads.  What if we say goodbye to the centralized way of controlling IT workloads.  Can we develop an idea that works in a decentralized way?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-concept&quot;&gt;The concept&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To build this concept, we will draw the use of the human way of operating a large ship. The crew of a vessel has different roles, which we will call the &lt;em&gt;coordinators&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;. Some of these coordinators could be a captain, officers, engineers, and oilers.  These coordinators have in-depth knowledge of their specific tasks but usually lack a detailed understanding of the other roles. In the “hive” of a ship, the specific requests to get tasks done are sent to coordinators who will receive, interpret, execute their particular tasks, and report the (non-) progress of these tasks or subtasks.  For example, the captain will create and agree to a schedule of maintenance tasks for the engine room. These are daily, weekly and monthly tasks that should be completed by the engineers and oilers. The engineers and oilers do not get continuous input from the captain. They get one instruction to follow the schedule and know what needs to be done for every task. The intermediate state (what is complete and what still needs to be addressed) is stored by the coordinators executing the tasks. This is the most efficient way of accomplishing tasks.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;jumping-to-the-it-industry&quot;&gt;Jumping to the IT industry&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we bring this concept to the IT world, we conclude that today’s IT systems are built in a significantly different way.  Most architectures (if not all) have a central facility that stores &lt;em&gt;all&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; information and &lt;em&gt;all&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; states of activity in a so-called central ‘database.’ A general norm within IT. However, these types of architectures are inefficient and are very complex - like the ship analogy -  a central command room (database) is created where every coordinator needs to report back. (1) The current level of activity, (2) the completion (state) of tasks, (3) the proper understanding of upcoming tasks by the coordinator to accomplish tasks in-progress or future - hence leading to the undesirable outcome of complexity due to centralization.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
In the ship example, we deem this type of functioning&#x2F;workflow inefficient; however, in the IT world, it is a common way of doing it.  Furthermore, IT infrastructures usually have different databases to store “state” in different parts of the IT architecture.  The analogy would translate to different command rooms that orchestrate different functions on the ship in our ship. This, in turn, introduces the need for another role in starting coordinating between the different command rooms to ensure that all information is shared and communicated. Taking this pattern forward leads to an endless loop of adding interfaces, layers, bridges between different parts of the system that all store information, multiple times, and in different ways.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;datastores&quot;&gt;Datastores&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By design, a decentralized IT  architecture should not use centralized data storage (databases) for multiple tasks (roles). It instead should feature a similar approach to the way of functioning as in the ‘ship’ example. In this architecture,  roles get short and precise instructions of the jobs to be completed and autonomously execute.  We call these execution engines &lt;em&gt;coordinators&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;.  Coordinators receive instructions, run on instructions and store all information about the current task &lt;em&gt;locally.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;  They store all the relevant information in a local storage facility (available to the individual coordinators only) and provide information about the state of execution if and when other coordinators ask for a state update.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;magical-coordinator&quot;&gt;Magical Coordinator&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;requirements-to-let-actor-based-management-work&quot;&gt;Requirements to let actor based management work&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
* Less complexity
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;State only with the actor itself (no-where else !!!)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understood language between actors&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Process = recipes of a cook, NOT IN A DB
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;actor-based-it-solutions&quot;&gt;Actor based IT solutions&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To simplify common IT architectures, we should look at a   new way of creating such a system that takes the current standards into account:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No people involved in integrating different components into a single solution&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Which, as a consequence, means no revenue generation based on creating and managing complexity.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No central state &#x2F; operational data storage&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Individual automated actors with specific knowledge for specific tasks&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Independent operating actors completing specific tasks
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Such a system should ideally be owned by many (not just a single organization, bringing centralization back into the equations) that operate IT tasks for many.  We have not seen such a system in existence, but we are as TFTech building and rolling out technology that can do this.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
We believe that IT’s future is in decentralization where specific coordinators (bots) will roam a network of capacity looking for a task to do, making themselves available where needed, creating more of them when the system grows, and allowing the global population to deploy and operate IT workloads.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>ThreeFold&#x27;s Long Story Short</title>
        <published>2020-05-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2020-05-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/how-it-works/"/>
        <id>https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/how-it-works/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/how-it-works/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;so-threefold-is-building-a-new-internet-why&quot;&gt;So, ThreeFold is building a new internet. Why?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We strongly believe that a new internet is needed for our planet and for humanity. “If not now, when? If not us, who?”
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
What it boils down to is that currently the internet is only available to about 1&#x2F;2 of the world (meaning billions are being left behind), it is centralized (a handful of large corporations own and profit off of our data), and it uses up to 10% of the world’s energy consumption. So, we’re building a new (peer-to-peer) internet that empowers equality (access), autonomy (data ownership, for example), and sustainability (reduces energy consumption). These values drive us forward.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-does-it-work&quot;&gt;How does it work?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything on the internet – websites, apps, photos, videos, etc – uses up capacity and is stored in huge data centers owned by big companies, mainly in North America, Europe, and some in Asia. In our solution, centralized data centers are replaced with a grid of “nodes” distributed around the world.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
These nodes are owned by &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold&#x2F;#&#x2F;what_is_farming&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Farmers&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; – but only the physical hardware – the data inside of the nodes belongs to the people or organizations who put it there. So, “farmers” plug in hardware and start to create capacity that can be used by people.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Farmers come in all shapes and sizes. Some farmers run small data centers while others simply run a node out of their living room.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
When Farmers connect active hardware (add capacity) to the ThreeFold Grid, ThreeFold Tokens are created. Farmers can then sell those tokens to people who want to use capacity (e.g. a developer that wants to build or host a website, or a person who wants to store some photos). More on tokens down below.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;seems-quite-lofty-how-will-you-build-it&quot;&gt;Seems quite lofty. How will you build it?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s true that rebuilding the internet is not so simple. But a lot of infrastructure has already been built and the technology is quite advanced. Over the past 2+ years (as of May 2020), independent ThreeFold Farmers have already plugged in more than 40,000,000 GigaBytes worth of storage and 15,000 CPU Cores across 21+ countries. That might not mean a lot to non-technical folks but it is quite a significant amount.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;21-countries-what-happened-to-equality&quot;&gt;21+ countries? What happened to equality?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As far along as we are, we still have work to do. One of our biggest goals in the near future is to expand the grid to Africa, South America, and parts of Asia where currently the Internet is too expensive or not available. Currently, we farming is incentivized around these key geographies.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;and-what-do-you-mean-by-peer-to-peer&quot;&gt;And what do you mean by peer-to-peer?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peer-to-peer means no middlemen – direct exchange of information and&#x2F;or value between equal participants. Peer-to-peer means decentralization – breaking away from pyramid-based systems, greed-based systems – and putting &lt;strong&gt;people&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; back in the center of their own (digital) lives.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;so-how-can-i-access-use-your-internet-today-what-can-i-do-on-it&quot;&gt;So how can I access &#x2F; use your internet today? What can I do on it?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By June, some of the first experiences will be live. This includes file storage and communication tools and a virtual browser, all with the advantages of being more sustainable for our planet and with full control of your own data. And over time, more and more experiences will come to this internet. We’ll be updating here and on our communication platforms as they come. But don’t worry, as a user it doesn’t change much – no coding required. :)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;will-enter-website-or-app-here-be-available-on-your-internet&quot;&gt;Will [enter website or app here] be available on your internet?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are some tremendous reasons for a website or app to use our internet, but that will really be up to the website or the app. In the end, we are providing a responsible solution for responsible people and organizations. We would love to host anybody who believes in what we are doing!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-are-you-making-sure-it-s-safe&quot;&gt;How are you making sure it’s safe?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hacking has become a part of life and is almost impossible to avoid in the current systems – they are too complex and require too many people to operate. This results in less security which results in lots of security breaches. We took a look at the existing Internet (seven layers) and simplified it down to three layers. By simplifying the architecture and instead creating technology that is self-driving &amp;amp; self-healing, we removed the human requirement and therefore vastly minimized the possibility for hacking or human error. Then we also developed a storage algorithm which makes it such that if some of the information gets lost or stolen (somehow) or if some hardware goes down, it is all retrievable. Long story short, we flipped the existing system on its head.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-about-the-data-ownership-part&quot;&gt;What about the data ownership part?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That has a bit to do with the security as well. Since you own your data, you decide who gets access. Which means your data isn’t just out “there” for the taking. Basically, we put you at the center of your digital life, where the applications and experiences you use serve you, not the other way around.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;and-how-is-it-better-for-the-planet&quot;&gt;And how is it better for the planet?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a few reasons for us being more sustainable. Data centers are super unsustainable, so the simple (but incomplete) answer is “no more huge data centers.” But if you want more detail:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We use up to 3x less hardware for the same output, and using hardware at least 2x longer while maintaining good performance&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Having capacity everywhere, local to where users are – this reduces network requirements (and can even improve security)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using new algorithms (e.g. the one mentioned above for storage) which have dramatic efficiency improvement&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Re-using hardware where possible – let’s not throw away&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-much-will-it-cost&quot;&gt;How much will it cost?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end we want to provide sustainable access to the internet and all of its solutions for less than a dollar per month per person but for now the cost will depend on what you choose to do. Certain experiences will cost money. Storing photos or videos, for example. But all at a fair price.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;speaking-of-money-so-what-s-up-with-the-threefold-token&quot;&gt;Speaking of money – so what’s up with the ThreeFold Token?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we mentioned above, tokens are generated when ThreeFold Farmers adds capacity to the ThreeFold Grid.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Essentially, the ThreeFold Token is the medium of exchange on the new internet. So, if a developer wants to build something (e.g. a website or an app) or a user wants to store something (e.g. photos), he&#x2F;she&#x2F;they use(s) ThreeFold Tokens.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;need-more-answers&quot;&gt;Need more answers?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We hope that helps explains things. Obviously there is &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold&#x2F;#&#x2F;&quot;&gt;a whole wiki&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to dive in to. If you don’t find what you’re looking for, please ask us on our &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&quot;&gt;forum&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;!
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Photo by Nong Vang on &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;unsplash.com&#x2F;photos&#x2F;9pw4TKvT3po&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Use cases for the ThreeFold Peer-to-Peer Cloud</title>
        <published>2018-09-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2018-09-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/new-edge-cloud/"/>
        <id>https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/new-edge-cloud/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/new-edge-cloud/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;use-cases-for-the-threefold-peer-to-peer-cloud&quot;&gt;Use cases for the ThreeFold Peer-to-Peer Cloud&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;any-docker-service&quot;&gt;Any Docker Service&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold nodes natively run containers - therefore they can run any Docker service.  But it does so in a more efficient way than the current Docker engine - the most used and known container technology platform in the world.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;iaas&quot;&gt;IAAS&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ThreeFold node technology enables hardware capabilities to be used for IAAS services in a very efficient way.  Overhead is reduced to a minimum by stripping out unnecessary layers of software that have been implemented over the last decade to patch scaling and performance problems. Our engineers have always looked at the root cause of issues and by innovating at the core algorithm level, solved many issues.
Examples are:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Less is more&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Scale down the operating system for a virtualization architecture to a minimum and boot it over the network - no local operating system files installed on local storage.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Look at root causes, no painkiller approach&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Step away from existing storage solutions that require proprietary acceleration hardware and use standard off the shelf, affordable and efficient components with a 100% software-based storage solution that can withstand hardware failures without requiring human intervention - creating a very efficient, reliable and performing storage solution that can operate standalone.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The platform is secured by using a network boot mechanism that makes it virtually hack resistant as there are no operating system files installed locally. Infrastructure as a service traditionally runs in hyper-scale data centers, remote from the businesses using it. ThreeFold node technology allows you to install, operate and run IAAS services close to your business locations operated by your local IT team.  It operates on a peer-to-peer network - only transferring bits of data that need to be transported to avoid network congestion and traffic bottlenecks.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;archive&quot;&gt;Archive&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data generation is growing exponentially. More data has been generated in the last 2 years than ever before. This creates a big need to archive data. The ThreeFold node technology creates storage and archiving capabilities by using standard hardware and known interfaces (S3, FTP, WebDav, CIFS, and NFS) will be built by developers worldwide and made available.  The low-level storage functionality supports version controlling of the archived data, which keeps all relevant changes without any limitation by using a small amount of actual storage capacity.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;security&quot;&gt;Security&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data security and reliability are key aspects of any storage system.  The ThreeFold node allows all data to be compressed and encrypted if and when needed. The distributed character of the storage system enables site redundant storage algorithms to be deployed while keeping large data volumes from being stored in a single location. This removes the risk of data being stolen (physically) and prevents a site outage to result in data outage.  The distributed character of the system is in line with the increasing spread of actual data generation.  ThreeFold has sensory equipment everywhere these days, and the overhead of storing all that information in a few central places is enormous. Data collection and storage happens once - reading data to use it for a particular workload happens many times.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;data-mining&quot;&gt;Data Mining&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On traditional server architectures, every application has to set up its servers that run their code in isolated silos, making sharing of data hard. The distributed character of the ThreeFold node technology presents compute and storage capacity everywhere.  This enables large data mining workloads to happen close to the source of the data.  By storing data in a distributed manner, mining can be distributed as well. Distributed compute capacity next to storage capabilities creates the possibility to create data mining operations on local storage (which makes it very fast and efficient) by coding data mining algorithms in programming languages (such as Python, Lua, Javascript, and Golang). Data mining follows distributed data storage.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Never run into scalability problems again with the ThreeFold node. Data storage can expand horizontally using thousands of distributed nodes to create large storage volumes.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;smart-contracts&quot;&gt;Smart Contracts&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smart contracts are applications that run on a decentralized platform, exactly as programmed without any possibility of downtime, censorship, fraud, or third-party interference. These applications run on a blockchain, a powerful shared global infrastructure that can move value around and represent the ownership of that value. Smart contracts enable developers to create markets, store registries of debts (or promises), move funds following past instructions (like a will or a futures contract), and many other things without a middleman or counterparty risk.  ThreeFold nodes run based on smart-contracts.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;self-learning-and-ai&quot;&gt;Self-Learning and AI&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blockchains can be seen as databases. By current database standards, traditional blockchains like Bitcoin are terrible: low throughout, low capacity, high latency, poor query support, and so on. But even with these terrible characteristics, blockchains introduced three new and important characteristics:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Decentralized data and shared data control&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;  leads to more data and better qualitative data which results in better models. Shortening the machine learning time also enables AI to progress at a faster pace.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Immutable audit trails&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; improve the trustworthiness of the data, and improves the models’ provenance on training and testing results.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Native assets&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; and assets exchanges make training and testing models intellectual property (IP) assets easier - enhancing decentralized data and model exchanges.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Blockchain technology allows more and better quality data to be presented to machine learning algorithms.  It has been proven (Microsoft researchers - Banko and Brill) that more data — not just a bit more data but way more data — while using the same algorithms results in a lot better machine learning.  Meaning that the future of machine learning is not in trying to create more sophisticated algorithms (which will happen). So by moving AI learning into a blockchain environment we speed up machine learning and in the end create AI.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Edge Cloud, not Grid Cloud</title>
        <published>2018-08-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2018-08-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/edge-cloud-not-grid-cloud/"/>
        <id>https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/edge-cloud-not-grid-cloud/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/edge-cloud-not-grid-cloud/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;edge-cloud-not-grid-cloud&quot;&gt;Edge Cloud, not Grid Cloud?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The term Edge Cloud or, to be more precise, Edge Computing is one of the most exciting technology terms of these days.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;750&quot; height=&quot;421&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;embed&#x2F;7uA9aoIfMZo&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;aautoplay; encrypted-media;&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;&#x2F;iframe&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;edge-computing-definition&quot;&gt;Edge Computing Definition&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Wikipedia, “&lt;strong&gt;Edge computing&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; is a distributed computing paradigm in which computation is largely or entirely performed on distributed device nodes known as smart devices or edge devices as opposed to primarily taking place in a centralized cloud environment.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In summary, this means that the cloud is divided into smaller pieces and distributed to the edge of the network.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;drivers-for-edge-computing&quot;&gt;Drivers for Edge Computing&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some latency-sensitive applications require fast response times to work correctly. A good example is self-driving cars. A lot of decisions in autonomous vehicles have to be made instantaneously; the decision to react to the unexpected while driving at high speed cannot afford to be slowed down by data traveling long distances to be processed. To improve the system’s reliability, additional hops, and any further points of failure must be eliminated. Moving to compute as far out as possible to the Edge is the logical choice.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More generically, real-world situations are increasingly relying on an IT component to be involved in some form of decision making where time is of the essence.  The current IT setup is that we have highly concentrated IT setups in data centers connected by fast networks to the rest of the world. This setup is rapidly becoming obsolete as we need to have the fastest possible response for everyday activities, which cannot sustain the time delay caused by (extended) network connections.  Having actual data processing and storage facilities close to these real-world situations is the next IT capacity evolution.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These thousands of situations are mostly in the IoT area. Still, other killer applications like streaming would greatly benefit from being served from the Edge rather than a distant central location.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;edge-computing-market-facts&quot;&gt;Edge Computing Market Facts&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to the billions of IoT devices driven by various use cases like autonomous driving,  a massive demand for Edge Computing is evolving rapidly. According to the Digital Journal, the Edge Computing market is growing extremely fast. With a  CAGR of over 35.0% and the market is expected to reach  USD 33.75 billion by the end of 2023.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Source: &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.digitaljournal.com&#x2F;pr&#x2F;3394129&quot;&gt;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.digitaljournal.com&#x2F;pr&#x2F;3394129&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Edge Computing and Grid Computing are often used in the same context and sometimes are confused. For this article, we’d like to define the terms going forward as follows:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Grid Computing means a computer network of 100% distributed computer resources like processing power, memory, and data storage of similar or different types to which authorized people can run their computation workloads. That means that Grid Compute nodes are mostly in data centers and maybe dispersed over more extensive regions but are typically still far from the Edge. Compared to Edge Computing,  Grid Computing environments are owned by more than one individual or company, and thus, controlled by many.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Edge computing has risen from a need to have data processing and storage as close as possible to real-world situations.  The situation could be as simple as recording biometric data by a smartwatch to support the required information for a self-driving car to function as intended.  The necessity comes from having local computing and storage capacity - it can be used by multiple use cases (situations) but does not have to.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-benefits-of-edge-computing&quot;&gt;The Benefits of Edge Computing&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edge computing comes with specific benefits that are mandatory for the next evolution in the IT industry.  We have optimized the central model to such a degree that the network connects the central capacity to use cases in the field, the next bottleneck.  Edge computing is solving several challenges faced by real-world situations with the following benefits:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;speed&quot;&gt;Speed&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Speed&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; is probably the most crucial benefit of edge computing, as there are plenty of use cases that require near-real-time computing.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;scalability&quot;&gt;Scalability&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The scalability of edge computing also makes it incredibly &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.vxchnge.com&#x2F;blog&#x2F;edge-computing-use-cases&quot;&gt;versatile&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. By partnering with local data centers further out on the Edge, companies can easily target desirable markets without investing in expensive infrastructure expansion. Edge data centers allow them to service end-users efficiently with little physical distance or latency. They also do not constrain companies with a substantial footprint, allowing them to shift to other markets rapidly should economic conditions change.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;availability-and-security&quot;&gt;Availability and Security&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Traditional cloud computing architecture is, by definition, centralized, which makes it especially vulnerable to &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.vxchnge.com&#x2F;blog&#x2F;how-to-protect-data-centers-from-a-new-generation-of-ddos-attacks&quot;&gt;distributed denial of service (DDoS)&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; attacks and power outages. Edge computing distributes processing, storage, and applications across a wide range of devices, nodes and data centers, which makes it difficult for any single disruption to take down the network which is why logically and geographically dispersed systems are often used for DDoS mitigation like in Content Delivery Networks (CDN)
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
By pushing everything to the cloud, you’re leaving your business open to ISP failures and cloud server downtime. Many mission-critical operations like railroads and chemical plants won’t even use the cloud today. Their server farms are the only way to guarantee uptime.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;process-optimisation&quot;&gt;Process optimisation&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another big benefit is process optimization. If self-driving cars were to use the cloud instead of the Edge, they’d be pushing all the data they gather up to the cloud. But if the Edge makes local decisions, the cloud may not need all that data immediately – or even at all.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;requirements-for-edge-computing&quot;&gt;Requirements for Edge Computing&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When compute and storage capabilities exist on the Edge, we need to overcome several challenges around capacity distribution.  Most traditional IT technologies do not allow this as they live in large data centers where there is a lot of “care” for these technologies.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The most significant generic hurdle to overcome is that there is going to be a lot less “care” for the technology to rely on at the Edge.  These “devices” have to be self-sufficient to no small degree.  If we want to sum up some of the specifics of edge technology, this will come out:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A typical edge device or node must run an OS that comes in at a low cost or, ideally, for free like some open source offerings. This enhances the proliferation of capacity at the Edge.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Container technology must be embedded in the OS at the lowest possible level to create the maximum benefit of efficiency from the edge hardware: classic Virtual Machine environments are just too inefficient and resource consuming for edge use cases. There will be Virtual Machine based edge solutions, but these are going to be out there for a certain period, catering for current IT workloads to move to the Edge.  The Edge’s correct move can only happen when traditional IT applications split up into pieces and require a lot less capacity to run.  Hence, it will convert over time to containerized technology.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Edge Computing hardware will consist of datacenter grade hardware and all sorts of other types of hardware.  The Edge might include some smaller sized data center facilities but also include different types of “homes” for compute and storage equipment.  Think of transportation as a specific use case - capacity on maritime vessels, capacity on trains, and vehicles’ capacity.  Hardware will have to accommodate different use cases,  price levels, form factors, and power consumption.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Edge hardware needs a lightweight OS that is very close to the hardware components to get the maximum out of compute and storage capacity.  Less is more - for real Edge capacity, local people won’t be able to interact with edge capacity - one further step - there will be no need to have remote people access these devices for maintenance purposes.  The ultimate edge computing solution will have a significant amount of self-sustainability - where there are no more highly technically skilled people required to keep the capacity available, up and running.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In most cases, Edge means being remote, and having no access to humans or humans are only too expensive for the specific use case.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Power outages or no network availability will cause system failures. The ideal OS to deal with this revolves around no people; the zero-touch approach should be stateless and needs to have self-healing capabilities run by automation software robots.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;existing-edge-computing-solutions&quot;&gt;Existing Edge Computing Solutions&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today there are a few Edge Computing platforms out there that cover some requirements as outlined above.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Microsoft, for instance, launched products like Azure IoT Edge and Azure Data Box Edge to extend their Datacenter based Azure cloud offering to the Edge.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Another attempt to bring centralized cloud technology to the Edge is the Openstack Edge Computing initiative, which is in the concept phase only so far.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A new OS for the Edge is CoreOs, also known as Container Linux, which runs on nearly any platform, whether physical, virtual, or private&#x2F;public cloud.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More recently, there are a few blockchain-driven technologies out there pushing for edge capacity to exist.  Examples are:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;sia.tech&#x2F;&quot;&gt;SIA&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;sonm.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Sonm&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;filecoin.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Filecoin&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Content delivery networks with a lot of “capacity” sitting close to end-users are expanding their capabilities beyond content delivery
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.limelight.com&#x2F;products&#x2F;iot-and-edge-cloud&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Limelight&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.akamai.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Akamai&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-holy-grail&quot;&gt;The Holy Grail&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The holy grail would be a self-healing Edge Grid. Edge, because of all the benefits Edge Computing brings to the user: Speed, Scalability, Reliability, Security, Versatility, and Process Optimization. Grid, because it fulfills the distributed workload requirements, a classic centralized cloud would generally be used without a centralized nature and all its disadvantages.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Probably the most critical part of the ideal solution is self-healing. The biggest challenge of an Edge Computing environment is the dependency on local care: humans to maintain hardware and upgrade or fix software components. Self Healing needs to do the job here, which means zero people can be involved.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Only a self-healing mechanism with zero-people involved, completely decentralized, brings down the cost and provides more security to the environment, and makes it highly scalable.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Some of you may think that new blockchain-based technologies may be the holy grail. But they are not.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
In most cases, their implementations are too slow, and that’s why it does not make sense to use them for production purposes. Another downside is the complexity of the application caused by stitching together 3rd party technologies. In many cases, these blockchain-based technologies are at a very early stage with beta implementations or even roadmap only type of technology.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The holy grail is something that hasn’t been created before; it needs to be a versatile system that is self-manageable.  A large global conglomerate should not own the capacity - it should be owned by many. Therefore, it should have a commercial model where people individually can decide to partake in building this global edge solution and where there is a defined return on investment for those partakers.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
A few groups of people, like us, are creating decentralized solutions for this, owned by the many, and creating services for all.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>A new approach to the Internet Architecture</title>
        <published>2018-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2018-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/tech-new-internet/"/>
        <id>https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/tech-new-internet/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/tech-new-internet/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;threefold-s-technology-does-not-follow-the-traditional-it-model&quot;&gt;ThreeFold’s technology does not follow the traditional IT model&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Edge internet needs a different approach. So, we started from scratch and shaped a new approach. ThreeFold’s open-source technology addresses the scalability, security, storage, energy, and operating issues by simplifying architectures and not relying on third-party software. This drives down costs and improves efficiencies.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-threefold-s-technology-toolbox&quot;&gt;What is ThreeFold’s Technology Toolbox?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold’s technology is based on three primary building blocks:  Stateless Computing, Self-Healing Technology, and Blockchain technology - this is the core of our “Technology Toolbox“.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stateless Computing&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: a stateless operating system, Zero-OS, enabling distributed hardware to form an Edge Internet grid generating IT storage and compute capacity&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Self-Healing Technology&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: controls and operates a distributed cloud and reserves, procures, and executes workloads on the grid using our Jumpscale platform. It delivers autoscaling and automation frameworks that enable self-healing and can be adapted for any kind of IT workload.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Blockchain Technology&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Via Rivine - our secure, scalable “proof of stake” blockchain, along with our identity management platform, ItsYou.online. Our blockchain technology enables user authentication, access controls, secure workloads, and heightened security.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;enabling-stateless-computing&quot;&gt;Enabling Stateless Computing&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The global decentralized internet will be composed of thousands (millions?) of nodes distributed geographically.  This means the decentralized internet must be powered by a stateless operating system that can be booted via the Internet (as opposed to living on the node locally). This removes the complexity of upgrades, truck rolls, etc.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Open-source components have been developed, Zero-OS, for the deployment of bare metal machines functioning as Internet nodes and application hosts.  Our Zero-OS platform runs containerized applications and software code on secure and distributed IT infrastructure.  Zero-OS can be deployed on off-the-shelf hardware by anyone willing to make server and storage capacity available in their markets and within our network.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-benefits-of-stateless-computing-are-substantial-including&quot;&gt;The benefits of Stateless Computing are substantial, including:&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Performance&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: lightweight OS without overhead for running bare-metal machines.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Free&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: finds the optimal performance of server &amp;amp; storage nodes at no cost.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Private&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: no data footprint remains while workloads move from one node to another.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Distributed&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: capacity is generated without the need for data centers: At The Edge.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;High-available&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: easy creation of clusters while applications run in fragmented segments.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Portability&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: moving software from one node to another within the grid is instant.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Secure&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: open-source distributed software with transparent code. No security backdoors&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sustainable&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: energy-efficient OS resulting in very low node power consumption.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;technology-that-is-self-healing-self-driving&quot;&gt;Technology that is self-healing &amp;amp; self-driving&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold’s Jumpscale framework and ZeroBot allow the creation of blueprints to auto-deploy applications within the compute environment. The bots are constantly checking the health and uptime of the infrastructure, and runtime environments, to guarantee the performance and availability of applications at all times.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-benefits-of-our-self-healing-technology-protocols-include-the-following&quot;&gt;The benefits of our self-healing technology protocols include the following:&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Self-Healing&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: the platform regenerates when health issues that cause downtime for infrastructure and applications are detected.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Intelligence&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: agents capture information from the grid and make intelligent decisions to provide an ideal and optimal host environment for software code and containerized applications.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lifecycle Management&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: the status of the infrastructure and the lifecycle of running applications are constantly checked and recorded.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Autoscaling&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: the platform automatically scales to meet application and infrastructure performance.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;blockchain-technology-to-execute-workloads-and-applications-via-smart-contracts&quot;&gt;Blockchain Technology to execute workloads and applications via smart contracts&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The engineers developed new blockchain algorithms based on proof of stake for validation purposes and turned this into our Rivine open-source blockchain software.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Unlike the “proof of work” blockchains that currently dominate the space, our Rivine blockchain is scalable, green, and secure - and does not rely on huge mining resources.  We run our blockchain on approximately 200 dedicated nodes and do not rely on any third-party software.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
In addition to our blockchain technology, we have also developed ItsYou.Online, an identity, and access management platform.  Itsyou. online uses three-factor authentication to manage access on our network and facilitate execution.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-benefits-of-tf-blockchain-technology-and-identity-management-platform-include&quot;&gt;The benefits of TF blockchain technology and identity management platform include:&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sustainable&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: our algorithms to reach consensus use a minimal amount of energy and electricity compared to other blockchain software and networks.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lowest possible cost&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: of transactions make it an efficient and fast payment system.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Neutral&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: state of the network and applications are recorded in a transparent and immutable manner.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Payment fulfillment&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: transactions are automatically paid using ThreeFold Tokens.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Smart Contracts&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: fully automated execution of contracts from customers buying Internet IT capacity.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
All of our technology is open-source and can be accessed in the following Github Repos:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Zero-OS: https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;threefoldtech&#x2F;zos&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jumpscale: https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;threefoldtech&#x2F;js-ng&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;BCDB : https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;threefoldtech&#x2F;bcdb&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Datacenter Myths</title>
        <published>2017-10-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2017-10-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/big-datacenter-myth/"/>
        <id>https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/big-datacenter-myth/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/big-datacenter-myth/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“This article was originally published by Andreas Hartl, a former member of ThreeFold Foundation.”&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;hyperscale-realities-are-very-different-from-what-most-people-think&quot;&gt;Hyperscale realities are very different from what most people think&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;myth-1-bigger-data-centers-are-more-efficient&quot;&gt;Myth 1: Bigger data centers are more efficient&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are advantages in building larger-scale data centers, like economies of scale and sheer bulk buying power, but these are not as significant as what people think. The average cost per rack in a hyper-scale data center is $20-35K USD including all energy requirements and safety systems. The cost of hardware per rack is around the $200-300K USD mark.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
What is often forgotten is that anything that is of enormous scale and highly concentrated comes with complexity and specific problems to deal with. For example. resource requirements such as investment, operational costs, knowledge, and people increase significantly with size.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
In reality, keeping things simple, small, and distributed is much more cost-effective than large complex environments.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;myth-2-big-data-centers-can-be-sustainable&quot;&gt;Myth 2: Big data centers can be sustainable&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The carbon footprint of a big data center is enormous. To improve the power usage effectiveness (PUE) of most data center farmers have adopted wind, hydro, and&#x2F;or solar power technologies, which indeed helps drop their PUE by an estimated 20%. But is this leading to more sustainability?
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
This 20% looks great on paper and in the farmers’ corporate social responsibility reports. However, it just represents an improvement in the cooling technology and sourcing of energy. It doesn’t actually impact the energy consumed by the equipment that runs in their data centers (servers, storage chassis, physical disks, etc.) which is the equipment responsible for the carbon footprint. PUE only refers to overhead power consumption, i.e. cooling the facility, opening, and closing doors, maintaining power security systems, etc.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Real improvement lies in deploying technologies that actually consume less power to deliver the actual Internet capacity to run workloads, real CPU chassis, physical disks, and storage cabinets. Improving on how hardware is being more effectively used can have an impact of up to a thousand percent and lead to ten times more power-efficiency.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;myth-3-redundant-systems-have-better-uptime&quot;&gt;Myth 3: Redundant systems have better uptime&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of us believe that systems need redundancy mechanisms to improve their operational uptime and reliability. While it may make sense to IT experts, let’s translate this for the non-IT world?
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
To make a car more reliable we add redundancy (as we do in IT). So for the risk of having a puncture, we add one extra tire for all the tires we use continuously. This adds 4 extra tires to the car. Then a decision needs to be made: Do we put those tires in a structure where they are always running along with the primary tires or do we choose not to have them “online” all the time, wearing and tearing in the same way as the primary tires?
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Building such a system would take a large number of engineers to come up with a solution, and would change cars as we know them. Wouldn’t it make more sense to think outside the box and solve the root of the problem by making tires un-deflatable?
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The IT industry has gone overboard with the concept of redundancy, having forgotten to look at the root cause issues. This has spawned a whole new industry of itself, which has a financial interest in creating complicated and expensive redundant systems.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;myth-4-big-companies-optimize-better&quot;&gt;Myth 4: Big companies optimize better&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Big companies with a certain track record will know better how to optimize as they have more people and resources.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
At first glance, this sounds logical, but in reality, ninety percent of the innovation within the IT space comes from startups. The giant IT companies have a heritage they hardly can overcome. They are locked in old infrastructure designs, and building outside of that infrastructure would be costly, timely, and probably put the breaks on their businesses.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Real innovation gives way to fix the core symptoms rather than taking the problem pain-killer approach.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>The need for ThreeFold&#x27;s neutral internet</title>
        <published>2017-06-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2017-06-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/new-neutral-internet/"/>
        <id>https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/new-neutral-internet/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/new-neutral-internet/">&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
**The Internet is growing like crazy and is now a trillion dollar problem. Together we can build a new neutral Internet.**
&lt;h2 id=&quot;an-introduction-to-the-problems&quot;&gt;An introduction to the problems&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Internet is no longer the neutral place it used to be. +80% of the Internet capacity is delivered by a handful of companies. This results in a loss of neutrality and openness and breeds inequalities.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To support the continuous growth of the Internet and connect billions to new Internet Of Things devices, 400 million new servers are needed by 2020. The world therefore needs another 4,000 large-scale data centers that each consume 200 MWe of electricity: &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;bit.ly&#x2F;1UPUZYG&quot;&gt;see source&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Today, about 4 billion people have no access to the Internet due to the high costs of connectivity and capacity. We believe these people have the fundamental right to have low-cost access to digital resources such as online identity solutions, education, health information and more. For this to happen, solutions that can lower the cost by a factor of 10 are required.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bandwidth does not follow Moore’s law. The growth of bandwidth required is much higher than the speed at which new capacity can be delivered. This is even more important in emerging markets.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Current blockchain technology is not scalable and not sustainable. Example: the Bitcoin blockchain alone uses more energy today than Croatia.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;current-internet-and-cloud-capacity&quot;&gt;Current Internet and Cloud capacity&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, the cloud computing industry represents a 100 billion dollar industry - mostly owned by about 20 global cooperations. Experts such as Bell Labs and Cisco believe the capacity requirements in the next decade will dramatically exceed existing infrastructure - requiring many more data centers and billions, if not trillions in investments.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The spectacular growth and advancements in cloud computing that occurred over the last decade resulted in large part from “hyper-scale” efficiencies - i.e. centralizing Internet infrastructure in very large billion dollar data centers.  However, demand for Internet capacity already surpassed the available infrastructure with emerging technologies such as Big Data, the Internet of Things (IoT) and Artificial Intelligence (AI) Technology. The existing hyperscale cloud architecture cannot cope with this growing demand as the requirements for land, power and funding are becoming outrageous.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The challenges facing the Internet includes the following:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trillions of Investment Required&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;. In the next decade, the global Internet infrastructure requires another 4,000 data centers (250M - 1B dollar investment each) to meet demand which would cost trillions - this money could be better used in education, healthcare, or sustainable innovations.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Impossible to scale the networks connecting users to the hyperscale data centers&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;. Since hyperscale data centers are built in large “central” locations, the network leading to these data centers is congested. Even more, remote regions that are less connected to the Internet cannot benefit from these data centers’ IT services.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Non-local data and capacity&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;. Governments around the world are becoming more and more concerned about data leaving their borders. To tackle this centralization issue, they would need local IT infrastructure. Also, IoT workloads need local capacity to deliver constant real-time computing and storage requirements - for certain applications and workloads (e.g. driverless cars), latency is not an option. Hyperscale data centers can simply not match these requirements.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Not secure &#x2F; at risk of choke point failures&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;. There are plenty of recent well-publicized problems around security, outages and loss of data. The reason for this is that centralized hyperscale architectures are inherently insecure - and failures at a single hyperscale location can cause widespread contagion and outages.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-threefold-solution&quot;&gt;The ThreeFold Solution&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our solution to these trillion dollar problems is to migrate Internet capacity to the Edge (closer to user location) - i.e. a “hyper-distributed” network architecture, located close to users (in cities, schools, offices, homes and even vehicles).
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Edge networks will not necessarily replace the existing hyperscale capacity powering today’s cloud - rather, they will scale to meet the increased capacity demands going forward. However, if the current hyperscale capacity can be decentralized to improve energy consumption and reduce costs, this would be a huge global success.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
By 2025, 60% of new Internet infrastructure will be decentralized and located at the edge of operator networks by using alternative locations which have stable (renewable) power and reliable connectivity.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;threefold-s-technology-main-benefits&quot;&gt;ThreeFold’s technology main benefits:&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Security&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: The ThreeFold Grid is distributed and benefits from our ItsYou.Online identity management platform - making it much more secure.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Decentralized&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: The solution enables to bring capacity closer to where users are located, enabling a Cloud at the Edge.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sustainability&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: The technology removes the need to build huge power hungry datacenters and by decentralizing the architecture enables up-to 1000% energy savings.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Making IT a true utility&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;:  We always approached IT as Energy. Today we provide 3x more uptime and between 3-10x more cost effectiveness.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Neutrality&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: The solution enables 100% neutral &amp;amp; private Internet IT capacity. Our blockchain technology provides security, neutrality &amp;amp; scale.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-threefold-zero-node&quot;&gt;The ThreeFold Zero-Node&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Zero-Node provides compute, network and storage capacity to the internet and ThreeFold’s blockchain. This capacity can be used for any possible workload. Here are some characteristics of ThreeFold’s Zero node:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Modularity&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Scaling from 8 vCPUs and 3.5 TB of storage (smallest) to clusters with 8000 vCPUs and 2 PB of storage (large), there is a range of possibilities at hand.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sustainability&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Storing the hardware uses about 10x less energy, and about 2-3x for other workloads.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Decentralized&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: The Zero Operating System (“Zero OS”) is ideally suited for Edge networking - where automation, self-healing and hyper-distribution are must-haves.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Zero-Nodes are deployed as close as possible to the consumers of Internet IT capacity (IoT, residential, business, government, education, …).&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This results in massive bandwidth savings, we estimate to be able to keep 99% of the required bandwidth locally which has a huge impact on cost.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is the only viable solution to be able to provide internet to the 3.2 billion people waiting.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Self healing&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: The architecture is designed to ensure that workloads and data can be accessed at all times.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Neutral &amp;amp; private&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: A lot of work has done using blockchain (technology which powers crypto currency) to guarantee privacy and net neutrality.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Designed around simplicity to be used by everyone.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The technology provides anyone with the autonomy to deliver complex IT applications without the need for complex integration services.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Empowers equality&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Our technology should be usable by the “other billions” that remain unconnected. Due to the low cost-points, low energy requirements and reduced need of backbone network capacity.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
</feed>
