<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
    <title>ThreeFold - bernadette_amanda_caster</title>
    <subtitle>Our global digital backbone</subtitle>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://dev.threefold.io/people/bernadette-amanda-caster/atom.xml"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://dev.threefold.io"/>
    <generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
    <updated>2024-08-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://dev.threefold.io/people/bernadette-amanda-caster/atom.xml</id>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Watch the ZOS Hub &amp; Flist Demo</title>
        <published>2024-08-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-08-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://dev.threefold.io/newsroom/zos-and-flist-demo/"/>
        <id>https://dev.threefold.io/newsroom/zos-and-flist-demo/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://dev.threefold.io/newsroom/zos-and-flist-demo/">&lt;p&gt;On Tuesday, Scott and Mik showcased Zero OS Hub &amp;amp; Flists, which enable an effective way of dealing with software data, providing fast deployment and high reliability. Curious to learn more? Take a look at the demo &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;youtu.be&#x2F;zRTtbyCzNsY?si=XhmeZCkl29wLiDT2&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Missed one of our recent demos? You can find them all &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;playlist?list=PLTGQlepPqwUUhbtKZW2okEszK3AkDgC4Y&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Project Internet Capacity: ThreeFold&#x27;s Next Chapter</title>
        <published>2024-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/introducing-project-inca/"/>
        <id>https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/introducing-project-inca/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/introducing-project-inca/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Please note the information below is subject to change as the project evolves and will be updated as is appropriate.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold’s journey over the past years has been one of deep, collaborative commitment, marked by significant technological advancements and milestones in building a new cloud infrastructure from the ground up, as well as the global expansion of the grid to its current state. Throughout this journey, we have learned, adapted, and evolved, leading us to a strong strategy for the next chapter and achieving our collective vision.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;meet-project-internet-capacity&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meet Project Internet Capacity&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are thrilled to introduce the Internet Capacity project, a promising new extension of our mission. Building on years of dedicated work by team and community, this project is the fourth generation of the ThreeFold Grid and introduces the $INCA token (more on that below). With this project, ThreeFold is ready to become a base layer for the DePIN ecosystem.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;youtu.be&#x2F;tXELhKk9RYg?si=fyz4K7gFQ1yD1PLS&quot;&gt;our most recent project update community call&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, we were grateful to hear from Michael Wellesley-Wesley, the founder of &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;green-edge.net&#x2F;en&quot;&gt;Green Edge&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and prominent farmer on the ThreeFold Grid since 2017-2018, who introduced the project to the community.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Internet Capacity project is rooted in three major objectives:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reliability:&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; Achieving service levels that allow edge and AI workloads to run efficiently.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Community:&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; Establishing scalable community and communication systems for vast communities at both the farming and user levels.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Growth:&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; Expanding the grid to a million nodes in order to see out the vision of a truly global decentralized cloud infrastructure and ecosystem.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;mission-and-vision&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mission and Vision&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an extension of ThreeFold, the Internet Capacity project promotes a decentralized, community-driven, and inclusive cloud network, providing secure, private, and autonomous access to computing resources for all. The technology ensures a resilient, censorship-resistant infrastructure that protects data integrity and privacy, fostering innovation, digital sovereignty, and a more equitable internet.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The vision is to provide a cloud engine for a decentralized internet where users control their data and digital interactions. A global network of interconnected servers and nodes known as the grid, will democratize access to computing power and storage, forming the backbone of a new digital era of sovereignty, security, privacy, and inclusivity. The token supports a robust ecosystem, enabling the free exchange of internet capacity among cloud service providers, builders, and users on the grid.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-to-look-forward-to-with-the-project&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What to Look Forward to with the Project?&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project introduces several exciting elements for farmers and users alike:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The most significant technological advancement is the Mycelium network, offering unbreakable connectivity and efficient routing, which is crucial for scalability – including for any DePIN protocol or project running on top of our grid&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hosts (farmers) will be able to earn on utilization as well as hosting rewards, and set their own competitive prices within certain limits&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A marketplace of capacity will make it easier for users to find and rent capacity&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To attract serious cloud customers at a commercial level, robust uptime and performance guarantees will be ensured through Service Level Agreements, KYC will be introduced for reliability, competitive pricing will keep customers happy, and simplified products and approach will make for a better user experience&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A quality-based reward system will motivate cloud hosts to provide reliable service, while the flexible earnings model makes hosting more appealing&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A new token will launch on a high profile blockchain&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, there are a variety of elements coming together to ensure a sustainable and healthy ecosystem to grow decentralized cloud and Internet capacity around the world.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-team&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Team&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An experienced team has been gathered around our DePIN launch, complementing the existing core team members. This combination of talent has a range of backgrounds and a collective understanding of how the $INCA token can bring a strong ecosytem for all stakeholders. This will be the natural evolution and continuation of what has been built by the ThreeFold team and community until today.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Michael Wellesley-Wesley&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Team lead, co-founder of Green Edge and a long-time member of the farming community.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;George Olver&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: An expert in the DePIN space, providing day-to-day leadership.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nick Hawkes and Max Gold&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Partners under &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;goldandhawks.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Gold Hawks&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, proficient in scaling DePIN ecosystem and historically part of the Helium and Solana communities.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quentin Issele&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Formerly of OKEx, specializing in liquidity and marketing.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rob Beland&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Founder of &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.depinconnect.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;DePIN Connect&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, with vast marketing and influencer connections.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Theo Chapman&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Managing Director of &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;zonaris.io&quot;&gt;Zonaris&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, coordinating execution within group.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mariza Wellesley-Wesley&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: A well-versed lawyer overseeing regulatory and legal aspects, co-founder of &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;green-edge.net&#x2F;en&quot;&gt;Green Edge&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sabrina Sadik and Mik Perrault&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Our vital connectors between the Internet Capacity and ThreeFold teams.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-inca-token&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The $INCA Token&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many questions have risen about the introduction of a new token to the ThreeFold ecosystem. $INCA should be seen as an extension of $TFT. It will co-exist with $TFT, both convertible and usable across TF Grid 3 and TF Grid 4. The primary differences are:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Higher Profile&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: $INCA will likely have a more prominent presence, especially on Solana.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tokenomics&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: $INCA will support app development, marketing, and community growth grants.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Max Cap&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Both tokens share a four-billion max cap, with $INCA providing an opportunity to double $TFT holdings (one $TFT converts to two $INCA).&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;benefits-for-tft-holders&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Benefits for $TFT Holders&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For $TFT holders, the benefits are clear:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Swapping&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Each $TFT converts to two $INCA (during 2024), enabling easy entry for token holders.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Market Presence&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: $INCA’s launch in the DePIN sector on Solana positions it in a visible and attractive market.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Limited Supply&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: The initial supply of $INCA will be limited, which could drive demand and price up.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;together-we-build&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Together We Build&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, while the Internet Capacity project brings a new chapter, it is really a continuation, simplification, and amplification of the ThreeFold journey. We anticipate exciting developments as we prepare for the TF Grid 4.0 launch and the introduction of the $INCA. We are happy to address any questions you may have on &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&quot;&gt;our forum&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; or &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefold&quot;&gt;our main chat&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, keeping in mind that we are still refining many aspects of this project.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Onward! Keep building, friends.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>On the Ground Activities in Tanzania</title>
        <published>2024-05-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-05-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://dev.threefold.io/newsroom/zanzalu-student-weekend/"/>
        <id>https://dev.threefold.io/newsroom/zanzalu-student-weekend/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://dev.threefold.io/newsroom/zanzalu-student-weekend/">&lt;p&gt;Take a &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;on-the-ground-activities-in-zanzibar-and-dar&#x2F;4357&quot;&gt;quick read&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; as we recap two events from this past weekend – Zanzalu Student Weekend in Zanzibar and the 8th GenAI Meetup in Dar Es Salaam – and look ahead to the Transformative Impact Summit in less than two weeks.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>ThreeFold @ Zanzalu</title>
        <published>2024-05-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-05-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://dev.threefold.io/newsroom/zanzalu-event/"/>
        <id>https://dev.threefold.io/newsroom/zanzalu-event/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://dev.threefold.io/newsroom/zanzalu-event/">&lt;p&gt;This weekend, some of the team will be joining &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;lemonade.social&#x2F;event&#x2F;66485bc7f40139b832e05abc&#x2F;info&quot;&gt;Student Weekend&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; at &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;zanzalu.super.site&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Zanzalu&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, a five-week pop-up city event in Zanzibar spun off from Zuzalu in Montenegro last year. It aims to connect African builders, explore alternative forms of city organization, and foster a growth ecosystem.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Student Weekend, we will show the audience how to deploy workloads on top of ThreeFold’s decentralized cloud infrastructure and participate in an ideathon, which then leads to a hackathon in mid-June where participants will try to build and deploy their ideas on top of ThreeFold nodes.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;An exciting opportunity to interface with local builders and showcase ThreeFold technology!&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To know more at what happened Zanzalu click &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.threefold.io&#x2F;newsroom&#x2F;zanzalu-event&#x2F;&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
</feed>
