<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
    <title>ThreeFold - event</title>
    <subtitle>Our global digital backbone</subtitle>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://dev.threefold.io/tags/event/atom.xml"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://dev.threefold.io"/>
    <generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
    <updated>2022-06-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://dev.threefold.io/tags/event/atom.xml</id>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Consensus 2022 Recap – ThreeFold Community Celebrates the  Internet of Internets</title>
        <published>2022-06-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2022-06-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/consensus-2022-recap/"/>
        <id>https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/consensus-2022-recap/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/consensus-2022-recap/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“This article was originally published by Hannah Cordes, a former member of ThreeFold Foundation.”&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ThreeFold Team was in Austin, Texas, in June to share our vision for a decentralized Internet as an exhibitor and sponsor of &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;threefold_at_consensus_2022&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Consensus&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; by Coindesk. The four-day conference attracted over &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;cointelegraph.com&#x2F;news&#x2F;consensus-2022-web3-unpacking-regulations-and-optimism-for-crypto-s-future&quot;&gt;20,000 people&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; who explored conversations on topics like decentralization, blockchain, crypto, Web 3 and more. The ThreeFold team shared our “planet first, people first” vision and story with hundreds of attendees who visited our conference booth to learn about ThreeFold – leading to new community members, farmers, token holders, and partners. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Co-founder &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;people&#x2F;adnan_fatayerji&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Adnan Fatayerji&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; conducted several media interviews and found that our story resonated well – after all, &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;threefold_at_consensus_2022&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Consensus&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is the Festival for the Decentralized World. Nevertheless, many of the other projects at Consensus are still using centralized infrastructure for hosting. We shared the potential for ThreeFold as the foundation to make a truly decentralized world a reality. Already, independent people and organizations from 80 countries and counting are connecting decentralized Internet capacity, bringing to life this new infrastructure.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;dev.threefold.io&#x2F;blogarchive&#x2F;consensus-2022-recap&#x2F;.&#x2F;threefold_booth_consensus.png&quot; alt=&quot;ThreeFold Booth Consensus&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;dev.threefold.io&#x2F;blogarchive&#x2F;consensus-2022-recap&#x2F;.&#x2F;threefold_booth_people.png&quot; alt=&quot;ThreeFold Booth People&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“As the Layer 0 for Web2&#x2F;3&#x2F;4 or 5, we came to Consensus with open arms and in the spirit of collaboration and that’s exactly what happened. We made friends and connected with the projects out there that are truly moving the needle of ‘Trust’&#x2F;Web3 forward. We look forward to nurturing these incredible partnerships on ThreeFold’s foundational layer and to scale ‘Digital Trust’ in all its forms towards mainstream adoption.” – Adnan Fatayerji&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;bringing-the-sovereign-internet-to-austin&quot;&gt;Bringing the Sovereign Internet to Austin&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Together with some of &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.yourhomecommunity.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;our Austin friends&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, we gathered with 45 like-minded people at Casa de Luz, a spiritual and wellness retreat, to launch the first sovereign Regional Internet in Austin, Texas. All of us shared our own stories and reasons for attending. Then we explored the opportunities, benefits and next steps for Austin to establish its own truly self-sovereign regional Internet.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We found shared values among a group of open, inspiring, passionate and like-minded individuals who formed this founding group. Austin has long been a hub for innovative thinkers and high-tech companies. Austin has a strong connection to and respect for nature. Austin is aligned well with our planet-first, people-first philosophy.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe that, together, we’re strong enough to build new regenerative systems powerful enough to enable anyone to have a sovereign, safer and more fulfilling life. And we’re honoured to be working with the people of Austin in the global rollout of the Internet of Internets. We’re now looking to launch the first 3Nodes there to lay the foundation of Austin’s sovereign Regional Internet.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;dev.threefold.io&#x2F;blogarchive&#x2F;consensus-2022-recap&#x2F;.&#x2F;threefold_austin_community.png&quot; alt=&quot;ThreeFold and Austin Community&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve spent a truly incredible week in Austin, spreading the word about ThreeFold, forming meaningful connections and finding a new home. Thank you, Austin!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“It’s been inspiring to meet everyone at Casa de Luz! Feeling so grateful for the opportunity to build Austin’s sovereign Internet together!” – Sacha Obeegadoo&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“It was such an honor. I’ll never forget that day. We’re going to do something really beautiful!” – Sam Taggart&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Connecting with the beautiful community of the good people of Austin was absolutely amazing. We really felt at home and Austin is a true freedom vortex in the US where people truly value their free spirits and the importance of staying resilient and independant. We could not have dreamt of a better place to start the Internet of Internets in the US and create the first local internet. Keep it weird Austin!” – Florian Fournier&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;next-steps&quot;&gt;Next steps&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The founding gathering in Austin was just the beginning. Building meaningful relationships with local communities to start the next few Regional Internets will be a big focus for the ThreeFold ecosystem in 2022. Therefore, we’ll be travelling to various places across the globe to &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;connecting_the_dots&#x2F;&quot;&gt;connect the dots&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; in the upcoming months.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After entering a partnership with &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;paradise_hills&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Paradise Hills&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to build the first Community Cloud, planting the seeds for the first Regional Internet in Austin represents another crucial step in our journey to create the &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;internet_of_internets&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Internet of Internets&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; – a glocal model that is infinitely scalable. So, the next few months will be vital for our &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;four_phases_of_threefold&#x2F;&quot;&gt;expansion phase&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and for building a better future for all of us.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Together, we’re building a better Internet by and for the people, the foundation for a better world. An Internet to regenerate our planet and to empower the collective – the many and not the few.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, we’re proud to join together to build the future we want to live in – whether by &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;farming&#x2F;threefold__diy_guide&quot;&gt;building&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; or &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;marketplace.3node.global&#x2F;&quot;&gt;buying&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; a 3Node, by buying the ThreeFold Token (&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;tft&quot;&gt;TFT&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;), or by helping us bring the sovereign Internet to your community or region.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;New to ThreeFold? &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefold&quot;&gt;Join&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; the movement now and learn how to &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;what_is_farming&#x2F;&quot;&gt;be&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; the Internet.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>ThreeFold at Consensus: A Decentralized World is in Our Hands</title>
        <published>2022-05-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2022-05-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/threefold-at-consensus-2022/"/>
        <id>https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/threefold-at-consensus-2022/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://dev.threefold.io/blogarchive/threefold-at-consensus-2022/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“This article was originally published by Hannah Cordes, a former member of ThreeFold Foundation.”&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s that time of the year when believers and builders of a decentralized tomorrow  gather to celebrate the festival for the decentralized world. About 15,000 people will attend Consensus 2022 by CoinDesk from June 9 through June 12. Throughout the festival, key topics around decentralization, blockchain, crypto, Web 3 and the metaverse will be explored and discussed.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is ThreeFold attending Consensus? Excellent question. The ThreeFold community truly believes that collaboration, decentralization and peer-to-peer systems are the foundation for a better Internet, and subsequently, a better world. And together we are making that world a reality. But we need to grow and extend the community on the ground with the right people, dreamers who choose to act now.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As many consider Consensus the festival for the decentralized world, some questions linger:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;How committed are the projects and participants to decentralization, and for what reasons? How far are they willing to go to bring that world to life?&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s no secret that many projects in the space still rely on centralized infrastructure – at least to some degree. So, are they really delivering on their promise of decentralization?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-decentralized-world-needs-a-decentralized-foundation&quot;&gt;A decentralized world needs a decentralized foundation&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think we’ve already come to Consensus that decentralization has to start at the foundational level. See what I did there? The ThreeFold co-founders have more than 20 years of experience in setting world records in Internet storage and cloud automation technologies. With ThreeFold, they started from scratch to build a fully decentralized Internet infrastructure that’s peer-to-peer and open source. We’re realizing the promise of an Internet built and owned by the people, back to the vision of Web 1 through the implementation of Web 4 technology. For us, it’s obvious that we simply cannot build a fair and equal digital world on top of today’s old-world infrastructure which is owned by the few.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With our fair, inclusive and decentralized Internet infrastructure, we’re laying the foundation for a better world. Following our ethos of &lt;em&gt;planet first – people second – profit (value) only as a result&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, we’re striving to regenerate our planet and to empower the collective – the many and not the few. By putting our planet and people first, we create real sustainable value. We believe that, together, we’re strong enough to build new regenerative systems powerful enough to enable anyone to have a sovereign, safer and more fulfilling life.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of today, people from 77 countries are connecting thousands of computers (3Nodes) to the ThreeFold Grid – all contributing to ThreeFold’s open-source peer-to-peer Internet infrastructure. And any node or dApp, actually anything that can run on Linux, can run on top of the ThreeFold Grid in a truly decentralized way. With ThreeFold’s infrastructure and thriving ecosystem, there’s an abundance of potential and opportunities – really anything is possible.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;threefold-consensus&quot;&gt;ThreeFold @Consensus&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ThreeFold team and community will soon gather at the Austin Convention Center, 500 E. Cesar Chavez Street, Austin. Meet the ThreeFold team at &lt;strong&gt;Exhibit Booth 310&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; not far from the Networking Lounge. We’ll be there throughout the entire exhibit to connect with participants, share the ThreeFold story and extend the community – Friday, June 10 through Saturday, June 11 from 9am until 6pm.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At our booth, you’ll be able to meet the team, see and hold a Titan 3Node, have the chance to win a free 3Node of your own, find resources that will empower you to get involved, and more.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold will also host a gathering outside of the Convention Center. We will share more via &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefoldnews&quot;&gt;our Telegram News Channel&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; when the details are finalized, so stay tuned.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold is more than an Internet. It is the foundation for a truly decentralized world. Are you ready to &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefold&quot;&gt;join&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; the global ThreeFold movement?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Check out the full &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;events.coindesk.com&#x2F;consensus2022&#x2F;agenda&quot;&gt;Consensus agenda&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and take advantage of &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;events.coindesk.com&#x2F;consensus2022?promo=a7MsHxui&quot;&gt;our 25% discount code&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to buy tickets.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And don’t forget to let us know if you’ll be joining ThreeFold at Consensus – we’d love to connect with you!&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
</feed>
