<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
    <title>ThreeFold - foundation</title>
    <subtitle>Our global digital backbone</subtitle>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://dev.threefold.io/partners-category/foundation/atom.xml"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://dev.threefold.io"/>
    <generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
    <updated>2024-07-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://dev.threefold.io/partners-category/foundation/atom.xml</id>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Holochain</title>
        <published>2024-07-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-07-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://dev.threefold.io/oldpartners/holochain/"/>
        <id>https://dev.threefold.io/oldpartners/holochain/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://dev.threefold.io/oldpartners/holochain/">&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;an-end-to-end-open-source-p2p-app-framework&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;An end-to-end open source P2P app framework&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.holochain.org&quot;&gt;Holochain&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is a framework for developing and running decentralized applications (dApps) designed to be scalable, efficient and adaptable, featuring a peer-to-peer content distribution protocol, cryptography and hash tables. Unlike traditional blockchain architectures, Holochain uses a distributed hash table (DHT) to enable peer-to-peer communication and data storage, offering greater flexibility and performance for decentralized applications. It addresses effectively scalability challenges and is highly environmentally friendly.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;dev.threefold.io&#x2F;oldpartners&#x2F;holochain&#x2F;holochain3.png&quot; alt=&quot;holochain&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A significant change enabling Holochain’s innovation is its shift from a data-dependent blockchain to an agent-centric system. Unlike blockchain’s need for global consensus, Holochain employs an agent system where each agent maintains a private fork, managed on the blockchain in a limited manner using a distributed hash table. This approach eliminates the scalability issues common to blockchain solutions, allowing decentralized applications (dApps) on Holochain to achieve more with fewer resources.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;dev.threefold.io&#x2F;oldpartners&#x2F;holochain&#x2F;holochain2.png&quot; alt=&quot;holochain&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold and Holochain will together go to market, Holochain as application layer being hosted on the ThreeFold Grid.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;partnership-with-threefold&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Partnership with ThreeFold&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The partnership between ThreeFold and Holochain merges decentralized infrastructure with advanced application development frameworks. By combining the strengths of both platforms, this collaboration seeks to drive innovation and expedite the adoption of decentralized technologies.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;how-the-partnership-works&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How the Partnership Works&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Integration of Services:&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; ThreeFold’s TF Grid will integrate with Holochain’s framework, providing decentralized hosting and storage solutions for Holochain-based applications. This integration will enable developers to deploy their dApps on a scalable and resilient infrastructure, enhancing performance and reliability for end-users.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Benefits for Users:&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enhanced Performance:&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; Users of Holochain-based applications hosted on the TF Grid will experience improved performance and responsiveness, thanks to the scalable and distributed nature of ThreeFold’s infrastructure.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Increased Reliability:&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; By leveraging ThreeFold’s decentralized hosting solutions, users will benefit from enhanced reliability and uptime for Holochain applications, reducing the risk of downtime and service interruptions.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data Sovereignty:&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; Users will have greater control over their data and digital assets, as Holochain applications hosted on the TF Grid will adhere to principles of data sovereignty and privacy.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion:&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; The partnership between ThreeFold and Holochain represents a strategic alignment of decentralized infrastructure and application development frameworks, aimed at empowering developers and users to build and deploy scalable, efficient, and resilient decentralized applications. By leveraging each other’s strengths and capabilities, the partnership holds the promise of driving innovation and accelerating the adoption of decentralized technologies across various industries and use cases.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information about Holochain, visit &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;dev.threefold.io&#x2F;oldpartners&#x2F;holochain&#x2F;holochain.org&quot;&gt;Holochain&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Our World Free Zone</title>
        <published>2024-03-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-03-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://dev.threefold.io/partners/our-world-free-zone/"/>
        <id>https://dev.threefold.io/partners/our-world-free-zone/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://dev.threefold.io/partners/our-world-free-zone/">&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-sovereign-economic-zone&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#a-sovereign-economic-zone&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: a-sovereign-economic-zone&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Sovereign Economic Zone&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine if an entrepreneur, digital nomad, or any organization could obtain a digital company license, a bank account supporting both fiat and cryptocurrencies, and handle their legal requirements and taxes – all within a single streamlined platform. ThreeFold technology will be leveraged to enable just that within the world’s first 100% digital free zone – accessible and affordable for all.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The government of Zanzibar is undertaking several initiatives to shift its economy from being largely dependent on tourism to embracing the IT sector. As part of this vision they have partnered with ThreeFold via &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;zictia.go.tz&#x2F;&quot;&gt;ZICTIA&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, the Zanzibar ICT Infrastructure Agency, to create the world’s first digital free zone.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This collaboration was formally announced by Zanzibar’s President, Dr. Hussein Ali Mwinyi, at ThreeFold’s Africa Regenerative Future Summit in July 2023 which brought together a group of passionate entrepreneurs and actors working on innovative planet-first projects in Africa. The president promised to establish the digital free zone from a regulatory perspective, with the goal of developing local skills, bringing about major changes in the ICT sector, and creating job opportunities to increase the nation’s income.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;freezone.png&quot; alt=&quot;our_world_free_zone&quot; width=&quot;600&quot;&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the world’s first digital free zone, this special economic zone will be supported by ThreeFold’s innovative tech stack. Merging traditional business structures with groundbreaking technology, the free zone will be a pioneering hub for business, fostering an ecosystem that is adaptive, resilient, and conducive to growth. It will be one of the first environments where Decentralized Autonomous Organizations (DAOs) can be legally established and operated. Some of the ThreeFold team is based in Zanzibar and working to make the free zone live by the end of 2024.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold’s latest technology, which is currently being fine tuned, the Digital Twin, will also be launched as part of the Free Zone membership. The Digital Free Zone (DFZ) Digital Twin application provides a centralized interface for accessing all free zone features and users will own 100% of the data and digital capabilities. You can be among the first to embark on the OurWorld Digital Free Zone journey.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;news-coverage&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#news-coverage&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: news-coverage&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;News Coverage&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.thecitizen.co.tz&#x2F;tanzania&#x2F;zanzibar&#x2F;zanzibar-seeks-to-become-digital-freezone--4316150&quot;&gt;The Citizen&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;dailynews.co.tz&#x2F;mwinyi-commits-to-improvement-of-digital-spaces&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Daily News Tanzania&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Sikana</title>
        <published>2024-03-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-03-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://dev.threefold.io/partners/sikana/"/>
        <id>https://dev.threefold.io/partners/sikana/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://dev.threefold.io/partners/sikana/">&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;education-for-all&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#education-for-all&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: education-for-all&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Education for all&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sikana is a non-profit organization on a mission to empower individuals with practical skills through free educational video programs. Targeting the 3+ billion people around the world with access to screens they have so far delivered over 400,000,000 online video lessons. Some of the projects they have been involved in include facilitating access to energy and fighting against energy poverty in the Ivory Coast, helping to save biodiversity in France and empowering women with vocational training at sewing schools in India.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;dev.threefold.io&#x2F;partners&#x2F;sikana&#x2F;sikana2.png&quot; alt=&quot;sikana&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the incredible scale of this inspirational project comes with significant hosting fees, inhibiting Sikana’s ability to equip people and communities around the world with new knowledge and skills. It was at this point in Sikana’s journey that co-founders Florian Fournier and Grégory Flipo met the ThreeFold team. We shared the same vision of making education accessible and creating a more equitable and greener world, sparking an exciting partnership between ThreeFold and Sikana, and bringing Florian and Gregory onto the team.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold’s decentralized grid can step in as the solution to these immense hosting costs allowing Sikana to extend its global reach and helping even more communities around the world. Together, we are working to create and provide local content in local languages on top of local infrastructure, fulfilling the goal of making education accessible to everyone.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can help us on this mission by either creating educational content which will be disseminated on top of the ThreeFold Grid or you can help create the necessary capacity to host these educational programs. Hosting a node can mean hosting someone’s education. Learn more about &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.sikana.tv&#x2F;en&quot;&gt;Sikana&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and how to host this impactful organization &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.threefold.io&#x2F;host&#x2F;&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;embed&#x2F;8ArbVX7bV1w&quot; title=&quot;The Sikana Trailer: What Is This Channel for?&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;&#x2F;iframe&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Social Network</title>
        <published>2024-03-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-03-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://dev.threefold.io/partners/social-network/"/>
        <id>https://dev.threefold.io/partners/social-network/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://dev.threefold.io/partners/social-network/">&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;scaling-bitcoin&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#scaling-bitcoin&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: scaling-bitcoin&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scaling Bitcoin&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earth Staking’s Social Network is the first Bitcoin Staking Layer 2 on Earth, designed to provide users with a more cost-effective, efficient and eco-friendly experience. Their mission is to decentralize scaling solutions for Bitcoin and create social networks that prioritize the well-being of Earth and its inhabitants. Having jointly identified challenges currently confronting Bitcoin and its alternatives, ThreeFold and Social Network have partnered together to improve the accessibility, security, scalability, reliability and energy efficiency of the Bitcoin Network.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;social_network.png&quot; alt=&quot;social_network&quot; width=&quot;800&quot;&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Social Network will be integrated with and enhanced by ThreeFold technologies. This includes, but is not limited to, ThreeFold’s decentralized cloud – featuring Quantum Safe Storage and the Mycelium Network – as well as decentralized computation, and Zero OS. ThreeFold’s infrastructure provides the ideal backbone for Earth Staking’s ambitions, offering a robust, low-level decentralized framework perfectly suited to empower its vision.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The partnership is also focused on advancing the development of cross-chain communication technology for Bitcoin, Ethereum, and others – enhancing scale, security, ease of use, and energy efficiency. To this end, ThreeFold and Earth Staking will look to create a seamless, frictionless, easy-to-use EarthWallet and node with built-in BTC Staking, ETH Light, and Nostr functionalities.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our partnership agreement was formalized in January 2024 and we are now in the process of technical implementation.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Tanzania&#x27;s Sovereign Internet</title>
        <published>2024-03-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-03-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://dev.threefold.io/partners/tanzania-sovereign-internet/"/>
        <id>https://dev.threefold.io/partners/tanzania-sovereign-internet/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://dev.threefold.io/partners/tanzania-sovereign-internet/">&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-sovereign-internet-by-and-for-tanzania&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#a-sovereign-internet-by-and-for-tanzania&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: a-sovereign-internet-by-and-for-tanzania&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Sovereign Internet, By and For Tanzania&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The current centralized Internet model works for the few and is GDP negative for most countries. Most nations do not own their Internet, instead with fiber optic cables transferring and storing their data in data centers in the Global North. A relatively small set of big companies have access to and control over the data of billions of citizens, making us a product. The result is a loss of national money, data, sovereignty and influence.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our feasibility study showed that Tanzania is losing around 10 Billion USD per year from not having their own infrastructure and applications. The current centralized model needs to change.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Centralized model vs ThreeFold model&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;object-cover w-full&quot; style=&quot;display: flex; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;todays_internet.png&quot; alt=&quot;tanzania_sovereign_internet&quot;&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;object-cover w-full&quot; style=&quot;display: flex; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;threefold_internet.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;tanzania_sovereign_internet&quot;&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tanzania shares this vision and together with ThreeFold has embarked on a mission to build their own sovereign Internet infrastructure where the people are in control and are the ones benefiting from their own digital lives. To achieve this mission, Tanzania’s ICT Commission has partnered with us to leverage ThreeFold technology to enable a Tanzanian-owned Internet infrastructure and allow local communities to build the digital solutions that they need and want on top of the grid.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold’s unique technology is ideal for this transformative project because of its affordability, efficiency, accessibility, reliability, security, sustainability and ability to be co-owned. By focusing on everyone owning and running things together, an autonomous digital future shaped by the community will become a reality. It will be a Tanzanian internet designed by and for the people.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project “Dunia Yetu”, meaning Our World in Swahili, was announced in January 2024 at a conference in Dar Es Salaam organized by ThreeFold and Tanzania’s ICT Commission. The next steps which the team is currently working on include helping local communities to deploy nodes across Dar es Salaam as well as opening a coworking hub. This hub will empower startups and entrepreneurs in Dar es Salaam to learn more about the ThreeFold grid and focus on knowledge sharing to help them build their own digital solutions on top of the grid. Learn more about Tanzania’s new internet &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;dunia-yetu&#x2F;&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding:56.63% 0 0 0;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;player.vimeo.com&#x2F;video&#x2F;919967495?h=340e62170b&amp;amp;badge=0&amp;amp;autopause=0&amp;amp;player_id=0&amp;amp;app_id=58479&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; fullscreen; picture-in-picture; clipboard-write&quot; style=&quot;position:absolute;top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;&quot; title=&quot;TBC NEWS JANUARY 19, 2024 | Sovereign internet: A game changer to Tanzania&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;iframe&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;&lt;script src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;player.vimeo.com&#x2F;api&#x2F;player.js&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;script&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>VeVerse</title>
        <published>2024-03-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-03-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://dev.threefold.io/partners/veverse/"/>
        <id>https://dev.threefold.io/partners/veverse/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://dev.threefold.io/partners/veverse/">&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-metaverse-eradicating-cultural-boundaries&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#a-metaverse-eradicating-cultural-boundaries&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: a-metaverse-eradicating-cultural-boundaries&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Metaverse eradicating cultural boundaries&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;VeVerse aims to create a virtual universe which eradicates cultural boundaries and supports the free flow of ideas and knowledge. The vision is to provide a metaverse platform which bridges virtual worlds, digital assets and communities and to empower museums, artists and game developers to construct captivating environments together where users can play, explore and connect.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the critical moments which inspired this project was when VeVerse’s founder, Vasily Gnuchev, traveled to Egypt. In his own words “experiencing the rich history and art of this ancient civilization firsthand, I became even more determined to create a platform where such wonders could be shared with people worldwide.” It was on this trip Vasily met ThreeFold co-founder Kristof De Spiegeleer, who shared a passion for art and decentralization and whose encouragement played a crucial role in propelling VeVerse’s first project, Artheon, forward. Artheon is a virtual museum which breaks down cultural barriers by providing global access to artistic masterpieces. Check out this fascinating project &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;artheon3d.veverse.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and visualize it in the video below.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;object-cover w-full&quot; style=&quot;display: flex; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;veverse.png&quot; alt=&quot;veverse&quot;&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the problems facing VeVerse, and all other metaverse products in existence, is the inadequate computational and connectivity infrastructure available today. Current infrastructure lacks the speed and capacity to power such expansive digital experiences. Latency levels are also significantly higher than the almost zero latency requirements of metaverse data being stored in close proximity to users. Edge computing emerges as a vital solution to realizing the metaverse, offering decentralized local data storage hardware that drastically reduces latency by storing data closer to users. This is where ThreeFold steps in as a pivotal player, offering the largest decentralized grid globally, equipped with edge cloud and computing capabilities essential for powering the metaverse’s future. The partnership between ThreeFold and VeVerse will help bring cultural artworks and historical artifacts to billions. Help host this innovative solution by expanding ThreeFold’s cloud capacity.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
 &lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;embed&#x2F;FCjofnZnTDk?si=GexBObXsBJ-9zvyz&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;&#x2F;iframe&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>VVerse</title>
        <published>2024-03-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-03-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://dev.threefold.io/partners/vverse/"/>
        <id>https://dev.threefold.io/partners/vverse/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://dev.threefold.io/partners/vverse/">&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-cutting-edge-metaverse-platform&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#a-cutting-edge-metaverse-platform&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: a-cutting-edge-metaverse-platform&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A cutting-edge Metaverse platform&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;VVerse offers a cutting-edge platform for virtual socializing and entertainment. One of their first products is &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.vindo.ai&#x2F;&quot;&gt;VinDo&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, the next generation communication and business tool to streamline your interactions, empower your business, simplify your workflow and amplify your results. Businesses can become virtual with VinDO and redefine customer experiences in the metaverse. Checkout the video below to see this metaverse in action.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;vverse.png&quot; alt=&quot;vverse&quot; width=&quot;800&quot;&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;VVerse has chosen to partner with ThreeFold as its infrastructure partner due to its unparalleled capabilities in powering the metaverse’s evolution. With ThreeFold’s decentralized grid and edge cloud computing, VVerse aims to overcome the limitations of current infrastructure, particularly in terms of latency and scalability. ThreeFold’s edge cloud infrastructure minimizes latency, enabling real-time interactions in VR and AR settings. Users will experience seamless interactions and immersive experiences without delays. As VVerse anticipates an influx of users engaging in diverse activities simultaneously, ThreeFold’s infrastructure offers scalable solutions. This ensures that the platform can efficiently handle spikes in demand, providing a smooth experience for all users.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through strategic partnerships with metaverse innovators like VVerse, ThreeFold is paving the way for a future where digital and physical realities seamlessly coalesce. Together, these efforts propel the metaverse towards its full potential, revolutionizing digital experiences for users worldwide.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding:56.6% 0 0 0;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;player.vimeo.com&#x2F;video&#x2F;917760972?badge=0&amp;amp;autopause=0&amp;amp;player_id=0&amp;amp;app_id=58479&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; fullscreen; picture-in-picture; clipboard-write&quot; style=&quot;position:absolute;top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;&quot; title=&quot;vindo_intro&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;iframe&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;&lt;script src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;player.vimeo.com&#x2F;api&#x2F;player.js&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;script&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
</feed>
